<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/aud_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-01-21T21:44:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed AUDUSD short @ 0.9057 for +126, +26, -13 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-audusd-short-09057-for-126-26-13-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-21T21:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-21:paper-trade-closed-audusd-short-09057-for-126-26-13-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-change-of-wind-for-australian-dollar-shorted-audusd-0-9183-and-audcad-0-9546/"&gt;AUD/USD short from yesterday&lt;/a&gt; played out exactly as I planned. But
I took profit a few pips earlier than I wanted because the bounce from
0.9025 fooled me. As you can see from Figure 1, AUD/USD is resting on
0.9000 support as I predicted. Now the million dollar question is,
should I go long in this currency pair because of the super long term
trend as I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-change-of-wind-for-australian-dollar-shorted-audusd-0-9183-and-audcad-0-9546/"&gt;discussed in my previous post&lt;/a&gt;? That brown support line in which AUD/USD is resting on now
(Fig. 1) extends all the way back to April 2008. However, there's also a
nearby support at &lt;a href="http://www.tradergav.com/2010/01/22/is-it-time-now-audusd-is-in-the-zone/"&gt;0.8945 as shown on Gav's Trading Blog&lt;/a&gt;. Since I
don't trade such a long term timeframe, I will be more conservative on
this by watching how the price reacts in the short term at this 0.9000
level. Gold also broke below 1100 but is holding above its own support
around 1080-1090 too. Both markets are finding support at current
prices. Let's see how well they last. I am flat in this pair until
things are more clear to me. On another note, this isn't exactly a
victory as I've been trying to short the Aussie for days. You would have
been better flipping a coin in comparison to my success rate lately.
I've lost more than I have gained on this move so far. In fact, I am
still on handicap mode (half position size) as I'm &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/work-harder-trade-fewer-in-a-long-and-excruciating-trading-drawdown/"&gt;still in a 3%
drawdown&lt;/a&gt; as shown in my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trading log&lt;/a&gt;. However, I am slowly
crawling my way out with limited risk and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/good-trade"&gt;profitable trades&lt;/a&gt; such as
this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/USD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-21-AUDUSD_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="good trade"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>A change of wind for Australian dollar: Shorted AUDUSD @ 0.9183 and AUDCAD @ 0.9546</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-change-of-wind-for-australian-dollar-shorted-audusd-09183-and-audcad-09546/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-20T13:24:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-20:a-change-of-wind-for-australian-dollar-shorted-audusd-09183-and-audcad-09546/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been barking up the short-Aussie-tree since the beginning of the
year. See post [#1][], [#2][] on AUDJPY, and [#3][], [#4][] on
AUDCAD for the long term analysis. (Also see my post on &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/early-bird-does-not-get-the-worm-in-forex-trading/"&gt;being early
shorting the Aussie&lt;/a&gt;.) Anyway, now that AUDUSD has backed off the 9300
level with a bang, it seems that the trend reversal in the Aussie is
getting clearer. Why do I say that? Notice the sequence of recent AUDUSD
price action depicted in the daily chart of Figure 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking below lower long term trendline (thick brown line, Fig. 1)
    on Dec 14 followed by a 300 pips down move&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reversing on Dec 22 at 8730 price level, right on the last long term
    support line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing the same trendline in #1 from below and gliding along it
    since the new year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bouncing off the previous resistance at 0.9330&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A rapid breakdown right to the neckline support at 0.9100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the breakdown of gold price (Fig. 2) is helping to keep the
downward momentum in this currency pair. Now that recent moves are
confirming my long term Aussie short outlook as discussed previously
([#1][], [#2][], [#3][], [#4][]), my plan is to stay on the short
for the long haul. My target on this dive for the AUDUSD is down to
0.9000 corresponding to the long term support line of #2 in that list
above. Of course, prices don't go one way. So remember to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/risk-management/"&gt;manage
risks&lt;/a&gt; and be prepared for some probable counter-trend moves. [caption
id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUDUSD, daily
chart"][&lt;img alt="AUDUSD, daily chart" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-20-AUDUSD_d.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-20-AUDUSD_d.PNG"&gt;AUDUSD, daily chart&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="Gold futures
(GC)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-20-GC.png" /&gt;][][/caption] If you've been following my analysis, you'll
see that I've converted from shorting AUDJPY to shorting AUDUSD. The
simple reason is that USDJPY looks to have bottomed out and is on a run
upward. Thus, the US dollar has more potential strength than the yen to
go long. Lastly, as the title says, I also shorted AUDCAD at 0.9546 for
the long term. See Figure 3. That short is playing out nicely as well
with an [amazing long term bearish setup][#3]. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUDCAD, daily
chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-20-AUDCAD_d.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-20-AUDCAD_d.PNG"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short AUDCAD @ 0.9583, Stop 0.9670</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audcad-09583-stop-09670/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-11T09:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-11:paper-trade-short-audcad-09583-stop-09670/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gold price made a 15 point jump over the weekend to 1160 and is
consolidating now (Fig. 1). Crude oil tested 84 and is back down to just
above 83 now. Yet, AUDCAD is still struggling to break above 9600 (Fig.
2). You would have thought that AUDCAD should mustered enough momentum
to break above this key resistance with all these gold bullishness and
oil bearishness. Thus, I am giving this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audcad-0-9489-stop-9540/"&gt;AUDCAD short setup as described
previously&lt;/a&gt; another try. I am only risking 0.16% on this trade. It is
half of my usual initial entry. First because it is a FTR (reversal)
setup and second because I am in a 3% drawdown. So my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/risk-management/"&gt;risk
manaegment&lt;/a&gt; rules dictate that I trade halved size. This setup is
according to the monthly and weekly chart, so it could take a while, and
probably more tries, before it shows its hands. I will keep shorting it
as long as it's below 9600 on the weekly. Limited by the amount at risk
according to my risk management rules, of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="Gold (GC
futures), 4-hour left, daily right"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-11-GC.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/CAD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-11-AUDCAD_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-11-AUDCAD_3h.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTR"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short AUDCAD @ 0.9489, Stop 9540</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audcad-09489-stop-9540/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-06T13:38:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-06:paper-trade-short-audcad-09489-stop-9540/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been stopped out of all my Aussie shorts on the breakout today. But
my setups for AUDUSD and AUDJPY are still intact as the resistances are
still safe. Having failed so many times in shorting AUDJPY (&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audjpy-84-53-stop-85-00/"&gt;first
try&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-retrying-audjpy-short-84-52-stop-85/"&gt;second try&lt;/a&gt;), I am taking a conservative approach on that
particular play. Although those setups are ripe for entries, I'll wait
til the test of resistances hold first before entering short again in
AUDJPY and AUDUSD. Which begs the question of, why AUDCAD, and why now?
First of all, I still have conviction about my Aussie short because of
the setups as &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audjpy-84-53-stop-85-00/"&gt;discussed previously&lt;/a&gt; and the fact that gold
price is holding the 40 day ema at 1135 at the moment. That 40 day ema
has worked well on the uptrend in the past few months. So it should be
respected if gold is indeed in a downtrend now as I surmise. So why
short AUDCAD instead of the popular AUDUSD? Simply because AUDUSD broke
out of a short term range whereas AUDCAD is still holding as seen in the
AUDCAD 3-hour chart of Figure 1. This shows AUDCAD is weaker even when
gold is making new short term high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/CAD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-06-AUDCAD_3h.PNG" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the big picture, see Figure 2 for the weekly chart of AUD/CAD. We
see that 0.98-0.99 has always been the turning point for a massive 1000+
pips selloff. We've hit 0.99 back in November and the slide is already
in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we see from Figure 2 that AUDCAD bounced off the 40 week ema
in late December and ran up to 0.95 from 0.92. 0.95 is a decidedly
important round number resistance as it was also a peak in April of
2007. You know, the time before the economy started to crack as shown
with the topping in the markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUDCAD,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-06-AUDCAD.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-06-AUDCAD.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I've established that the trend is pointing down. I still need
to time my short entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 shows the daily chart of AUDCAD. In view of the above
discussion, we have a good chunk of resistance above 9550 as marked by
the purple box in Figure 3. This is the all important safety net for
this short entry. As long as AUDCAD stays below 9600, this long term
setup remains intact. And don't forget the broken uptrend line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUDCAD,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-06-AUDCAD_day.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-06-AUDCAD_day.png"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, notice the RSI trends in both the 3-hour (Fig. 1) and daily
charts (Fig 3.), they are both showing negative divergences. Figure 1 is
my timing for this entry, see the current negative RSI divergence marked
by the downward trend in RSI versus the toppy price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, here are my signals for this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/FTC"&gt;FTC setup&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weekly chart shows downward trend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big resistance above current price on daily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broken uptrend line on daily on retracement from weekly chart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intermarket relation with gold testing 40 day ema at 1135.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negative RSI divergence on 3-hour chart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper Trade: retrying AUDJPY short @ 84.52, Stop 85</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-retrying-audjpy-short-8452-stop-85/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-06T09:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-06:paper-trade-retrying-audjpy-short-8452-stop-85/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audjpy-84-53-stop-85-00/"&gt;previous AUDJPY short entry&lt;/a&gt; was early as I surmised (entered
without short-term confirmation). I made a number of ins and outs with
that trade as depicted in Figure 1. Some were winners, some were losers.
In all, it's around breakeven in that trade. However, I have re-entered
this short in AUDJPY just now at 84.52 using &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audjpy-84-53-stop-85-00/"&gt;the same long term
setup&lt;/a&gt; (see weekly chart in that post) as
it hasn't been broken yet. Moreover, AUDJPY is in the process of making
a negative divergence on the 3-hour chart as shown in Figure 1. The key
word is "in the process". There is still a possibility of a breakout
upward from here. I am being aggressive to establish a position here
because of intermarket divergence in Aussie crosses versus gold price
overnight. See Figure 2. As you can see, gold made a marginally higher
high above 1130 on the 4-hour chart of Figure 2. Yet, neither AUDUSD nor
AUDJPY followed suit. Those two currency pairs are holding their
respective double top. The exception is EURAUD, it keeps diving
downward, but that can be accounted for by Euro weakness. It would have
been a perfect picture of EURAUD can hold its bottom though. I wouldn't
count this trade to work out just yet. That's why I'm only risking 0.2%
of my account with a small &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tools/forex-position-sizer/"&gt;position size&lt;/a&gt; for now. As you can see
from my trade orders shown in Figure 2. I have a couple limit orders
just below the near-term supports to add to this short. My pawns have
been placed. Let's wait and see what the market does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUDJPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-06-AUDJPY_3hr.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="580" caption="Aussie crosses and gold
price"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-06-AUD_crosses.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-06-AUD_crosses.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short AUD/JPY @ 84.53, Stop 85.00</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audjpy-8453-stop-8500/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-04T14:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-04:paper-trade-short-audjpy-8453-stop-8500/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven't done one of these &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/entry/"&gt;trade analysis post&lt;/a&gt; for weeks. So I
thought I'll start the year on this promising long term (more than a
week) trade on one of my favourite currency pairs, AUD/JPY. This entry
on shorting AUD/JPY is executed according to my Forex Trend Reversal
(FTR) setup. Figure 1 shows the weekly chart. Please excuse the mess.
There are only 3 relevant lines in addition to the price. Referring to
Figure 1, first line of note is the top of that 4-line descending
channel. Notice that 84.50 correspond with the resistance this week.
Secondly, there are 3 ascending trendlines drawn. We have a triple
X-cross on the 2 ascending and 1 descending lines at around 85.00 last
week. AUD/JPY failed to touch it. If this trade goes well, AUD/JPY
shouldn't test 85.00 again because it has missed its chance. That's
where I placed my stop. Anyway, these are just doodles on a chart, we
need confirmations. For that, let's take a look at the major Aussie
crosses and gold prices in Figure 2. [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="580" caption="AUD/JPY, weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-04-AUDJPY.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="Aussie crosses and gold,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-04-AUD_crosses.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-04-AUD_crosses.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] The recent strength in Aussie is clear in
the 4-hour charts of Figure 2. From top to bottom, Figure 2 shows
AUD/USD, EUR/AUD, AUD/JPY, and GC (gold futures). We also see that gold
prices is staying at a depressed level below 1120. This rising Aussie
but toppy gold price is a sign of divergence. Furthermore, we have a
shooting star candlestick pattern in the previous gold price bar. Gold
spiked above 1130 briefly but couldn't hold above 1120 so far. Another
plus for the short. Now that the entry signals have been met. I needed
to time my entry. This the the part that I should have done better. I
basically just shorted it at the '50 resistance without giving it much
thought. The short-term bullishness is still strong and I really should
have waited for a lower high on the 3-hour chart. Figures 3 and 4 are
the daily and 3-hour charts, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-04-AUDJPY_1day.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-04-AUDJPY_1day.png"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="580" caption="AUD/JPY, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-04-AUDJPY_3hr.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-04-AUDJPY_3hr.png"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] I took a
smallish position in this trade at an obvious resistance level. My
intention is to add to it as long as AUD/JPY stay below 85. Also, a
safer stop should be 85.50 as seen from Figure 3 (daily). 84.40 was a
recent top in October. Lastly, I chose to short AUD/JPY instead of
AUD/USD because I have some other U.S. dollar longs already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTR"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category></entry><entry><title>AUDJPY Short 81.37/77.17: Anatomy of my first 400+ pips trade</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/audjpy-short-81377717-anatomy-of-my-first-400-pips-trade/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-26T22:34:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-26:audjpy-short-81377717-anatomy-of-my-first-400-pips-trade/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;420 pips in my demo account to be exact. Still, I feel very lucky. In
this post, I will review why I entered this position, why I added to it,
and why I exited. The goal is for myself to learn from what works and
what can I do to improve on this trade given some hindsight advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Signal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See Figure 1 on the daily chart of AUDJPY (first entry price pointed
with blue arrow). Notice the lower highs, with the 2nd high inside my
fChannel and the 3rd (last, just before entry) high below a yet longer
term fChannel. Plus 1 point for the lower highs and another 1 point for
the highs moving into the channels. Two points here. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="AUDJPY"][&lt;img alt="AUDJPY" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-26-AUDJPY.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-26-AUDJPY.png"&gt;AUDJPY&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Choice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both AUDJPY and AUDUSD seemed promising. I focused on AUDJPY
because the Yen seemed better poised for strength. I discussed my
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-use-fx-futures-to-narrow-down-which-forex-pair-to-trade/"&gt;method of choosing a better counter currency for trading&lt;/a&gt; in another
post, so I won't discuss it here. However, as this trade became more and
more obvious and into the green, I diversified my short by adding shorts
in NZDJPY and NZDUSD. Those two netted around +100 and +250 pips also.
Another plus 1 point for picking and choosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Confirmation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What really gave me confidence in this trade is the price action in gold
in comparison to the Aussie. Figure 2 shows the Gold Futures price (/GC,
lower left) and Australian dollar futures (/6A, middle left). Notice
that gold has been trending up steadily for days but the Aussie made a
lower low. That's a negative divergence. Plus 1 point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="4-hour charts of
forex markets, gold, and crude oil"][&lt;img alt="4-hour charts of 6 major
currencies, gold, and crude oil" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-26-ForexOverview_4h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-26-ForexOverview_4h.png"&gt;4-hour charts of 6 major currencies,
gold, and crude oil&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Timing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For timing this trade, I observed the intraday movement of AUDJPY,
EURUSD, and other related pairs. The most obvious sign of Aussie
weakness was from comparing the price action of EURUSD and AUDJPY. The
3-hour charts of EURUSD and AUDJPY are shown in Figures 3 and 4,
respectively. Notice on Nov 24 and 25, EURUSD trended higher and made a
new high. At the same time, AUDJPY barely moved on the 24th and squeezed
even more on 25th. The difference was even more noticeable when I was
watching the 30-min at the time. I had thought that my datafeed was
lagging when AUDJPY barely moved yet EURUSD was rocketing up. Plus 1
point for the 3-hour price action and then another 1 point for the
30-minute price action (not shown).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURUSD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="EURUSD, 3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-26-EURUSD_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-26-EURUSD_3h.png"&gt;EURUSD, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUDJPY, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="AUDJPY,
3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-26-AUDJPY_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-26-AUDJPY_3h.png"&gt;AUDJPY, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Entries and Exits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six points total for the trade, time to establish a position. You can
see my orders in Figure 4 above. My first entry was Nov 25 15:12 at
81.37 with a half position. It is marked by a yellow triangle at the
cliff beforethe dive (how lucky). I added another half that evening
23:06 at 79.94. I was waiting for a 50% retracement to 80.50 to add but
that didn't seem to be happening. So I added 1/2 when AUDJPY failed to
break 80.0 with a strategy to add another at 80.50. But 80.50 never
happened and it took another dive. My exits are determined at the time
as usual by using stops. I simply keep moving the stop along and
narrowing them once we break support level. After the move became
vertical, I zoomed out to the daily chart to view potential targets. The
77.0 and 76.00 levels (as shown in Figure 1) became my not-be-greedy
targets. I had my stops really tight at those point and even had a take
profit set for half the position at 76.0, but that level wasn't tested
before I got stopped out. The two red dots at 77.17 and 77.08 are my
stopped exits as shown in Figure 4's last bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made this lucky trade happen is that I had spent a lot of time
analyzing it from different perspectives and watching the intraday price
actions for days. I also took my time to scale in and out to minimize my
risk. To make this a habit, I will use this point counting system from
now on to help me analyze more and trade less. One thing that I'd like
to improve upon is to be more aggressive on a winning position. How?
That will be saved for another post when I figured it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTR"></category><category term="good trade"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category></entry><entry><title>How to use FX futures to narrow down which forex pair to trade</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-use-fx-futures-to-narrow-down-which-forex-pair-to-trade/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-20T14:10:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-20:how-to-use-fx-futures-to-narrow-down-which-forex-pair-to-trade/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A problem I have is that once a currency pair shows a viable trading
setup, other related pairs often show the same setup too. A reason for
this phenomenon is that markets don't operate in a vacuum. When markets
really move, everything move together. So the highly correlated markets
can scream for entry at the same time. The real question though, is
which one should I put my chips in? There are limitless methods on how
you can approach this. The one I'll talk about in this post is a simple
method of comparing your candidates using the currency futures. Why use
the futures? Because they provide a standardized platform, which is
essential when comparing things. As a bonus, there is a US dollar index
futures to help with analysis of the dollar. Not a trivial process on
its own. I will explain my method by way of an example. This morning, I
was considering to go long in AUD/JPY, CAD/JPY, AUD/USD, or short
USD/CAD according to signals from my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC setup&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, I could have
just choose which one to trade based on the RSI rating or some other
indicator. But I don't put much faith in indicators for various reasons.
So a method I typical use is to just go through the charts to manulally
identify which has better reward/risk or better support/resistance. As
you can imagine, this is very time consuming. In practice, I only
compare AUD/JPY vs. CAD/JPY and AUD/USD vs. USD/CAD, and then compare
the winners of those two matches. Like in a tournament. Not that much of
a hassle but the issue with this approach is that I'm adding another
layer of uncertainty with all these unscientific comparisons. That could
have a significant negative impact on my trading. In a good trading
strategy, every step taken should be to improve your probability of
success or the reward/risk ratio. As such, it's better to keep my
process simple. This is where the currency futures indices is of value.
They provide a big picture perspective and serve as a standardized data
for comparison. Using my example, I needed to choose between shorting US
dollar or Japanese yen (I repeated the process for choosing AUD or CAD).
Figure 1 below shows the 4-hour chart of both currencies for the past 10
days. It's evident from the chart that the US dollar is in a range and
the Japanese yen (actually it's JPY/USD) is moving up. 1 point goes to
US dollar trade. Next, I identify the strength of the support/resistance
to estimate in the case that the trade goes against me, which would have
better cushioning. It's a crude form of risk estimation. From the figure
below, see that the dollar has a clear resistance just below 76 and it
is currently stretched away from the cyan-coloured moving average.
Whereas the yen is near a recent top with no prior occurence and it has
been sitting above the moving average for a while. Another point for
dollar short. USD 2 : JPY 0. Consequently, I went long AUD/USD this
morning instead of AUD/JPY. This is by no means a vigorous methodology.
I'm not saying that shorting US dollar is a good idea from this
simplistic comparative process. It's just that my setup tells me to go
long AUD/USD or AUD/JPY, this is just a quick and easy way to help me
decide which trade to take. Nothing more. As an aside, some people may
prefer to use currency ETF, UUP and FXY, instead. But I don't like to
use ETF as a data source as the price is noisier because they are
affected by other factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="504" caption="US dollar and
Japanese yen futures indices"]&lt;img alt="US dollar and Japanese yen futures
indices" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-20-DX-6J.PNG" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="indicator"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Stopped out AUD/JPY longs @ 81.3 (+7 pips) and 81.29 (-28 pips)</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-out-audjpy-longs-813-7-pips-and-8129-28-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-20T11:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-20:paper-trade-stopped-out-audjpy-longs-813-7-pips-and-8129-28-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-audjpy-81-22-sl-80-99-tp-82-50/"&gt;AUD/JPY long from yesterday&lt;/a&gt; got stopped out after I moved the
exit stop to a breakeven price. Then I gave it another try once AUD/JPY
had a quick dip and recovered to 81.30 level around Tokyo noon. That has
been a time of large moves recently. My entries and exits are shown on
the 3-hour chart of AUD/JPY in Figure 1. The problem with this entry is
that the downside momentum is stronger than I thought. While being wrong
is perfectly fine in trading, I need to put more thoughts in short-term
analysis to improve my probability. In addition to the analysis which
I've done as previously discussed for &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-audjpy-81-22-sl-80-99-tp-82-50/"&gt;my entry&lt;/a&gt;, I am going to take into account yet another shorter
timeframe for my trade timing. Figure 2 shows a 30-minute chart of
AUD/JPY. Referring to Figure 2, the two blue triangles are my entries.
The two red dots are my exits from stops. In hindsight, my first entry
was about an hour early. Short-term resistance was obvious at 81.60 but
there is no short-term support shown. I should have entered either above
the resistance or when we failed to break 81.10 support the second time.
For the next few hours from 12:00 to midnight, AUD/JPY is testing that
long term resistance fChannel as shown in Figure 2. We can see that the
trendline is imposing a strong resistance on the pair as it hasn't been
able to hold more than a few bars above it. The second entry at 81.60 is
acceptable. AUD/JPY tested 81.30 again but managed to jump right back
up. Particularly if we look at the 3-hour chart of Figure 1, it would
seem that this is merely a short-term retracement from the 82.00
resistance. A stop at 81.30 as I have done has limited risk and it would
mark the line in the sand. If I'm to try going long this pair again with
this setup, I would use a half sized position only as the setup has
failed me twice already. But as can be seen in Figure 2, AUD/JPY is
failing 81.30 this morning again. This is an obvious sign of weakness in
the pair. So that's it for me for now to go long in this pair. A more
detailed log of my trades can be found on my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trade log page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY, 3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-20-AUDJPY_3h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-20-AUDJPY_3h.PNG"&gt;AUD/JPY, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY, 30-minute"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY,
30-minute" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-20-AUDJPY_30m.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-20-AUDJPY_30m.PNG"&gt;AUD/JPY, 30-minute&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Long AUD/JPY @ 81.22, SL 80.99, TP 82.50</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-audjpy-8122-sl-8099-tp-8250/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-19T10:49:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-19:paper-trade-long-audjpy-8122-sl-8099-tp-8250/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several major pairs are testing their support on this market correction
with a 20 points drop in the S&amp;amp;P500 before 10 am. This is a short term
capitulation scenario. From looking at the major pairs, the long term
trend still seem to be intact. In particular, I am interested in
shorting Yen because I'm seeing &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC setups&lt;/a&gt; across the board in JPY
crosses. I compared AUD/JPY, CAD/JPY, EUR/JPY, GBP/JPY, and USD/JPY
pairs to decide which one to go long with. Seeing that I already have a
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-1-0122-sl-1-0060-tp-1-0225/"&gt;USD/CHF long position&lt;/a&gt;, USD/JPY is out. Then EUR/JPY is out too
because of recent Euro weakness from my observations of intraday price
actions. I haven't had much luck with British Pounds, so GBP/JPY is out
too. That leaves me with my two favourites, CAD/JPY and AUD/JPY. So I
checked with USD/CAD and AUD/USD charts to see which has better
support/resistance. USD/CAD has a lot of resistance above 1.06, so going
with CAD/JPY long seem like to be less risky. However, from looking at
the 3-hour chart, I changed my mind to go with AUD/JPY long because it
is showing a positive divergence there. From the daily chart of AUD/JPY
shown in Figure 1, we can see that the up-trend is losing steam. The
price action is expected to be choppy. Long term condition, up and
choppy. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="AUD/JPY"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY.png"&gt;AUD/JPY&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Figure 2 shows the
3-hour chart of AUD/JPY, this is where things get more clear. Notice
that AUD/JPY is testing the lower fChannel the third time in a month
with the lowest RSI. This is a clear positive divergence. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY,
3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY_3h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY_3h.PNG"&gt;AUD/JPY, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] However, the strong short-term
down move is making this long entry very dangerous. Thus, I am using the
NYSE intraday sentiment (Fig. 3) to pin point my entry. Notice the
extreme negative open and then the intraday positive divergence as shown
by the S&amp;amp;P500 and TICK. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="NYSE intraday sentiment"][&lt;img alt="NYSE intraday sentiment" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-intraday.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-intraday.PNG"&gt;NYSE
intraday sentiment&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] As part of my analysis for this trade, I
compared the current scenario with earlier this month. Figure 4 is the
hourly chart of AUD/JPY when I entered this trade. Figure 5 is the
hourly chart of AUD/JPY from Nov 1st - 4th, when AUD/JPY last tested the
lower fChannel. I noticed that AUD/JPY had a tendency to break below my
fChannel by about 50 pips before reversing. With the fChannel at 81.80
today, AUD/JPY should fall to 81.30. I watched that level closely this
morning and timed my entry with the intraday sentiment as described
above. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY,
1-hour"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY, 1-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY_1h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY_1h.PNG"&gt;AUD/JPY, 1-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY November 1st-4th,
1-hour"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY November 1st-4th, 1-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-04-AUDJPY_1h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-04-AUDJPY_1h.PNG"&gt;AUD/JPY November
1st-4th, 1-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Position size: 100% Entry: 81.22, entered
based on intraday sentiment. Stop: 80.99, below round number support.
Target: 82.50, previous congestion and near top of channel. Reward /
Risk = 128 / 23 = 5.57 &gt; 3. A risky trade with great potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry></feed>