<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/bad-trade_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-11-08T15:38:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Story of a bad trade and a missed opportunity</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/story-of-a-bad-trade-and-a-missed-opportunity/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-08T15:38:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-11-08:story-of-a-bad-trade-and-a-missed-opportunity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The market took a big bite out of me this week just as when I am not
giving it its fullest attention. I took a short-side trade in Manulife
Financial (MFC.TO) last Thursday simply &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-4-mfc-11jan-put-14-00-0-93-mark-13-97/"&gt;because of a price pattern&lt;/a&gt;.
I did not seek to confirm my hypothesis with short-term price action and
intermarket analysis like I usually would because I've been so consumed
with &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/i-got-jforex-running-smoothly-on-amazon-ec2-t1-micro/"&gt;setting up my trading system on the cloud&lt;/a&gt;. I became careless
because of my recent win streak and my involvement in so many matters. I
lost my focus. My short in Manulife Financial (MFC.TO) is deep in red as
of this writing. The market gapped above my stop loss price over the
weekend and never eased back for me to exit at my stop as planned. I've
placed in a limit order to target a retracement to \$14.50 because
there's not much left to recuperate if I dump my position now. MFC.TO is
well above \$15, so I am prepared for the worst. Judging by the volume,
this looks like a valid breakout too. At least my put options don't
expire until January. If my puts expire, this will be a loss of \$372 +
\$9.90 commission = \$381.90 = 3.9% of my RRSP account. To put this into
perspective, according to my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trade log&lt;/a&gt;, this may become my biggest
single loss in a trade in this account. Three folds greater than my
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/boughtsold-250-tck-b-to-34-1033-68-loss-1-2/"&gt;previous biggest loser at 1.23%&lt;/a&gt;. Ouch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Manulife
Financial (MFC.TO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-11-08-MFC.TO.png" /&gt;][][/caption] Manulife is only half of my
blunder this week. The real killer is in Ventana Gold (VEN.TO). As you
may recall, I have been very bullish on VEN.TO. In fact, I've been
stalking this gem for months by &lt;a href="../tag/ven.to/"&gt;nibbling on small bullish positions&lt;/a&gt;
to test the water now and then. Just as when I dug myself into a hole
because of this extended loss, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/i-didnt-miss-a-boat-i-missed-a-freakin-rocket/"&gt;VEN.TO launched off on a rocket&lt;/a&gt; (Fig.
2). I am just staring at its takeoff outside the fence without the
ability to take a position because of my self-regulated risk exposure
limit. There goes a few weeks of research and analysis out the window.
Double ouch! [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570"
caption="Ventana Gold (VEN.TO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-11-08-VEN.TO.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-11-08-VEN.TO.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] As bad as my
trading can be, at least I am adament with my risk management and
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/3-reasons-why-i-even-bother-trading-a-small-account/"&gt;traded within my limits&lt;/a&gt;. A 3.9% loss in a trade is horrible, but
it's not catastrophic. I will survive this one, redo my research, regain
my focus, and be able to fight on another day. This is what trading is
about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Sold 300 HOD.TO @ 9.12, Loss -0.6%</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-300-hodto-912-loss-06/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-25T11:44:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-10-25:sold-300-hodto-912-loss-06/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Update: Crude is making a dive. This might be the move that I waited but
got stopped out. I shorted crude oil on Friday afternoon below the 82
resistance. It was an undocumented trade. Now I am closing at a loss.
It's a slap on the hand for breaking my own trading rules. Oil broke
above 82 over the weekend. Fortunately, the opening gap was filled
before noon and I took the opportunity to cover my short. I was down 1%
at the open. Good thing I didn't panic and waited patiently (with a hard
stop just below the opening low) for a more rational exit. My planned
stop was \$9.15, the opening low was \$8.87, and I covered at \$9.12.
Just a tad under my plan but a lot higher than the low so far. Figure 1
is a chart of U.S. Oil Fund (USO) at the time of my exit. I traded the
Horizons BetaPro Oil Bear Plus ETF (HOD.TO) as a vehicle for shorting
crude oil. The chart of USO is a better proxy of crude oil prices as
it's a few magnitudes higher volume (i.e. more popular) than HOD.TO.
From the looks of it, I will stay on the sideline until at least the
midterm election in the United States next week. Loss for this trade is
(\$9.12 - \$9.29) * 300 = -\$51 - \$9.90 commission = -\$60.90 = -0.6%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="U.S. Oil Fund
(USO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-10-25-USO.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="Energy"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="HOD.TO"></category><category term="short"></category></entry><entry><title>Bought/Sold 250 TCK.B.TO @ $34.10/$33.68, Loss -1.2%</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/boughtsold-250-tckbto-34103368-loss-12/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-28T14:17:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-06-28:boughtsold-250-tckbto-34103368-loss-12/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What I thought would be an intermediate term hold turns out to have
lasted mere minutes. I bought Teck Cominco (TCK.B.TO) after a small
bounce at \$34 support during lunch today. Figure 1 shows the clear
support level. Also note the fact that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-4-mfc-10oct-puts-17-00-1-43-mark-16-27-loss-0-5/"&gt;my recent shorts haven't been
working&lt;/a&gt;, so I thought I would go with the flow and go long. [caption
id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Teck Cominco
(TCK.B.TO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-06-28-TCK.B.TO.png" /&gt;][][/caption] However, the market edged lower almost
immediately after my long entry (something I haven't done in a while).
TCK cracked the \$34 support swiftly to \$33.80, my mental support. My
alert was sounded and I kept an eye on it afterward. But then not long
after \$33.80, my hard stop at \$33.70 was filled and TCK traded down to
\$33.66 or so. It has now stabilized around \$33.80 as of 2pm. Figure 2
shows the intraday chart of TCK.B.TO. [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="TCK.B.TO intraday chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-06-28-TCK.B.TO-intra.gif" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-06-28-TCK.B.TO-intra.gif"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Loss
for this trade is (\$33.68 - \$34.10) * 250 = -\$105 - \$4.95 * 2
commission = -\$114.90 = -1.2% of account. My account is now
experiencing a 3.4% drawdown since &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-6-cm-10oct-put-74-00-6-60-mark-70-70-8-0/"&gt;the high on June 8th&lt;/a&gt;. I can't
help but feel that this was a stop hunt. TCK is creeping higher at the
moment. However, as my initial position was stopped out, I am not going
to re-enter this trade just yet. Let's see what it does near the close
today. I am labelling this particular trade as a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/bad-trade/"&gt;bad trade&lt;/a&gt; because
my stop was clearly too tight based on the time frame that I am
observing. I should have reduced my position size and widened my stop to
account for the recent volatility. Update: TCK gapped down 7% the day
after. At least my exit was timely.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="Mining"></category><category term="TCK.TO"></category></entry><entry><title>Sold 4 MFC 10OCT Puts 17.00 @ @1.43, Mark $16.27, Loss -0.5%</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-4-mfc-10oct-puts-1700-143-mark-1627-loss-05/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-28T13:14:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-06-28:sold-4-mfc-10oct-puts-1700-143-mark-1627-loss-05/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not much is happening in the market as it is trading in a tight range.
This is not good for my options as the time delta will slowly eating
away my premium. So I've decided to unload this position at a small loss
just now as the market is testing support across the board. The U.S.
dollar index is testing \$86 resistance. Oil is testing \$78 support.
S&amp;amp;P500 is testing the 1070 support zone. Purchase price for these puts
were &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-4-mfc-10oct-puts-17-00-1-48-mark-16-38/"&gt;\$1.48 per contract last Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. When Manulife Financial
(MFC.TO) was trading at 16.38. Loss is (\$1.48 - \$1.43) * 100 * 4 =
\$20 - \$13.95 * 2 commission = \$47.90 = 0.5% of account. As you can
see, the commission is horrible on my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;RRSP trading account at
Questrade&lt;/a&gt;. I will wind down trading options from now on and move back
to trading forex in the summer. My live account at &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143/"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt; is
ready... Update: The market finally broke support the day after this
exit. This was not a good exit as I lost patience. MFC is testing \$16
support on June 29th opening hour and I don't expect it to hold. This
could turn out to be a winner if I had held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Manulife
Financial (MFC.TO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-06-28-MFC.TO.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="financial"></category><category term="MFC.TO"></category><category term="options"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Stopped USDCAD short @ 1.0540 for +131 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-10540-for-131-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-15T09:23:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-15:paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-10540-for-131-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally a profitable trade in my USDCAD short after being stopped out a
few times. My decision last week to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/usdcad-short-target-hit-1-0581-trying-something-new-to-hold-for-longer/"&gt;hold this for longer&lt;/a&gt; after
USDCAD touched my target paid off. I moved my stop closer last Thursday
evening and the order got filled on Friday. However, as I type this on
the following Monday, USDCAD is trading even lower at 1.0478. It looks
as though my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;original target of 1.0415&lt;/a&gt; is in the cards. Even though
this is a profitable trade with a 0.17% gain in my demo account, there
is one major flaw with this short USDCAD play. I was not able to squeeze
more out of this profitable move. As I've said, this short took a few
tries. In fact, if we consider all the entires and exits of this play.
My stopped out losses totaled 0.29% and my single win here is merely
0.17%. So I'm actually at a net loss of 0.12% from all these work. My
win/loss rate is about 40% based on my review of recent forex trades. I
was able to edge out more than &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;10% profit in four months&lt;/a&gt; because
when I am wrong, I take small steps. But when I'm right, I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;pile into a
position&lt;/a&gt;. Ever since my trading environment has changed, I've been
trying to trade a longer timeframe. This USDCAD short is my first
attempt on a new strategy. Evidently, I will need to re-think and
re-learn what I've become accustomed to in the past few months. One of
the necessary trait of a successful trader is to be able to adapt.
Markets change. Traders need to evolve with the markets or they will
become obsolete. This will be a good test of myself to see if I can
re-invent myself to adapt to a changing trading environment. [caption
id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-13-USDCAD_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="CAD"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Early bird does not get the worm in forex trading</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/early-bird-does-not-get-the-worm-in-forex-trading/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-08T10:30:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-08:early-bird-does-not-get-the-worm-in-forex-trading/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[This post was updated on January 13, see addendum below.] I have
discussed my enthusiasm in shorting the Aussie a few times this week.
First trade was &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audjpy-84-53-stop-85-00/"&gt;shorting AUD/JPY at 84.53&lt;/a&gt;. After that got stopped
out, I re-tried at the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-retrying-audjpy-short-84-52-stop-85/"&gt;same level the next day&lt;/a&gt;. My trade history in
this currency pair is shown in Figure 1 below. Evidently, I am early in
my trades as the recent upward momentum is still going. But that's just
speaking from hindsight advantage. What is actually wrong with this play
is that I was too eager at the first entry when the price was just at a
minor resistance (short-term trendline of Fig 1). In turn, that caused
me to lose my confidence and not be as aggressive as I should be when
the price reached a major resistance at 85.50. Referring to Fig. 1, I
made 5 attempts on the minor resistance below 84.60 in the first round.
What's worse is that I didn't have enough patience to wait after these
shorts failed and I tried again at 84.52. Even though that resistance
level is voided already. But here comes the kicker. I actually &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-audjpy-84-53-stop-85-00/"&gt;noted
the important 85.50 level before my first attempt&lt;/a&gt;. It was clearly on the chart and I even mentioned about its
significance. I just figured that it wouldn't be touched. How wrong I
was. As I said, another problem with being early in a trade is that it
stripe you of your confidence prematurely in a good setup. My setup to
short AUD/JPY is as good as ever now. I am drooling over that negative
RSI divergence shown in Fig. 1... But since I've already taken a beating
in this pair this week, my account drawdown dictates that I limit my
risk. As such, I can't back up the truck to pile in on this trade at
this point. But why not? I won't break one rule to compensate for
another. Although I am light in this trade now, I will not compromise my
risk management rules to compensate for my own mistakes. That would just
open a whole new can of worm. Besides, I can't say this often enough --
risk management is always the top priority in trading. In any case,
there will always be other opportunities. The moral of the story is
this. Do not be too eager to get into a trade. Secondly, adjust your
position size accordingly to the significance of the setup in play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-08-AUDJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] &lt;strong&gt;Update January 13:&lt;/strong&gt; Figure 2 below shows
an updated view of AUD/JPY a week later. The red dot on the 9th was my
last stopped out entry. As you can see, I missed the smooth 200 pips
ride down. This experience is proving to be better than I expected to
illustrate how being early in a trade can really hurt your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="A week later in
AUD/JPY, 3-hour chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-13-AUDJPY_3h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-13-AUDJPY_3h.PNG"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category></entry><entry><title>An example of how trading in fear is bad for your account</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-example-of-how-trading-in-fear-is-bad-for-your-account/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-18T19:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-18:an-example-of-how-trading-in-fear-is-bad-for-your-account/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having had &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-bad-eurusd-day-trading-and-what-to-do-about-it/"&gt;a hard time day trading the EUR/USD last week&lt;/a&gt;, things
haven't been well for me this week either with the market in a gridlock.
My one and only viable setup so far is &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftcs/"&gt;built for a trending market&lt;/a&gt;.
So this range-bound market is new territory for me as I experiment (in
hindsight, haphazardly) to come up with more profitable forex trading
setups. As you can imagine, trading without discipline is a recipe for
diaster. I have given back all the paper gain from this month by the
start of this week and is treading on thin ice with my demo account
dipping dangerously close to the November opening balance. Needless to
say, I do not want to see my account in the red for this month. But that
is what happened after today's string of failed trades. I am officially
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;in the red for this month&lt;/a&gt;, for now. While there are several mistakes
I made resulting in this mess, I think it all boils down to one flaw in
my trading this week. Yes, those day trading stints I did surely have
put a dent in my demo account, but what's worse is that I've
unconsciously have let those losses affect my trading mentality. These
losses were stuck in my mind and my mental "goal" for this week was
recovering from them. However, I have approached the problem in the
wrong way by not wanting to lose anymore in my account. In other words,
I was afraid of losing. So how did that materially affect my trading?
Here is a simple example as illustrated in my order history on the
GBP/JPY chart attached at the bottom of this post. The 3 yellow
triangles are my short entries and the 3 red dots marks the stopped
exits. According to my setup, my original entry at 149.50 had a stop at
150.50. But I moved my stop closer to 149.80 in the morning because I
didn't want to risk more. That got taken out easily as 149.80 is within
the congestion zone. Then I tried to short it a couple more times with
tight stops because I see the downside potential to be still intact.
Those were eaten up alive too and now I don't have a position because it
would have been more foolish to keep trying in vain. While just 3 trades
wouldn't have done much damage, I was doing the same thing across the
board in shorting CAD/JPY and EUR/CAD. A few here and a few there. They
add up to a bad day. As of this writing, it looks like these pairs are
finally moving in my direction. But instead of being patient with
reasonable stops, I thought I could do better and micro-managed my
positions to end up taking multiple small losses and with nothing left
on the table to ride the move. So what is the correct way of following
up on a dent in the account? I should have done the following instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce risk exposure by limiting trade size or overall opened
    positions until I am back up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on what I did wrong last week and stop doing that, i.e. no
    more day trading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recall my best trades and do more of that, i.e. my one and only
    finalized setup, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so coincidentally, now that I'm in the deepest drawdown ever, this
is as good as ever to put this emergency recovery procedure into
practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="GBP/JPY,
1-hour"][&lt;img alt="GBP/JPY, 1-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-GBPJPY_1h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-GBPJPY_1h.PNG"&gt;GBP/JPY, 1-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="drawdown"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="recovery"></category></entry><entry><title>My bad EUR/USD day trading and what to do about it</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-bad-eurusd-day-trading-and-what-to-do-about-it/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-14T18:20:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-14:my-bad-eurusd-day-trading-and-what-to-do-about-it/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've stayed home from work this week because of the flu. So with spare
time on my hands, I had the urge to experiment with day trading the
forex market. Bad decision. After a good 3-4 days of day trading EUR/USD
with my demo account, here is what I have to show as illustrated in my
account balance graph for the past 4 trading sessions below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="Account balance
Nov 10-14, 2009"][&lt;img alt="Account balance Nov 10-14, 2009" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-14-account_balance.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-14-account_balance.png"&gt;Account balance
Nov 10-14, 2009&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Yes, you can push back up your dropped jaw
now. I considered not accounting for these losses in my paper trading
account because these trades were meant to be experimental only.
However, as the whole point of me paper trading the forex is to learn
and improve, I decided to keep these losses and suffer the consequences
of my own doing. Heck, I wouldn't have had the choice if this were real
money (which is the way that I should treat this demo account anyway). I
stepped out of my circle of strength (swing trading) into something that
has burned me many times before. Well guess what, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/1000-in-2-days/"&gt;history does repeat
itself&lt;/a&gt;. Enough with lambasting myself. The real focus of this post is
to point out what I did wrong and what can I do to improve in day
trading the forex. Not that I'm intent on day trading though. This is
merely to increase my arsenal in forex trading. Figuring out what I did
wrong is actually obvious in hindsight. Figure 2 below depicts the
trades I made on Nov 13, which led to most of that steady decline in my
account balance as shown in Fig. 1. See the bounce from about 1.4820? I
kept shorting it and shorting it all the way up to 1.4880. What was I
thinking? The main reason for this epic failure is that I broke a
fundamental rule in trading. &lt;strong&gt;Trade what you see and what you thought&lt;/strong&gt;
(Techniques of Tape Reading by &lt;a href="http://www.realitytrader.com/blog/"&gt;V. Graifer&lt;/a&gt;). Based on the previous
day's market sell-off from 1.5000 and the Asian markets failing to break
1.4900, I thought the market would follow through on Friday and break
through this 1.4820 support. In particular, just before NY open before
9:30am, EUR/USD had a couple of big drops, as shown in Fig. 2. All these
circumstances led to my believe that we'll see a weak day like
yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EUR/USD,
5m"][&lt;img alt="EUR/USD, 5m" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-13-EURUSD_5m.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-13-EURUSD_5m.PNG"&gt;EUR/USD, 5m&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] However, a support is
still a support until it's broken. I shouldn't keep shorting it even
though it has obviously bounced. While identifying the trend is trivial
in hindsight, what evidence did I have at the time to tell me that? The
evidence was in fact staring me in the face that morning. Figure 3 shows
part of the screen that I usually use for intra-day observation. As you
can see, S&amp;amp;P500 rejected the previous day's close with a strong negative
TICK reading and then broke above the morning range. The TICK also
remained strong with many +800 readings in the morning. All the classic
signs that point to a strong positive trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="577" caption="intraday
sentiment"]&lt;img alt="intraday sentiment" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-13-intraday_am.PNG" /&gt;[/caption] Furthermore, if only I had
stepped back and observed the bigger picture, as shown in Fig. 4 with a
30-minute chart, I would have seen that we have a great positive
divergence swing setup (and which I normally would have exploited if I
weren't so focused on trading the 5m that day).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EUR/USD,
30-minute"][&lt;img alt="EUR/USD, 30-minute" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-13-EURUSD_30m.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-13-EURUSD_30m.PNG"&gt;EUR/USD, 30-minute&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] What
is my goal in future day trading? Instead of a declining equity curve as
in Figure 1, just flip it up-side-down and that's what would be perfect.
All I needed to change is being able to spot the right trend and ride
it. Easier said than done. So what is the moral of this story? I have
once again proven that I am still no good at day trading. Stick with
swing trades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="day trading"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>An undisciplined trade: Shorted EUR/USD @ 1.499, stopped 1.505 (-62 pips)</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-undisciplined-trade-shorted-eurusd-1499-stopped-1505-62-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-26T11:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-26:an-undisciplined-trade-shorted-eurusd-1499-stopped-1505-62-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started to doubt this move mere minutes after placing it, which rarely
happens. And not because of the price action. It was solely for my
reasoning for this trade. On a quick mental review of this entry, I
noticed that they sounded more like excuses than reasons. First sign of
it was that I laid in a 100% position to fade a strong trend on the
daily on the basis of my 3-hour chart. My strategy is to not risk more
than 50% (preferably 25% - 33%) to fade a trend on the daily. Lack of
discipline #1. Next, I already had six 50% positions open at the time.
That would roughly translate to 3% of my account, without even taking
into account the high correlations (working on a spreadsheet for this).
By adding this 7th position, I've broken my fundamental rule of risk
management to not risk more than 3% of the totals funds at any single
moment. Lastly, it was the end of the trading day on Friday. Carrying
trades over the weekend is well known be even more risky than usual
because so much could happen over the two days. To add a low probability
trade on a loaded to the neck account into the weekend is practically
suicidal. I'm just glad that I had a hard stop to limit my risk. At
least I did something right here. In terms of the dollar amount lost,
the loss for this trade is \$44.17 on paper. And after this stupid move,
I have given up all my +500 pips gain (also on paper) from the week
before. Much work remains to be done to improve my trading performance.
A last note to self from this what-not-to-do lesson. All trades should
be taken with logic and reasons. I failed to do that in this trade by
convincing myself that USD should reverse over the weekend. On top of
it, I took as big of a position as my system allows to gamble on this
intuition. These are two breaches of trading rules that could ruin an
account. It's good that I'm stopped out with a loss in this trade
because if this became profitable, it could boost my ego and this
problem would only get worse. Another silver lining in this is that I am
beginning to trade forex with &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper trading&lt;/a&gt; instead of diving in
with real money first. In addition to testing my forex strategies (which
I haven't followed as diligently as I should), I'm learning much about
my weaknesses in trading in general by keeping a detailed journal and
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;statistics of my trades&lt;/a&gt;. Update: EUR/USD cratered to 1.4844 today.
Another shortcoming with an undisciplined trade is the opportunity cost.
If I weren't so preoccupied with the stop loss from this morning, I
would have followed my setup and shorted EUR/USD today as it went
spiraling down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="EUR/USD"][&lt;img alt="EUR/USD" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-26-eurusd1.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-26-eurusd1.png"&gt;EUR/USD&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EUR/USD, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="EUR/USD,
3-hour" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-26-eurusd_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-26-eurusd_3h.png"&gt;EUR/USD, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry></feed>