<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/blog_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2012-08-04T12:42:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Quantisan.com is now compiled and statically served</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/quantisancom-is-now-compiled-and-statically-served/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-04T12:42:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2012-08-04:quantisancom-is-now-compiled-and-statically-served/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just migrated this blog from a self-hosted Wordpress site to a Pelican statically generated blog. It took me a whole weekend to do it because I have almost 600 posts. Much is still broken at the moment but at least the site seems presentable so I pushed it through. The fixes will just have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered using Jekyll as it appears to be the most popular static site generator. A look at its github page though shows no patch has been made for months. Development on Jekyll appears to have paused for some reason. Furthermore, I didn't have much luck getting &lt;a href="https://github.com/thomasf/exitwp"&gt;exitwp&lt;/a&gt;, which is a wordpress xml to jekyll importer, to gracefully parse my many custom posting tags. I also gave &lt;a href="http://www.ruhoh.com"&gt;Ruhoh&lt;/a&gt; a quick trial, but it also relies on exitwp to import wordpress posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found that &lt;a href="http://doc.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; had its own importer tool using &lt;a href="https://github.com/jgm/pandoc"&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;, which I tested works much better for the non-standard tags in my posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, here are the steps I took to migrate to Pelican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export Wordpress into a XML file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;transfer comments to Disqus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install Pelican 3.0.0 dev build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use pelican-import to convert the XML file into markdown posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moved some posts around into its directory/category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use Textmate to do a bunch of batch fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;configure Pelican and made a Makefile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;install ghp-import&lt;/del&gt; rolled my own gh-pages script into Makefile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;customised a &lt;a href="https://github.com/Quantisan/pelican-svbtle"&gt;pelican theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setup Github for custom domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated DNS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all of that, this site is now &lt;a href="https://github.com/Quantisan/www.quantisan.com"&gt;hosted and served on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="blog"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="wordpress"></category></entry></feed>