<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/broker_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-04-14T07:28:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Comparing Trading API from 6 Online Forex Brokerages</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/comparing-trading-api-from-6-online-forex-brokerages/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-14T07:28:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-04-14:comparing-trading-api-from-6-online-forex-brokerages/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Choosing a discount broker for forex trading is time consuming. As the
forex market is not centralized, choosing a discount broker is sort of
like picking a stall in a farmer's market. They all offer the same
product, but prices, features, quality, and services can vary
considerably between fx brokerages. One criteria that I consider
seriously is the Application Programming Interface (API) offered by the
broker. Most people couldn't care less about API because they never
intend to develop their own automated trading program. However, if this
is something that interests you, then I'd like to save you some time
here with the following table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Forex brokers
API table"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-04-13-FX_API_table.png" /&gt;][][/caption] All the dollar values are in U.S. dollar.
I highlighted the important limitation of each API. I have different
level of experience with each of these six APIs. As of this writing, I
am using &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/jforex/"&gt;JForex&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143/"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/in-a-forex-brokers-and-trading-platforms-jumble/"&gt;various personal reasons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="API"></category><category term="broker"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I am staying with Oanda a while longer before moving to Dukascopy</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-am-staying-with-oanda-a-while-longer-before-moving-to-dukascopy/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-10T21:27:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-10:why-i-am-staying-with-oanda-a-while-longer-before-moving-to-dukascopy/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just sent in my paper work to &lt;a href="http://fxtrade.oanda.com/"&gt;Oanda&lt;/a&gt; to open a live forex account
with them last week. Then I heard from @InEgoVeritas the news about
&lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt; (get 35% discount on commission with that link) reducing
their minimum lot size to micro-lots. After doing more research
comparing Oanda and Dukascopy in the last 24 hours, I think I will go
with Dukascopy in the long term. But I won't make the switch just yet.
Here are my reasons why. Before getting to that, I need to describe my
situation. Choosing a forex broker is like buying a car, we are all
unique and what fits me might not be right for you. Long story short
though. My goal all along is to split my funds 50/50 between interactive
trading and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated trading&lt;/a&gt;. Since Oanda's API access cost \$600
per month, I was to open an additional account with &lt;a href="http://www.mbtrading.com/"&gt;MB Trading&lt;/a&gt; for
automated trading once I have developed something consistent. In
addition to this latest news from Dukascopy, they also lowered their
minimal opening balance down to \$5,000, and began beta testing for
Metatrader 4 recently (Update: Dukascopy abandoned MT4)! Both Oanda and
Dukascopy are very reputable forex brokers. But Dukascopy has the huge
advantage of providing a free API access. That is one big motivation for
me to go trade with them. Then I can just do everything in one account!
But as I said, I will proceed with live trading with Oanda as planned
soon (once I am out of this drawdown from being &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/early-bird-does-not-get-the-worm-in-forex-trading/"&gt;too early in shorting
Aussie&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;other pairs&lt;/a&gt;). The reason is that Dukascopy has always
been catered towards institutional or big pocket forex traders. This
aggressive move to welcome retail traders and small timers could be good
and bad. The good part is more business and more buzz for their service,
obviously. The bad part though, is that widening the door to a new
market can turn out stinking the entire operation. It would be analogous
to Mercedes suddenly decided to compete in the budget cars market... oh
wait, they did that! (Mercedes &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercedes-Benz_B-Class"&gt;B-class&lt;/a&gt;, enough said) More
specifically regarding Dukascopy, I am most concerned of the impact on
the quality and speed of their trading service. As well as their
customer service. Let's face it, we know that new forex traders (such as
myself) whine a lot and expect a lot for little to nothing. Since I have
my paper work done with Oanda already, it can't hurt to just wait a few
more months to see how the changes go. Nevertheless, I am thrilled of
the new changes with Dukascopy! In the mean time, I will continue to
work on my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/risk-management/"&gt;risk management&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-psychology/"&gt;trading psychology&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;trading
strategy&lt;/a&gt; (great plug, isn't it?). Update December 2010: I moved my
account over to Dukascopy and have been with them for a few months. So
far so good. My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/jforex/"&gt;automated trading development with JForex&lt;/a&gt; has been
going well too.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="broker"></category><category term="dukascopy"></category><category term="oanda"></category></entry></feed>