<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/canada_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-03-29T07:40:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Ranking investment options for my self-directed RRSP</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/ranking-investment-options-for-my-self-directed-rrsp/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-29T07:40:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-29:ranking-investment-options-for-my-self-directed-rrsp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If the idea of handing your RRSP contributions over to a sales person
(a.k.a. financial advisor) at a bank isn't appealing to you, then it is
time to consider your investment choices. I am about to contribute for
the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/considering-investment-options-for-my-first-rrsp/"&gt;first time ever into my RRSP&lt;/a&gt; this year. So I performed my due
diligence by researching and evaluating my choices. This post is a
ranking of my findings. I evaluate each investment strategy according to
three criterias, in descending order of importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk&lt;/strong&gt;. Will I lose sleep at night if I put all my money in it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward&lt;/strong&gt;. How much can I potentially gain?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effort&lt;/strong&gt;. How much time and energy do I need to spend on it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My overall portfolio is exposed to enough risk already from my other
trading activities. So my risk appetite is leaning towards a
conservative approach. Also note that I factor in costs as a part of my
risk assessment. I place a 40% emphasis on this criteria. Next, I
consider the return of each investment vehicle using a 40% weight. For
obvious reasons. Lastly, I prefer something that requires as little time
and effort as possible. I weight this criteria at 20%. As I've said
numerous times, I don't like the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/not-pay-trading-income-taxes-through-a-tfsa-trading-account/"&gt;limitations in a registered
account&lt;/a&gt;. It is like trying to invest with one hand tied behind my
back. I do not want to put much effort to manage this account because I
can do better in my regular trading. The resulting ranking of the six
types of markets &lt;em&gt;that I am considering&lt;/em&gt; for my RRSP (and TFSA) is as
follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guaranteed savings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indices or sectors (through passive mutual funds or ETF's)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed income (using a mutual fund or ETF bond index)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actively managed mutual funds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing of note about investing in physical gold within a registered
account is that it can only be done at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;Questrade&lt;/a&gt; as far as I know.
Although I doubt they are the only one. Here is the table I used to
estimate this ranking. I give each category a score from 1 (bad) to 5
(good) based on my own experience and my sentiment of future market
condition. So yes, it is a very crude guess at best. Nevertheless, the
table shows that my best choice is to either put my RRSP money in a
savings account or invest in indices using passive mutual funds (like
the TD e-Series) or ETF's. However, I plan to do both. I will trade
indices in my RRSP and put my TFSA money in a high yield savings
account. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="493" caption="RRSP
investment choices ranking"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-26-RRSPchoicesranking.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="RRSP"></category><category term="tax"></category></entry><entry><title>My first analysis of the S&amp;P/TSX 60 Index</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-first-analysis-of-the-sptsx-60-index/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-27T11:04:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-27:my-first-analysis-of-the-sptsx-60-index/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seeing that I will be trading (not investing) the Canadian market in my
RRSP, I am starting to follow the S&amp;amp;P/TSX 60 Index. I will adapt a
method that I have been using for the S&amp;amp;P 500. Namely technical analysis
(price), internal sentiments (depth), and intermarket analysis (breath).
Nothing fancy, really. I will discuss my method and analysis in this
post. The goal is not to find a holy grail trading method, but to get a
feel of the ebbs and flows of the market. Let's review the TSX from
three angles. First is a standard price chart. As I was saying in the
beginning of the month, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-reason-against-stocking-into-a-registered-trading-account-this-year/"&gt;my long term view of the TSX is still
bearish&lt;/a&gt;. The one and only condition to invalidate my bearish outlook
is that the TSX stay clear of the 12,000 resistance price level on the
weekly chart. As you can see in Figure 1 below, that hasn't happened yet
despite a continuing intermediate term (in weeks) bullishness. On the
other hand, the intermediate term up move in the market is undeniable.
The market has been making higher highs and higher lows for months now.
So the fight continues as we wait to see which side will win. The 12,000
resistance or the relentless rally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX 60
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_wkly.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows a reason for my bearishness. As the price of TSX 60 moves
up in the past few months, the percentage of companies on the TSX
Composite (representing over 70% market capitalization on the Toronto
Stock Exchange) that are over their 200 day moving average has been
forming a toppy pattern (top of Figure 2). Similarly, the 50 day moving
average percentage confirms this price divergence from a shorter term
perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX internal
sentiment"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_internal.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_internal.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Lastly, I consider the dynamics between
the financial and energy sectors, two of the biggest components on the
TSX. Here is why I picked those two sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing that the financial sector is the bane of global economy in recent
months, price moves in this sector represent public risk appetite.
Conversely, the energy sector is the foundation of the Canadian economy.
As such, I use it as a crude measure of risk aversion. So a ratio
between the TSX financial index versus the TSX energy index is my way of
estimating risk appetite versus risk aversion. I call this ratio my risk
meter. Basically, a high value is good and a low value is bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 shows that the up trend in recent months is actually confirmed
by an increasing risk meter. So as much as I've been ringing the bear
bell, this rally is legitimate so far. As such, the market is decidedly
bullish in the intermediate term (as if anyone doesn't know by now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX Financial
vs. Energy"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_sectors.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_sectors.png"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, my long term view is bearish but my intermediate term view
is bullish. Even though a month has passed since my last peak of the
TSX, things remain the same. The line in the sand at 12,000 is still
being fought for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not short or long the market until a clearer scenario presents
itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="3D analysis"></category><category term="Canada"></category><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>Considering investment options for my first RRSP</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/considering-investment-options-for-my-first-rrsp/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-26T07:29:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-26:considering-investment-options-for-my-first-rrsp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been fortunate enough to not have to think about taxes for the
longest time. Unfortunately though, that is because of my long stay in
academia plus a couple of years of a low salary research position. I
didn't have to pay much income taxes, if at all. Things are different
now that I am working in a full time job with a decent pay. I am
reminded of the impact of our high Canadian taxes from the missing chunk
on every paycheck. That is why I am looking into what to do with my RRSP
contribution lately. Last month, I analyzed the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/is-a-5000-questrade-tfsa-trading-account-cost-effective-part-1/"&gt;cost-benefit of a Tax
Free &lt;em&gt;Trading&lt;/em&gt; Account&lt;/a&gt;. I concluded that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/is-a-5000-questrade-tfsa-trading-account-cost-effective-%e2%80%93-part-4/"&gt;a TFSA trading account is
not worth my while&lt;/a&gt; for the moment. So I will probably just stash my
TFSA contribution in a good old savings account for now. That is not the
case with a RRSP. One big difference that change the whole argument
around with RRSP is that any contribution that I make into it is tax
deductible! I won't go into details here because I hate taxes. Refer to
the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Registered_Retirement_Savings_Plan"&gt;Wikipedia entry on RRSP&lt;/a&gt; if you are unfamiliar with it.
Essentially, I am guaranteed about 30% (or your marginal tax rate) of
"profit" by way of tax refund for the amount of money which I put into
my RRSP account. I don't know about you, but 30% is a massive return for
me! And it's risk free! (Technically it's just a refund of my own money,
but still) The benefit of having a RRSP is obvious. What I have been
pondering about is where should I put my money in my RRSP? As I
discussed in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/not-pay-trading-income-taxes-through-a-tfsa-trading-account/"&gt;Benefits of trading in a TFSA account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, there are many
limitations to a self-directed registered account. Although there are
certainly other options than just trading stocks in a registered
account. Here are the options that I have considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Savings account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutual funds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exchange traded funds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual stocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next post, I will &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/ranking-investment-options-for-my-self-directed-rrsp/"&gt;rank my preferences for each retirement investment option&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="RRSP"></category><category term="tax"></category></entry><entry><title>How Greece bailout is affecting the Canadian markets</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-greece-bailout-is-affecting-the-canadian-markets/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-18T09:44:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-18:how-greece-bailout-is-affecting-the-canadian-markets/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Parity, parity, parity. That's all I hear about in Canada these days.
The &lt;a href="http://www.businessweek.com/news/2010-03-13/loonie-approaches-parity-on-bets-central-bank-to-increase-rates.html"&gt;media is saying&lt;/a&gt; (Businessweek) that the strength in loonie is
due to a higher than expected inflation data and so a possible rise in
our interest rate by the Bank of Canada this year is in the cards. But
that's just part of the story. As I was saying in my previous post,
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-should-i-care-about-other-markets-if-i-only-trade-___/"&gt;markets don't operate in a vacuum&lt;/a&gt;. The biggest news so far this year
on the global economy is the Greece bailout. Or more specifically, &lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/brussels/2010/03/18/is-there-a-greece-bailout/"&gt;is
there a bailout&lt;/a&gt; (WSJ) and &lt;em&gt;by whom&lt;/em&gt;? Greece is the 27th biggest
economy according to Wikipedia. Their GDP is 24% of Canada's. They are
by no means a small country. A default of this magnitude would have a
domino effect on the weak PIGS (Portugal, Ireland/Italy, Greece and
Spain) countries and beyond. Traders will lose confidence if Greece is
not saved. Then everyone will unload their holdings in those PIGS
countries and massive selling will drive their markets even further
down. A vicious cycle of downward spiral is thus formed in the short
term. Given that even a small time trader such as myself is aware of the
grim consequence, it is likely that Greece will be saved. So the next
question is, by whom? That is the big question which is still up in the
air and fiercely debated this month. The two candidates are the European
Central Bank (ECB) and the International Monetary Fund (IMF). As far as
we know, the ECB doesn't seem to want to take the burden upon itself.
The European Union isn't doing exactly well lately, in case you haven't
noticed. Its best performing country, Germany, doesn't want to penalize
their hardworking taxpayers for &lt;a href="https://www.cia.gov/library/publications/the-world-factbook/docs/notesanddefs.html?countryName=Greece&amp;amp;countryCode=gr&amp;amp;regionCode=eu#2116"&gt;the mistakes of Greece&lt;/a&gt; (CIA World
Factbook). So that leaves the IMF, the last line of defense for troubled
economies. If the IMF bails out Greece, that means the United States is
on the hook too as they are the biggest economy and backer of the IMF.
Europe's problem will become an American problem too. More bailouts for
the U.S. means more spending. Having spent &lt;a href="http://www.usdebtclock.org/"&gt;trillions already pumping up
the financial markets&lt;/a&gt; (U.S. debt clock) in the past couple of years,
this would tank the U.S. dollar into the abyss. Likewise, if the ECB
confirms that they will contain the problem and that IMF isn't involved.
The Euros will tank and the dollar will rise. But that's just guess work
for now. The one thing that's for sure is that a massive amount of money
will be spent to save Greece. Excessive money means inflation and higher
cost of commodities in the long run. Seeing that the Canadian market is
heavily commodity-related and that our loonie is even known as a
commodity currency, that is the reason behind why inflation is rising
fast and our economy is being propped up. Not necessarily because we are
doing terrific, but because we are sitting on a pile of gold and oil.
Real, tangible wealth in any kind of economy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bailout"></category><category term="Canada"></category><category term="fundamental analysis"></category><category term="Greece"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Scraping the Toronto Stock Exchange: Extracting 3,660 companies' data</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-11T07:29:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-11:data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the tasks that I've always wanted to make more efficient in my
stock trading is the work of scanning for stocks to trade. One look at
my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;trading strategy posts&lt;/a&gt; and you'll see that I have devised many
stock scanning systems in the past few years. The most recent system
that I've used is one that uses &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/week-of-sept-13-2009-in-play-stocks-breakout-results/"&gt;options data to filter stocks&lt;/a&gt;.
However, it is not automated. So it takes a lot of time to gather and
analyze the data. Furthermore, the set of tools that I use is limited to
U.S. stocks. Now that I have taken an interest in the Canadian stock
market, I can't seem to find any public tool that I like. Thus, I am
biting the bullet now and taking my time to develop a custom system once
and for all. Before we can analyze stock data, we need to extract them
first. Where better else for that than go straight to the source at
TMX.com, the parent company of Toronto Stock Exchange (TSX) and TSX
Venture Exchange (TSXV). TMX.com provide a list of publicly traded
companies in ten Excel files. The files are divided by sectors. Each
contain a number of fundamental company data, such as market
capitalization and outstanding shares. So step 1 is to extract those
data. This is where I am at now. I attached the source code for an
alpha/developmental release below for anyone interested. It is a working
program to scrape the data from TMX.com's files. But it's still a
work-in-progress. That's why I am calling it a version 0.1. The next
milestone is to program a Stocks class to hold, organize, and manage all
three thousand, six hundred, and sixty companies' data. This is an easy
task to do by extending the built-in dictionary class in Python.
However, I haven't gotten to that chapter yet in my scientific
programming with Python learning book. I stopped at chapter 8 to work on
this project. Chapter 9 is the inheritence and hierarchical material.
The goal of this project is to build an automated data scraping program
for TSX and TSXV data from various sources into my computer. Once I have
my data, that's when the real fun starts. Regarding the code below, I
know that source code is useless for most people. Once the project is
complete, I will compile the code into a standalone application and post
it on this site. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/feed/"&gt;Subscribe to my RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; so that you can keep
up-to-date with the progress of this project and my other ramblings on
trading. [python] # extractTMX.py # version: 0.1 alpha release #
revision date: March, 2010 # by Paul, Quantisan.com """A data scraping
module to extract company listing excel files from TMX.COM""" import
xlrd # to read Excel file #import sys from finClasses import Stock #
custom Stock class def _verify(): """Verification function for a
rundown of the module""" pass # copy test block here when finished def
findCol(sheet, key): """Find the column corresponding to header string
'key'""" firstRow = sheet.row_values(0) for col in
range(len(firstRow)): if key in firstRow[col]: return col # return
first sighting else: # not found raise ValueError("%s is not found!" %
key) def scrapeXLS(book): """Data scraping function for TMX Excel
file""" listingDict = {} # dict of ('ticker': market cap) for index in
range(book.nsheets): sh = book.sheet_by_index(index) mcCol =
findCol(sh, "Market Value") assert type(mcCol) is int, "mcCol is a %s" %
type(mcCol) osCol = findCol(sh, "O/S Shares") assert type(osCol) is int,
"osCol is a %s" % type(osCol) secCol = findCol(sh, "Sector") # multiple
matches but taking first assert type(secCol) is int, "secCol is a %s" %
type(secCol) hqCol = findCol(sh, "HQ\nRegion") assert type(hqCol) is
int, "hqCol is a %s" % type(hqCol) for rx in range(1, sh.nrows): sym =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=4)) # symbol s =
sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=2) # exchange col. if s == "TSX": exch =
"T" elif s == "TSXV": exch = "V" else: raise TypeError("Unknown exchange
value") mc = sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=mcCol) # market cap # check
for empty market cap cell mc = int(mc) if type(mc) is float else 0 os =
int(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=osCol)) # O/S shares sec =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=secCol)) # sector hq =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=hqCol)) # HQ region listingDict[sym] =
Stock(symbol=sym,exchange=exch, mktCap=mc,osShares=os,
sector=sec,hqRegion=hq) return listingDict def fetchFiles(fname): infile
= open(fname, 'r') # text file of XLS file names listing = {} for line
in infile: # 1 file name per line if line[0] == '#': continue # skip
commented lines line = line.strip() # strip trailing \n print "Reading
'%s' ..." % line xlsFile = "TMX/" + line # in TMX directory book =
xlrd.open_workbook(xlsFile) # import Excel file
listing.update(scrapeXLS(book)) # append scraped the data to dict
return listing #if __name__ == '__main__': # verify block #
if len(sys.argv) == 2 and sys.argv[1] == 'verify': # _verify() if
__name__ == '__main__': # test block listing =
fetchFiles('TMX/TMXfiles.txt') [/python]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="data scraping"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="source code"></category><category term="TSX"></category><category term="TSX Venture"></category></entry><entry><title>Forex Trading: Income or Capital Gain Tax in Canada?</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/forex-trading-income-or-capital-gain-tax-in-canada/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-08T10:29:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-08:forex-trading-income-or-capital-gain-tax-in-canada/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've always known that foreign exchange trading is treated as capital
gain tax in Canada. But just to be sure before filing my taxes soon,
I've decided to double check the facts from Canada Revenue Agency. As
you know, the difference between income tax and capital gain tax is
substantial. Income tax is taxed at your marginal tax rate. Whereas
capital gain tax is a generous half of your marginal tax rate. That
works out to a 10% to 20% difference. Taxes in Canada is generally
simple to do. The problem though, is sifting through the cacophony of
information within the Canada Revenue Agency to find out the applicable
rules. I've copy and pasted a couple of relevant excerpts from the 2010
CRA &lt;a href="http://www.cra-arc.gc.ca/menu/ITSC-e.html"&gt;Income Tax Interpretation Bulletin&lt;/a&gt; for the record. Basically,
forex trading can be treated as either income or capital gain tax in
Canada (surprise). According to &lt;a href="http://www.cra-arc.gc.ca/E/pub/tp/it95r/it95r-e.html"&gt;IT-95R Foreign exchange gains and
losses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where it can be determined that a gain or loss on foreign exchange
arose as a direct consequence of the purchase or sale of goods abroad,
or the rendering of services abroad, and such goods or services are
used in the &lt;strong&gt;business operations&lt;/strong&gt; of the taxpayer, such gain or loss
is brought into income account. If, on the other hand, it can be
determined that a gain or loss on foreign exchange arose as a direct
consequence of the&lt;strong&gt;purchase or sale of capital assets&lt;/strong&gt;, this gain or
loss is either a capital gain or capital loss, as the case may be.
Generally, the nature of a foreign exchange gain or loss is &lt;strong&gt;not
affected by the length of time&lt;/strong&gt; between the date the property is
acquired (or disposed of) and the date upon which payment (or receipt)
is effected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it is very vague. That's why forex trading can be
considered income or capital gain tax. It is up to you and your
accountant to figure out which works for you. A noteworthy point in the
above excerpt is that the holding period is not taken into account.
&lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;So there's no 30-day rule
like in the states whereby frequent trading would miss out the capital
loss credit if they re-purchase the same asset within 30-day of
disposal.&lt;/span&gt; Update: Looks like I have misconstrued the above
article with regard to capital loss. As Olga pointed out in the
comments, Chapter 5 of T4037 defines &lt;em&gt;Superficial Loss&lt;/em&gt;. In which if you
&lt;em&gt;repurchase&lt;/em&gt; your property (e.g. stock) within 30-days after a sale at a
loss, then that initial loss cannot be deducted as a capital loss. More
about the &lt;a href="http://www.wheredoesallmymoneygo.com/superficial-loss-rules-in-canada/"&gt;Superficial Loss rules in Canada&lt;/a&gt; can be found at
WhereDoesAllMyMoneyGo.com. Further down the page in IT-95R, we have the
following bullet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A taxpayer who has transactions in foreign currency or foreign
currency futures that do not form part of business operations, or are
merely the result of sundry dispositions of foreign currency by an
individual, will be accorded by the Department the &lt;strong&gt;same treatment as
that of a "speculator" in commodity futures&lt;/strong&gt; see 7 and 8 or IT-346R.
However, if such a taxpayer has special "Inside" information
concerning foreign exchange, he will be required to report his gains
and losses on income account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cra-arc.gc.ca/E/pub/tp/it346r/it346r-e.html"&gt;IT-346R Commodity Futures and Certain Commodities&lt;/a&gt; explains the tax
treatment of speculation in the commodity markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a general rule, it is acceptable for speculators to report all
their gains and losses from transactions in commodity futures or in
commodities as&lt;strong&gt;capital gains and losses&lt;/strong&gt; with the result that only
one-half the gain is taxable, and one-half the loss is allowable
subject to certain restrictions, (hereinafter called "capital
treatment") provided such reporting is followed consistently from year
to year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there, we have it. Amateur forex traders, such as myself, can report
our forex trading gain/loss as capital gains and losses. The reason
being that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex"&gt;forex trading&lt;/a&gt; isn't part of my business operation because
I have another primary source of income (e.g. salary from another job).&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="tax"></category></entry><entry><title>Another reason against stocking into a registered trading account this year</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-reason-against-stocking-into-a-registered-trading-account-this-year/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-05T07:32:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-05:another-reason-against-stocking-into-a-registered-trading-account-this-year/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's another reason why I am so &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/is-a-5000-questrade-tfsa-trading-account-cost-effective-part-1/"&gt;reluctant to put money into a TFSA
trading account&lt;/a&gt; to invest in Canadian stocks. As you know, in a
registered trading account, such as a RRSP self-directed trading account
or a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;Questrade TFSA trading account&lt;/a&gt; (aff), you cannot short shares
and can only buy because you can't trade on margin. As such, a
registered trading account is an account for buy-only trading. It
doesn't take a genius to figure out that a buy-only trading strategy is
best used ... in a bull market. As trading wisdom goes, trade with the
trend. So the question is, are we in a bull market in 2010? Figures 1
and 2 shows the weekly chart of TSX Index and the TSX Venture Index,
respectively. Referring to Fig. 1, TSX is bumping up against some
headwind at a 12,000 resistance. Unless TSX can stay above 12,000
cleanly (a weekly low above that level at least), I am still bearish in
the market because that financial crisis back in 2008 (&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-breakdown-of-a-major-multi-year-support-are-we-going-down-and-i-mean-really-down/"&gt;remember those
days&lt;/a&gt;?) is still overshadowing long term prices and trader sentiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-TSX_wk.png" /&gt;][][/caption] TSX Venture is depressed even more as seen
in Figure 2 below. Just look at the huge gap from current price to the
200 week moving average (red line). This isn't a good sign as lack of
interest in high-risk stocks means traders are generally cautious. Yes,
it's true that the equity market has been running up, up, and up for a
good year. However, the fact that TSX is sitting at the same level as in
2001 proves that the long term, multi-year bull market has been cleanly
broken. We might very well see pockets of multi-month rallies
materialize (like we're seeing now), but unless proven otherwise, the
long term trend is not looking green for the markets. It will not be
easy money in the stock market like back in the pre-tech bubble 1990's.
As opined by Bill Cara, the &lt;a href="http://www.caracommunity.com/"&gt;time for buy-and-hold is gone&lt;/a&gt;. It is
well known in the community that the coming years will be volatile with
big ups and downs. That is my little secret for moving to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;trade
forex&lt;/a&gt;last year and the main reason why I am reluctant to set aside
money on a one-sided stock trading account. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX Venture,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-CDNX_wk.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-CDNX_wk.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="TSX"></category><category term="TSX Venture"></category></entry><entry><title>Not pay trading income taxes through a TFSA trading account</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/not-pay-trading-income-taxes-through-a-tfsa-trading-account/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-19T10:12:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-19:not-pay-trading-income-taxes-through-a-tfsa-trading-account/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;RRSP contribution deadline on March 1st is fast approaching. Like most
Canadians, this is pretty much the only time when I give my&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Registered_Retirement_Savings_Plan"&gt;Registered
Retirement Savings Plan&lt;/a&gt; some attention. Right now, my RRSP balance
stands at \$0. That's right, nothing. I've been putting my money at work
for 10 years trading all sorts of markets but willfully ignoring the
biggest cost to any trader. Taxes. Now that my marginal tax rate is for
the first time running above 30%, and with no tax break in sight, it's
time that I take a hard look at my tax strategies to reduce my trading
costs. Don't worry, this isn't yet another post about RRSP. (But if
you're indeed looking for RRSP information, I point you to a Canadian
personal finance blog, &lt;a href="http://www.milliondollarjourney.com/"&gt;MillionDollarJourney&lt;/a&gt;) The reason why I
haven't placed money into my RRSP is same as why I don't invest in real
estates. Which is, a lack of liquidity. As the name suggest, RRSP is for
retirement. Here's the problem simplistically put. If I take money out
while I'm still working, I get taxed at my full marginal tax rate for
those money. Even if they were supposed to be capital gain. Thus I
effectively lose my 50% tax discount from my investment capital gain. So
money into my RRSP would effectively be locked in while my salary is
still my main source of income! I don't have a wad of cash where I can
just stash away yet. So that's why my RRSP stands at \$0 this year.
Although I am thinking of opening an RRSP soon... But I digressed. The
fact is, taxes in Canada is ridiculously high. So I need to do something
about it soon. While looking for RRSP information, I came across
Questrade's Tax Free Trading Account. It is a reincarnation of the &lt;a href="http://www.tfsa.gc.ca/"&gt;Tax
Free Savings Account&lt;/a&gt;. As far as I know, Questrade is the only
discount broker offering this type of account. Basically, it is a
trading account in which there is no income taxes involved and any
profit taken out would not count towards annual income too. Sounds too
good to be true? Here are 3 limitations for a TFSA trading account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit of \$5,000 contribution per year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra costs for trading the U.S. markets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cash account only, no margin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will discuss #2 shortly. But #3 is what matters the most to me as a
trader. No margin means no leverage, no shorting, and no futures and
forex trading. No shorting?! One-way trading is not a good thing for a
trader. This is obviously a ploy to get people to buy, buy, buy. And no
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;forex trading&lt;/a&gt;?! Yet, I can't expect to have my cake and eat it too.
Yes, this TFSA trading thing has strings attached. But. It's tax-free!
That's enough incentive for me to consider incorporating it into my
portfolio. Make no mistake, this will not be my primary, or even
secondary, trading account. My plan is to use it as an
&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;ultra-conservative&lt;/span&gt;
investment vehicle only. It's about time that I replace my abysmal 1%
yield savings account! Before&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade"&gt;opening a Questrade TFSA trading
account&lt;/a&gt; (affliate link) though, I need to do my homework on Canadian
stocks. Because TFSA is a Canadian government offer, trading U.S.
markets would incur extra costs (a devious way of "Buy Canadian"). As
such, the only cost effective way for me to maximize a TFSA trading
account is to trade TSX and TSX Ventures stocks. This is yet another
item on my to-do list. Come up with a strategy to trade this account
&lt;strong&gt;with minimal risks&lt;/strong&gt; (can't stress this enough)using Canadian stocks.
I actually have some ideas already. But I'll save that for another time.
In my next series of posts, I ask a fundamental investment question like
any trader should. Is a \$5000 Questrade TFSA trading account cost
effective? P.S. For more information on Questrade, youngandthrifty.ca
offers a &lt;a href="http://youngandthrifty.ca/questrade-review-2/"&gt;review of this discount broker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="Questrade"></category><category term="RRSP"></category><category term="tax"></category><category term="TFSA"></category></entry></feed>