<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/cfa_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-03-14T14:34:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Today is day 1 of Quantisan, the company</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/today-is-day-1-of-quantisan-the-company/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-14T14:34:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-03-14:today-is-day-1-of-quantisan-the-company/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
&gt; The reasonable man adapts himself to the world: the unreasonable one
&gt; persists in trying to adapt the world to himself. Therefore all
&gt; progress depends on the unreasonable man. G. B. Shaw, *Maxims for
&gt; Revolutionists*

While cramming for the CFA level 1 exam the past 3 weeks, I can't let go
of the fact that I'm leaving my work out cold on the table. This sense
of urgency feels like every minute that I delay my trading system
development projects, bits of them will fall apart. This weekend I
finished reading through my Schweser study notes from cover to cover, to
cover to cover, and repeat that 3 more times for a total of 5 books.
It's certainly useful and interesting material. But I can't see the
value of cramming for 3 more months to memorize everything in even more
excruciating detail. No term will be without a definition in my head and
no problem will be without a solution on my BA II Plus calculator. Just
so I can say that I passed my level 1 exam on my resume. What the
curriculum offers is information, but what we need more in this world is
wisdom. I stand by my belief that [credibility is as important as
experience and skills][]. However, that doesn't mean that I need to head
for the path most traveled. Why can't I be unreasonable and push my
limit to do what I've always been set out to do. Credibility can be
gained from attaching professional designations to your name, but it can
also be gained from simply achieving results in the real world. So this
morning, before going to work, I took the first baby step in turning
this little hobby of mine into a real business. I registered a business
entity with our government. After 10 years of [trading][], 5 years
[blogging about the market][], and 3 years in [trading system
development][], today is day 1 of Quantisan Systems! And this -- is how
my business got officially started. My plan towards [unreasonable
goals][] in a world of reasons is finally set in motion.

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CFA"></category><category term="Quantisan Systems"></category></entry><entry><title>Just because it's math does not mean it's not without its caveats</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/just-because-its-math-does-not-mean-its-not-without-its-caveats/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-01T07:21:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-03-01:just-because-its-math-does-not-mean-its-not-without-its-caveats/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am more than half way through my first speed run of the CFA level 1
material. This chapter discusses portfolio management. In particular, I
just read the Markovitz Efficient Frontier. What strikes me most about
this chapter is that these mathematical material are presented so
matter-of-factly. Recalling in chapter 1, Ethics, the idea of prudence
and due diligence was evident. This was exemplified later in the
Financial Statement chapter. Methods of drafting balance sheet, income
statement, and cash flow statement were presented in excrutiating
details before a discussion about ways to analyze them. Just so we can
understand the mechanics of it to spot bias, pitfalls,
misrepresentation, and outright frauds. In fact, a good portion of the
section were reserved for discussing the caveats in financial statement
analysis. As boring as it was to sit through the accounting details,
that was good prudence and good due diligence. Fast forward to this
discussion on Modern Portfolio Theory (MPT), it is simply explained in
the text that expected risk of a portfolio with individual asset
correlations less than 1 will be less than its weighted average risk.
Where are the billboard-sized warnings and neon-red danger signs?
Perhaps &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modern_portfolio_theory#Criticism"&gt;criticisms of MPT&lt;/a&gt; will be discussed later or perhaps I
simply missed it with my \~200 pages/day scanning pace (in which case,
just ignore me). But if I don't see a caveat lector on MPT in bold,
underlined, and boxed fonts later, then I am surely going to be very
disappointed. This is a big deal because of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-volatile-week-and-no-sign-of-the-bull-yet/"&gt;historic events of
2008&lt;/a&gt;. In which we witnessed the havoc caused by countless funds that
blindedly rely on MPT's validity (i.e. diversification of risks on the
naive basis of constant correlations and normally distributed returns),
and &lt;a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/77bf5f98-4441-11e0-931d-00144feab49a.html"&gt;other risk models&lt;/a&gt;, go under. There can be no worse mistake than
underestimating your risk in trading. Let me repeat that, there can be
no worse mistake than underestimating your risk in trading. &lt;em&gt;Careless
use of MPT&lt;/em&gt; (not MPT, per se) leads to exactly that. The problem is that
people take these financial theories to heart too much without reading
the fine prints. Just because it is presented in mathematical formulas
does not mean a theory is law. The least the CFA text can do is to
broaden financial prudence from not only dissecting financial statements
but to encompass other important intellectual matter related to the job
too. I am appalled by the fact that thousands of CFA level 1 hopefuls
might actually believe that you can always reduce portfolio risk and
identify an efficient asset mix from mere correlations and standard
deviations (which in and of themselves are flawed in the real world),
with no strings attached. "Science is the belief in the ignorance of the
experts", Richard Feynman.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CFA"></category><category term="Modern Portfolio Theory"></category></entry><entry><title>Open sesame with three more letters</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/open-sesame-with-three-more-letters/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-21T07:55:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-02-21:open-sesame-with-three-more-letters/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I apologize in advance if I occasionally disappear in the next 15 weeks.
My study guide for a professional exam in financial analysis arrived
last Friday. I spent most of this weekend studying as I need to squeeze
in 300 hours of studying time between now and the exam in June. Topics
of the exam range from professional standards to investment analysis to
asset management. This is a major commitment as 300 hours in 3 months is
no joke. Fortunately, I am familiar with a majority of the material.
Unfortunately, most of the details I have forgotten already as level 1
of this exam covers the very basic. For example, I haven't heard terms
like price elasticity and marginal cost in 10 years. The quant section,
at least, I am finding it to be a breeze as I finished skimming through
the 400 pages of material in a few hours and realized that I don't need
to spend anymore time on statistics or technical analysis to answer the
practice questions. Having said that, I do not take this exam lightly
and will have to put most other work on hold. This is a difficult
decision because having spent hours and hours in the past few months
over our trading system, it is coming to shape. In fact, I just tape-out
a major component of it last Friday. Studying with this curriculum would
provide me with a big picture perspective of financial analysis. Still,
I would rather spend the time to study pertinent works like &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0071592539?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=quantisan-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0071592539"&gt;Security
Analysis by Graham and Dodd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=quantisan-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0071592539" /&gt;, or &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0691042896?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=quantisan-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0691042896"&gt;Time Series Analysis by
Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=quantisan-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0691042896" /&gt;, or &lt;a href=""&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs
by Abelson et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=quantisan-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0070004846" /&gt; (aff.), some classics on my shelf that I
still couldn't fully appreciate yet. Better yet, I want to finish my
trading system prototype as soon as possible because I've learned so
much in bringing these systems (having gone through several incarnations
already) to life than anything else I have done previously. However, it
is also because of my desire to do this for the long term that I need to
take the time to garner some industry recognition. As superfluous as
doing an exam might seem for my outside-of-the-box approach to the
market (mostly out of necessity as I have neither the bank roll nor
brain cells to directly compete with the sharks), the fact is, to be
successful in this industry, I need experience, skills, and credibility.
The latter of which is something I lack. Neither Graham, Hamilton, nor
Adelson can provide me with credibility that these three letters can --
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chartered_Financial_Analyst"&gt;CFA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;http:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//www.amazon.com/gp/product/0070004846?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=quantisan-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0070004846&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="CFA"></category></entry></feed>