<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/chf_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-01-22T15:36:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Closed EUR/CHF and GBP/CHF Shorts: Best. Trade. Ever.</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-22T15:36:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-22:closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I was saying earlier this week, I have been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;stockpiling in EUR/CHF
short&lt;/a&gt; in my demo account (Fig. 1). Aside from that, I've also stocked
up some GBP/CHF shorts this week (Fig. 2). Both positions are now closed
because of my adjusted stops. These positions have single-handedly
lifted me half way out of a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/work-harder-trade-fewer-in-a-long-and-excruciating-trading-drawdown/"&gt;deep drawdown&lt;/a&gt; in my demo account. These
trades netted me about 1.5% in my demo funds. Yes, you read that right,
a meager 1.5% gain and I'm calling these my best trades. No, it's not
like I haven't had &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/good-trade/"&gt;good trades&lt;/a&gt; in terms of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-eurjpy-135-00-500-1-pips/"&gt;money made&lt;/a&gt; or the
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/eurusd-95-pips-in-2-hours-an-example-of-swing-and-day-trade-convergence/"&gt;fastest pips&lt;/a&gt;. These shorts aren't even close from just looking at
the numbers. Heck, it would have been a lot more profitable if I shorted
Euro and Pound with a Dollar or Yen counter this week. So why? If you
read my post on &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/analysing-monthly-forex-trading-performance-in-changing-market-conditions/"&gt;measuring trading performance&lt;/a&gt;, you may recall that I
don't measure success by profit alone. It is performance &lt;em&gt;in terms of&lt;/em&gt;
amount risked that matters in trading. These shorts in EUR/CHF and
GBP/CHF are my best forex trades ever (in my 4 months of fx trading so
far) simply because I risked no more than 0.2% at any given time (most
of the time there were no explicit risk as my stops have locked in
profits) to make that 1.5%. 1.5% gained by risking maximum of 0.2% gives
a Reward/Risk ratio of 1.5/0.2 = 7.5! There were several occasions when
I had doubts to add to my position or were pondering about taking
profits to settle my worries. Despite all of that, I soldiered on,
managed my stops like they were my babies, and piled more into the
position according to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;my plan&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/FTC/"&gt;trading setup&lt;/a&gt; (Fig. 1). By the time I started scaling out, I have
built my biggest (non-scalp) position. That gave me a lot of freedom in
scaling out as you can see on my exits shown in Figure 1 (red dots).
This Reward/Risk ratio is the highest I have achieved in recent memory.
I have always read about 10x or even 20x trades at the &lt;a href="http://www.smbtraining.com/blog/"&gt;SMB Capital
blog&lt;/a&gt;. Those guys can achieve this type of reward/risk ratio day in
and day out (I'm not affiliated with them). I guess that's the
difference between the pros and me. This is definitely something I am
strifing to do myself. &lt;strong&gt;Executing consistently high reward/risk
trades.&lt;/strong&gt; How I might do that? By continuing to improve on my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/"&gt;trading
skills&lt;/a&gt; and my understanding of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;forex markets&lt;/a&gt;. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EUR/CHF,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-EURCHF_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="alignnone" width="580"
caption="GBP/CHF, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-GBPCHF_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-GBPCHF_3h.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="good trade"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>How to stockpile a trade position one step at a time</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-18T11:56:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-18:how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Arguably the single most important skill a trader needs to master in
trading any market is to &lt;strong&gt;cut your losses short and let your profits
run&lt;/strong&gt;. This is simply another saying of &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/risk-management/"&gt;managing risks&lt;/a&gt; and
maximizing opportunities. However, this is easier said than done. Ever
tried to cut your losses short but only to see the price run in your
favour soon afterward? Or, that you've built a sizable and profitable
position only to see it turn into a loss? As with much of other trading
skills, managing your trade is not an exact science. That is why you
need to have probabilities in your favour on every step. You enter a
trade because it is &lt;em&gt;likely&lt;/em&gt; to be profitable. You exit a trade when it
is not. If you can apply this axiom on every trade you do, it is
&lt;em&gt;likely&lt;/em&gt; that you will be profitable, with all things being equal. So
what does this have to do with cut your losses short and let your
profits run? In this post, I will discuss one &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;trading strategy&lt;/a&gt; which
I use to do exactly that. The key to this strategy is divide and
conquer. Instead of taking one trade for each position, consider taking
multiple smaller trades by scaling in and out of a position. That way,
you can have more freedom in your trade by using your position size to
your advantage. Here's the gist of the strategy and the rationale for
it. The rule is simple: increase a position by scaling in as the
probability of success increases; and decrease a position by scaling out
as the probability of success decreases. One way to do this is to add on
a position as the price breaks support on a faster timeframe. You keep
adding on this position as long as your trade setup (on a higher time
frame) is valid. At the same time, you limit your risk by &lt;em&gt;lowering the
stop&lt;/em&gt; of your previous trade to breakeven. That way, even though you are
stockpiling a position, the overall risk stays the same. This is an
essential step in the technique. Otherwise the risk would just multiply.
It is as much managing the entries as well as the stops/exits. Let's put
this into perspective with a real-world example. Figure 1 shows the
support levels for my EUR/CHF short on a 3-hour chart. I identified this
trade using my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/FTC"&gt;FTC setup&lt;/a&gt; on the daily chart. The failed break above
1.4800 on January 14 was the signal for entry. I took an initial short
position risking 0.20% of my account as EUR/CHF reverted back below
1.4800 (first support, not marked). Then I kept adding on to this
position below 1.4787, 1.4761, and 1.4742 supports as shown in Fig. 1
with the horizontal dashed red lines. On each subsequent new entry, I
move the stop on the previous entry to b/e. I only risk 0.1% on each of
these additions with half the position size after the initial entry. As
I keep adding, I keep moving the stops one step behind. So on my third
scale-in, my initial stop have locked in some profits at a price level
between my first and second entries. Figure 2 is the same chart but with
the actual filled orders (yellow triangles) and current stops (red
lines) marked. As you can see, I have effectively accumulated a sizable
position size in this short while limiting my risk to just a fraction
(0.2% versus 1.0%) if I were to enter my maximum size all at once.
Furthermore, my confidence and probability of this trade increase
gradually as I see the short-term support levels break one after
another. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURCHF,
3-hour, showing supports"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-18-EURCHF_3h.PNG" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EUR/CHF, 3-hour, showing
orders"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-18-EURCHF_3h_2.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-18-EURCHF_3h_2.PNG"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] There are limitations to this strategy.
First of all, this strategy is mostly suitable for trading setups with
an expected high reward/risk ratio. You might not want to use this for a
range trading strategy as there's probably not enough price move to
break the trade into steps. Secondly, this technique is mostly for an
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated system&lt;/a&gt; or longer term manual strategies (hours or more).
Just so you have sufficient time to manage all these extra work without
adding on an unnecessary amount of stress. Lastly, an obvious downside
to this approach is that your account will take a hit from the spreads
and commissions for each move. So do take those costs into account in
building your own adaptation to this concept. Now that I've discussed my
scaling-in technique, what do you think? &lt;strong&gt;Update January 22:&lt;/strong&gt; I've
closed this position and it turns out to be &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/"&gt;one of my best trade
ever&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="FTC"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Long USD/CHF @ 1.0122, SL 1.0060, TP 1.0225</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-10122-sl-10060-tp-10225/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-18T21:22:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-18:paper-trade-long-usdchf-10122-sl-10060-tp-10225/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seeing that this is my first commitment after the big drawdown, I'll
bring back my tradition of writing a post to log my rationale and market
conditions on this entry for later review. I sifted through the weekly
charts of all pairs on my watch-list tonight and found that USD/CHF long
is the most promising. Figure 1 shows my daily chart for the setup and
Figure 2 is a 3-hour chart with my entry timing. Let's talk about Figure
1 first. USD/CHF is making a triple bottom with a positive divergence as
shown. I have also marked the current major support at 1.0010. USD/CHF
has trade below it for about a week now but failed to break any lower.
Today is the first day when we've opened somewhat above it. Secondly,
note that we have broken above a descending channel as shown in Figure
1. USD/CHF has also tested the 1.0010 support twice already at both
sides of that channel. And accompanied with a positive divergence as I
said. The major caution as shown in Figure 1 is that we're still trading
below the 10-day ma. As for the entry timing, observe Figure 2. Notice
that USD/CHF just made a higher low outside and above the descending
fChannel (the two thicker brown lines). This is the signal for entry.
Note that the fChannel is my proprietary channel. This trade is
initiated according to my new Forex Trend Fading (FTF) setup. Position
size: &lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;,
50%&lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt; Entry: 1.0122,
from fRays signal. Stop: 1.0060, below major support Target: 1.0225,
first major resistance, ease off some at that point, add more above it.
Reward / Risk = 103 / 62 = 1.66 \&amp;lt; 3. Not not good enough for my usual
R/R target, but I've been considering lowering it to 1.5. So lets see if
an R/R of 1.5 is a good enough number. I would have been more
comfortable with a 2.0 though. Anyway, let's see how this goes. Update:
I took half of it off at breakeven because of the lower R/R and the new
setup. Only 50% in this trade now. I'm looking to add a EUR or JPY cross
for my other half allocation. Update 11/19: I'm stopped out of this
position @ 1.0150 for +27 pips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="USD/CHF"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF.png"&gt;USD/CHF&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF,
3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF_3h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF_3h.PNG"&gt;USD/CHF, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTB"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Long USD/CHF @ 1.009, out 1.0245 (+155 pips)</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-1009-out-10245-155-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-29T20:12:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-29:paper-trade-long-usdchf-1009-out-10245-155-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. dollar finally picked up some strength last Thursday and I
loaded to ride the trend. One of the earliest trade I made in this wave
is going long on USD/CHF. Figure 1 is taken today after a full week
since the initial move in USD. The vertical line marks the day when I
entered this trade on Thursday 22nd late afternoon. Here are my reasons
for making the entry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parity level 1.0000 was a mere 30 pips away from the low the day
    before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obvious positive divergence on the indicator, Fig. 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breakout on the shorter 3-hour timeframe, Fig. 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I placed the order just above the resistance and beyond the short term
channel. The order was filled the next day in the morning on the 23rd.
In hindsight, I should have used a half position only and added to it
once it broke the longer term descending resistance as shown in Fig. 2.
That's because a short term break is a low probability move given that
the downtrend was strong. However, USD/CHF was testing parity, which is
as strong a support as you can find for many reasons. As you can see
from Fig. 2, the entry was rather good overall (could have been better
as discussed above). However, I think the exit was also a disciplined
move. My original target was 1.026 as noted below. It was just below
that horizontal resistance at 1.0267 which I marked on Fig. 1. Yet,
there's also the longer term trendline marked on both Fig. 1 and Fig. 2.
I had 4-5 positions open at the time and this was one of my strongest
two (the other being CAD/JPY short), so I tried to add to my position
once the pair broke that longer term trendline. However, the line proved
to be strong as USD/CHF retraced and took out my stop as shown in Fig. 2
(red dot, 2nd from right). Nevertheless, the pair remained above 1.0200
and my core position was safe (I moved my stop up). But not all was
well. USD/CHF eventually broke 1.025 but it didn't go far. It printed a
couple more bars on the chart while I kept moving my stop closer and
closer. Also noting that the pair was short-term overbought, I moved my
stop right up to below 1.025 at 1.0245 to lock in most of the profit.
That stop was eventually taken out and the pair took a dive as shown in
Fig. 2. Moving the stop up tight in a short-term overbought condition
was a good choice. I learned this from my recent trades when I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdcad-all-out-1-0872-196-6-pips-and-1-0821-145-6-pips/"&gt;left
profits on the table&lt;/a&gt;. So I got out against my hope for higher pips
even when the talk of USD making a return to strength was ubiquitous. I
traded what I saw and not what I hoped for, and against the opinions of
other people. If only my entry was a bit more patient, this would have
been one of my best executed trades. Below are the data for my entries.
Position size: 100% First Entry: 1.009 First Stop: 1.0030 First Target:
1.0260 Reward / Risk #1 = 170 / 60 = 2.8 \&amp;lt; 3, but close enough. Second
Position Size: 25% Second entry/stop: 1.0232/1.0220 I didn't have a
target in mind for this addition because it was only to add on the
strength of the existing position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="USD/CHF"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-29-usdchf.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-29-usdchf.png"&gt;USD/CHF&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF,
3-hour" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-29-usdchf_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-29-usdchf_3h.png"&gt;USD/CHF, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="good trade"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: USD/CHF sold at 1.03138 (+39.10 pips)</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdchf-sold-at-103138-3910-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-07T22:54:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-07:paper-trade-usdchf-sold-at-103138-3910-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;USD/CHF didn't bounce as planned. Although my trailing stop did keep me
some of the profit. But considering that the high of USD/CHF during my
holding was 1.03598, this isn't exactly good. However, as I'm focusing
on the daily, I don't want to micro-manage my trades either. So I guess
this trade went as planned. USD/CHF has broken down below 1.0280 now and
looks to be moving down. I'm not going to try this again just yet
because I have a couple long USD positions open already with my
short&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-audusd-short-50-0-90040-stop-0-9100/"&gt;AUD/USD&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-nzdusd-100-0-73701-stop-0-7480/"&gt;NZD/USD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF, 3-hour" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-07-usdchf_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-07-usdchf_3h.png"&gt;USD/CHF, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: USD/CHF 50% long @ 1.02747, trailing stop 1.0236</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdchf-50-long-102747-trailing-stop-10236/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-06T17:52:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-06:paper-trade-usdchf-50-long-102747-trailing-stop-10236/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've switched back to using the daily chart as &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/not-to-lose-focus-by-defining-what-i-want-from-trading/"&gt;noted earlier today&lt;/a&gt;
to save myself some hassle. This is the first entry using the daily
chart since the switch. But I actually placed this order before going to
bed and then it was executed last night while I was sleeping. USD is
taking a beating these days and USD/CHF is testing a double bottom. I
entered this trade based on Figure 1 for the following 4 reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSI is shaping up a positive divergence if we can hold this support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSI is as oversold as December 2008.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entry price of 1.027 is at a previous congestion zone based on
    Figure 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USD/CHF took a very fast dive in the past 3 days, which usually
    prelude a retracement up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the trend remains obviously downward. That's why I'm entering
with only a 50% as there's no confirmation just yet. Once there's
confirmation, such as the RSI making a U bottom, I plan to add the other
50% position. Entry: 1.02747, previous congestion zone, see Fig. 2 Stop:
1.0236 Target: 1.045 Reward / Risk = 175.3 / 38.7 = 4.5 &gt; 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF
daily"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF daily" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-06-usdchf.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-06-usdchf.png"&gt;USD/CHF daily&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF
3-hour" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-06-usdchf_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-06-usdchf_3h.png"&gt;USD/CHF 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: USD/CHF short @ 1.0296, out @ 1.03013</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdchf-short-10296-out-103013/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-05T22:26:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-05:paper-trade-usdchf-short-10296-out-103013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My long USD/CHF got stopped out just minutes ago.  The support at 1.0300
has broken.  The intermediate and short term trends are both down.  So I
have entered a short trade for USD/CHF with 1/2 position to see how it
goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially had set the stop at 1.0340 for this trade.  But the support
at 1.0270 looks hard to break on first try.  So I readjusted my target
and stop to aim for an exit at 1.0270.  In fact, IÃƒÂ¢Ã¢â€šÂ¬Ã¢â€žÂ¢ve
placed an order to reverse and go long at 1.027 with a full position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entry: 1.0296, just below round number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop: 1.0340, trailing, set at the previous congestion zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target: 1.0270, previous support level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reward / Risk = 26 / 19 = 1.4 \&amp;lt; 3ÃƒÂ¢Ã¢â€šÂ¬Ã‚Â¦ this is horrible.  So
I just closed my trade at a slight loss at 1.03013 for -\$1.56.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF
1-minute"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF 1-minute" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-05-usdchf_1min.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-05-usdchf_1min.png"&gt;USD/CHF 1-minute&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: USD/CHF all stopped out @ 1.03099 and 1.0300</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdchf-all-stopped-out-103099-and-10300/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-05T21:54:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-05:paper-trade-usdchf-all-stopped-out-103099-and-10300/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My last half of USD/CHF long just got stopped out @ 1.0300. As shown in
Figure 1, USD/CHF is now in bearish territory. I'm going to wait and see
if the support at 1.0300 can hold tonight. Here are the statistics for
my two trades (each 1/2 position counts as a trade): Entry: &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdchf-entry-1-0320-stop-1-0300/"&gt;1.032&lt;/a&gt;,
full position at 6000 units Stopped out: 1.03099 and 1.0300 Net Pips:
-10.10, -20 Net \$: -\$3.03, -\$6.01 Time Held: 32 minutes, 83 hours %
Drawdown: -0.10%, -0.19% % from Top: 0.30%, 0.61% In hindsight, I should
have paid more attention to the short term trend. The break of the
recent trendline should have been a warning sign against going long. As
I'm still trying to work out the details to this strategy, these paper
trades have been tremendously helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="USD/CHF"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-05-usdchf.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-05-usdchf.png"&gt;USD/CHF&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF 30-min"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF
30-min" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-05-usdchf_30min.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-05-usdchf_30min.png"&gt;USD/CHF 30-min&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: USD/CHF entry 1.0320, stop 1.0300</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdchf-entry-10320-stop-10300/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-02T11:41:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-02:paper-trade-usdchf-entry-10320-stop-10300/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I figured I should write this sooner before the market moves more and
skew my thoughts on this entry. After my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdchf-out-at-1-03998-50-pips-and-1-03798-30-pips/"&gt;earlier entry in USD/CHF were
stopped&lt;/a&gt; out this morning, I tried to enter once, got stopped out; and
then an even better setup appeared, so I entered again. See Figure 1.
This is a really awesome setup for the following 5 reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trend is on our side as it's still pointing up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identical setup to last week's dive before the climb, same RSI, same
    candlestick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bounced right at 1.031, which is at a longer term Fibonacci fan line
    as shown in Fig. 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another support at round number 1.030, which is very near.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good reward/risk ratio, see below for calculation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I entered 6000 units (2/3 position as usual) and placed the stop at
1.0300, just 20 pips away. USD/CHF climbed up to 1.0345 almost
immediately after my entry. So I moved my first stop to 1.0310
(Fibonacci level) for half my position. That got taken out minutes later
and it marked the bottom (for now) at 1.0309. I was a bit too hasten to
move my stop up for this part. See Figure 2 for my orders. One big
caveat to this entry is my tight stop at 1.0300. It is simply too
obvious of a stop price. I'd imagine the market would try to gun the
stops there before a run-up. However, if 1.030 breaks, it would ruin the
setup as described above. And if they're able to break that level, who
knows how far this can go further down. So I'm keeping my stop as is.
Anyway, I still have half of my initial position left. USD/CHF is
trading around 1.034. I don't think I'll do anything to this position
for now. I'm comfortable with just half position sitting in for the
weekend. Entry: 1.0320, Fib fan line support, see Fig 1. Stop 1: 1.031,
triggered already for a loss of 10 pips. Stop 2: 1.030, round number
support. Target: 1.038 - 1.040, starting point of this quick dive.
Reward/Risk = 60 / 20 = 3, right on the line of my goal. Although I am
secretly eyeing the 1.045 level as a target, I'll be cautious starting
from 1.038. Probably by setting a trailing stop if we do touch that. As
always, let's wait and see how this goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="USD/CHF"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-02-usdchf_2.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-02-usdchf_2.png"&gt;USD/CHF&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF, 30-min and capture an
hour later than Fig. 1"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF, 30-min and capture an hour later
than Fig. 1" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-02-usdchf_30min2.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-02-usdchf_30min2.png"&gt;USD/CHF, 30-min and capture an hour later than Fig.
1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: USD/CHF out at 1.03998 (+50 pips) and 1.03798 (+30 pips)</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-usdchf-out-at-103998-50-pips-and-103798-30-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-02T10:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-02:paper-trade-usdchf-out-at-103998-50-pips-and-103798-30-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm all stopped out of my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-1-03498-stop-1-03240/"&gt;USD/CHF positions from a couple of days
ago&lt;/a&gt;. I considered re-entering when we failed to break 1.037 a few
minutes later. But the 1.04-1.043 range seemed heavy, so I postponed
that idea. About this trade, the maximum drawdown was terrific at a mere
0.12% (see stats below). I seem to do well with my entry. However, I'm
leaving profits on the table once again. For my second exit, USD/CHF
touched a high of 1.0451 but I was only able to get out at 1.03798.
Granted, this portion is supposed to be loose to capture bigger moves,
but that didn't happen. So once again, &lt;strong&gt;I need to work on my exit&lt;/strong&gt;.
Another thing here is that my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-1-03498-stop-1-03240/"&gt;USD/CHF target of 1.045&lt;/a&gt; was spot on. I wanted to exit half
my position at that level. But I couldn't figure out how to do both
target stop and stop loss at the same time after my entry order is sent.
This problem has been resolved by asking customer support at Oanda. I'm
not entering any more new trade (aside from the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-nzdusd-entry-stop-0-7040/"&gt;NZD/USD stink bid&lt;/a&gt;
which I placed this morning) because it's Friday and I don't see anymore
obvious good setup across the board (a small board) for my 4h timeframe.
&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Nevermind, I was eyeing 1.0350 when I got stopped out as a
entry point. USD/CHF just touched it as I'm writing this post. So I'm
back in now with a tight trailing stop... (and it doesn't seem to be
holding after just a few minutes... and it's stopped out for an
additional loss of \$4.86 on this tap.) Entry: &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-1-03498-stop-1-03240/"&gt;1.03498, 6000
units&lt;/a&gt; Stopped out 1:
1.03998, 3000 units Stopped out 2: 1.03798, 3000 units Net: \$14.97 +
\$8.97 Time held: 14:51:00 and 37:10:00 Max. Drawdown %: -0.12% for both
Net from Max. Gain: 102.40% and &lt;strong&gt;237.33%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="USD/CHF"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-02-usdchf.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-02-usdchf.png"&gt;USD/CHF&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF,
30-min"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF, 30-min" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-02-usdchf_30min1.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-02-usdchf_30min1.png"&gt;USD/CHF, 30-min&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry></feed>