<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/contest_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-12-06T12:23:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Another trading contest from Dukascopy</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-trading-contest-from-dukascopy/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-12-06T12:23:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-12-06:another-trading-contest-from-dukascopy/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dukascopy started a new contest this month. This contest is manual
trading only on a demo account with no cash commitment by contestants.
The twist is that the ranking is determined not only by your demo
account balance, but also the total pips gained, popularity, and scoring
by Dukascopy's judges. Each trade in the contest needs to be commented
by the contestant through the JForex trading platform (when you submit
an order the platform asks you for a comment). See &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/tradercontest/?action=blog&amp;amp;trader=Quantisan"&gt;my contest page for
comment examples&lt;/a&gt; (shameless plug). About half of your score is based
on these trade comments as they are the basis for generating popularity
points and the Dukascopy judges' final evaluation. I can see the
potential in this contest as it offers transparency and encourages
interactions rather than let everyone just gamble away. However, most of
the trade comments now are meaningless as it's clear that you can
generate buzz simply by making ridiculous gains. Perhaps this might
change after this month's final ranking is released as it is not clear
how Dukascopy will allocate each contestant's 25% of points. The judging
by Dukascopy can effectively bump or dump you a few ranking. The
incentive to do this is the USD \$15,000 'cash' prizes to be won every
month just like the Dukascopy Strategy Contest. And similarly, these
'cash' prizes are deposited into the winner's Dukascopy trading account
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/reading-the-fine-print-for-dukascopy-jforex-strategy-contest/"&gt;with a withholding period&lt;/a&gt;. So they're forcing you to open an account
with them if you win, which is understandable as this is a marketing
effort. For information or registration in the contest, &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143/"&gt;visit the
Dukascopy website&lt;/a&gt; and navigate to the Trader Contest page.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="contest"></category><category term="dukascopy"></category></entry><entry><title>Why winning automated contest strategies don't work in real trading</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-winning-automated-contest-strategies-dont-work-in-real-trading/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-27T13:14:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-09-27:why-winning-automated-contest-strategies-dont-work-in-real-trading/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I despise sellers of trading robots making misleading promises like
"doubling your money every month". They are nothing more than snake oil
salesmen exploiting on the greed and ignorance of others. Yet I am
finding myself in a similar situation lately. Ever since &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-interview-at-dukascopy-in-geneva/"&gt;my interview
at Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt; about my JForex automated trading contest win, I seem to
have established a persona for being able to generate 45%+ return per
month using my strategy. Despite my constant reiteration that this is
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/number-one-with-40-percent-return-in-a-month-so-am-i-rich-yet-not-really/"&gt;merely a lucky result in a risk-free game&lt;/a&gt;, I am still getting
inquiries from people interested in following my trading signals. In
another attempt to rein in expectations, consider this chart of my
contest demo account balance for this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="September 2010 JForex contest balance" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-09-27-contestbalance.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, my strategy doubled the account within days. However, it
also lost half of its paper value plus some more soon afterward. As it
stands now, my September strategy will not be in the top 10 for this
month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I haven't mentioned this embarassing negative return, you wouldn't
have noticed it, would you? That's the thing with trading contest and
those snake oil trading robots, we hear a lot about them when somebody
win. But what happens to those same people when they aren't winning or
the countless other unfortunate followers lost money?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of the lottery system. Our perception of the probability
of winning the lottery is drastically distorted because we hear about
the winnings so much while neglecting the fact that there are millions
of losers out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact is, most of the seemingly impressive trading robots out there
will not last for the long term. The only reason that I have won three
times out of the five months is that I change my strategy's parameters
in expectation of the future month's market condition. That expection is
based on my own market analysis from my real trading. It isn't something
that can be readily quantified yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, the only way in which others can exploit my success is
to buy my real secret trading system, which is, perhaps unfortunately,
my brain.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="contest"></category></entry><entry><title>My interview at Dukascopy in Geneva</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-interview-at-dukascopy-in-geneva/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-23T12:28:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-09-23:my-interview-at-dukascopy-in-geneva/</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe width="560" height="349" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/1QPxPcd9Eow" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complete script for my August 2010 winning strategy is
&lt;a href="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/6028806/quantisan_aug10.java"&gt;available for free&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href="http://db.tt/5vkkEMAm"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;. And for those not familiar with
Java programming, I have explained &lt;a href="/jforex-example-multiple-time-frame-strategy/"&gt;the logic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="/jforex-example-dual-timeframe-moving-averages-setup/"&gt;the setup&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="/jforex-example-not-letting-profit-turn-to-losses-with-a-breakeven-stop/"&gt;the risk management&lt;/a&gt; behind the strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, here is an important disclaimer about my winning, &lt;a href="/number-one-with-40-percent-return-in-a-month-so-am-i-rich-yet-not-really/"&gt;Number
one with 40+ percent return in a month! So am I rich yet? Not really&lt;/a&gt;.
If that isn't enough, here's an illustration on &lt;a href="/why-winning-automated-contest-strategies-dont-work-in-real-trading/"&gt;Why winning automated
contest strategies don't work in real trading&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="contest"></category><category term="dukascopy"></category><category term="JForex"></category></entry><entry><title>To gamble or not to gamble?</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/to-gamble-or-not-to-gamble/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-29T09:12:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-04-29:to-gamble-or-not-to-gamble/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is only two more trading days left in the April &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt;
JForex Strategy Contest. I am currently ranked 6th. But there's a fierce
fight for my spot. I've been moving between 6th and 8th all week even
though I haven't made any trade. The other people are putting on big
bets hoping to squeeze in a top 6. Why? According to the winning prize
structure, the 4th to 6th winners will each receive \$1,000. Whereas the
7th to 10th will each receive \$500 only. With my current account
standing at \$120,032 (20% gain) this month, it is quite viable for
others to try to take my spot. See the table below for the top 10
standings as of this writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="April standing 2 days before close" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-04-29-contestranking.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My options are to either fire up my strategy to make more trades or do
nothing. The risk in running my strategy again is that I might lose
money and make myself even less competitive. My strategy's working
timeframe is in hours, so there isn't much room for error. As such, I
feel that with only two days of trading left, time is not on my side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I will probably lose out my 6th spot as I am not far
away from others behind me. So if I do nothing, I will most likely end
up 7th or 8th and lose half the prize money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After pondering about this briefly, I've decided to do nothing. The odds
are just too much against me. I have seen too many people in this
month's contest risking to move up from a good rank only to expose
themselves too much and lose out of the top 10 completely.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="contest"></category><category term="JForex"></category></entry><entry><title>An explanation of my Keltner Channel and Candlestick hybrid setup</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-explanation-of-my-keltner-channel-and-candlestick-hybrid-setup/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-09T18:16:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-04-09:an-explanation-of-my-keltner-channel-and-candlestick-hybrid-setup/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is an explanation of my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated trading&lt;/a&gt; strategy for the
Dukascopy JForex Strategy Contest in April. This strategy just made its
first trade today after running for about 72 hours. My contest demo
account closed with a gain of 7% on this first trade. Note that this
strategy is built for competing in a contest and not for real trading
(i.e., it's purely a no cost gamble). Here is the concept for this high
probability trading setup. Referring to Figure 1 below, the red arrow
marks my short entry on EURGBP today. These are the technical analysis
indicators the strategy uses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trend: Signaled by 50 bar moving average above (bullish) or below
    (bearish) the 200 bar moving average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Momentum: Oversold or overbought RSI conditions, but not used in a
    traditional manner...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volatility: I use the Keltner channel to measure volatility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price action: Observe candlestick behaviour to identify trend
    continuation. This is where the secret to this strategy happens. I
    will explain this below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I used a Bollinger Bands in the chart of Figure 1 because I
couldn't find the Keltner Channel indicator in Metatrader (my charting
software). It doesn't affect my conceptual illustration anyhow. The
setup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify overarching trend via 50/200 moving averages as explained
    above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm price is still playing to the trend by checking if current
    market price is on the right side of the 200 bars moving average.
    Price above for bullish and below for bearish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once steps 1-2 are in place, it's assumed that the trend is strong.
    We look for a setup in the trend's direction. In particular, we look
    for a &lt;em&gt;failed counter-trend retracement&lt;/em&gt; setup using candlestick in
    combination with the Keltner channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sounds fancy but it's simple. Using a short-side example, the bar's
    high has to penetrate above the Keltner channel yet it closes within
    it. Then the short entry is signaled. The opposite for a long-side
    entry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSI overbought and oversold conditions are used to filter out slow
    and steady counter-trend moves (those are evil).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit of using a price channel is that I also use it to peg my
take profit target and stop loss. As I said in my previous post, because
&lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143/"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt; expects winning contestants to submit their source codes,
I am not using anything proprietary or extraordinary here. As such, this
is totally different than &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;what I use to trade on my own&lt;/a&gt;. Namely more
reliance on indicators and less on price action and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/risk-management/"&gt;risk management&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-04-09-eurgbp_30m.gif" title="EURGBP, 30m" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="candlestick"></category><category term="channel"></category><category term="contest"></category><category term="dukascopy"></category><category term="JForex"></category><category term="momentum"></category><category term="trend"></category></entry></feed>