<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/corn_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2008-01-09T23:51:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Starting manual day trading</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/starting-manual-day-trading/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-09T23:51:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-01-09:starting-manual-day-trading/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://bp0.blogger.com/_Vlx60iTPx5s/R4WWUfY4uZI/AAAAAAAAAE8/x03wdcZpaFk/s400/ym_daytrade.jpg" /&gt;][]I will day trade manually for a short period to gain some
experience while I develop my auto system. The market I've chosen is YM
(mini Dow) for the short term, ZG (CBOT Gold) for the longer term, and
Corn for the long long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YM is on CBOT, so I wouldn't have to shell out another \$55 for the
NYMEX data. It's also a more popular/mature market than ER2 so I can
obtain fundamental analysis easier to complement my technical analysis.
The recent price action is also very predictable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the marked spot on the left graph is a potential strategy.
Notice the breakdown of the TRIX corresponds with an imminent breakdown
of the price. This is just one example. But observing price pattern and
TRIX pattern seems to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my other two choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gold is hot at the moment, so there could be huge swings. It's now
around \$890 and I'm expecting a correction based on the fundamentals.
I'll watch the price pattern and indicators to time my entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corn is on a run for the past 3 months. It has low margin requirement
(\~\$1000) and the price are quite consistent. So waiting for
breakout/down can riding the trend could be a long term profitable
trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://bp0.blogger.com/_Vlx60iTPx5s/R4WWUfY4uZI/AAAAAAAAAE8/x03wdcZpaFk/s400/ym_daytrade.jpg" /&gt;]: http://bp0.blogger.com/_Vlx60iTPx5s/R4WWUfY4uZI/AAAAAAAAAE8/x03wdcZpaFk/s1600-h/ym_daytrade.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="corn"></category><category term="day trading"></category><category term="gold"></category><category term="YM"></category></entry></feed>