<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/emfp_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2009-04-28T20:22:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>EMFP: The trade that broke me</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/emfp-the-trade-that-broke-me/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-28T20:22:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-04-28:emfp-the-trade-that-broke-me/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="/about/"&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt;, I summarized my trading history. You'll no doubt
see that between now and then, I admitted that I plundered my trading
account twice. Needless to say, that was a memorable period in my life.
The easy money from my lucky early years bit back hard and were taken
away within months. I'm surprised at myself why I'm even back at this
game now. There's a reason why I'm bringing this up. No, I am not broke
again. I only commit what I can lose in trading now. Still, I am aware
that I need to do a lot better in terms of risk management and
discipline before I can become a decent trader. But I digressed. You
see, like a dead pirate clinging on to his treasure, I've never let go
of those shares from that trade that broke me. As of this writing, I
still have a sizable shares of EMFP that I purchased from 2006 for
average of $1.23. For the record, here are my 3 entries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 9, 2006 for 3500 shares at $0.77&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 30, 2006 for 9512 shares at $0.56&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 31, 2006 for 34695 shares at $1.46&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, comparing the dates and entry prices with the chart of Figure
1, it seems that my record is wrong because the trading prices on those
dates are way off. I will need to dig up some paper and check my record.
Anyway, my average price is correct at $1.23. For the first few months
of the share price dive, I was so naive that I thought the stock was
&lt;em&gt;cheap&lt;/em&gt;. Then once reality sets in, I was just in shock that I didn't do
anything about it. By then, it was too late to savage anything
worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from Figure 1, the move from $2.00 to $0.20
took 1 year. Since then, I just wrote this position off in my mind and
left the shares to collect dust. As you can see, EMFP even dipped to
$0.01 last year. My intention is to unload it in a later year when I
need a tax break. However, this week, EMFP moved from $0.07 to $0.35
and closed at $0.20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, EMFP, or Emergency Filtration Products
Inc., markets a product called NanoMask that has been independently
tested to be effective against influenza and other viruses as a face
mask. With the recent talk of a global pandemic because of the &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/news/health/2009-04-28-swine-flu_N.htm"&gt;swine flu scare&lt;/a&gt;, it's clear to see why there's renewed interest in EMFP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the volume has spiked to about 2 million yesterday and almost 1
million shares today. There were days and weeks with no share traded at
all for EMFP in the past year. I am not so naive anymore to think EMFP
may climb back to its former glory. However, I hope EMFP can stir up
some more interest and trading volume, just so I can finish the fight
once and for all and close this embarassing trade in my log book. So,
I'd like to start this trade log and put EMFP back on my radar. I should
have unloaded a chunk of my holding yesterday when EMFP stayed around
$0.25. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I thought that I've waited this long, I might as well
let this flu panic play out and give EMFP more time to do something.
This is the first of my mistake, greed. This could very well cost me my
last chance to ditch this. My reason for holding is that we've hit the
200 day MA at $0.35 yesterday (Figure 2), so a bounce back was
expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then today, EMFP held above the $0.13 support (low was
$0.14) on the retracement. With the still relatively low volume, this
stock is swinging like a wild bull. So large trading ranges is a given.
There are definitely a lot of resistance at $0.30. Yet, we have
established an up trend since the bounce from $0.01. This recent gap up
at huge volume would look good if EMFP can break above this up trend
with this momentum. Otherwise, breaking below $0.13 support would lead
this back to the coffin. Anyway, it's too early to tell. I usually say
watch the price levels at this point, however, in this case, I say that
it's more important to watch the volume. A sustained level of volume in
EMFP means there's finally some interest. And since we're pretty much at
rock bottom for the price, volume would lead to higher prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Emergency Filtration Products Inc. (5 years, weekly)" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-28-emfp.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Emergency Filtration Products Inc. (daily left, weekly right)" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-28-emfp_ind.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EMFP"></category><category term="entry"></category></entry></feed>