<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/es_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2008-10-10T14:38:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Dabbling in day trading again on this historic day</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/dabbling-in-day-trading-again-on-this-historic-day/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-10T14:38:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-10-10:dabbling-in-day-trading-again-on-this-historic-day/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_334" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="ES Setup"][&lt;img alt="ES Setup" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/2008-10-10-es.png?w=500" title="2008-10-10-es" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned previously &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/reducing-overall-market-exposure-according-to-market-volatility/"&gt;about avoiding volatility&lt;/a&gt;. But with VIX about
75 now, I couldn't help but to take the opportunity to day trade. I
know, I know, I said I wouldn't do it again. So I'm only trading an
account with&lt;strong&gt;paper money&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate the abundance of day trading opportunities these days, I
just launched my trading screen and within minutes I can see a viable
setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 1 minute chart on the left, notice the small doji at \$844 with a
high volume. Also off the chart is a low of \$837 for the day in the
morning. So \$840 is an effective support for the moment. Since the doji
at \$844 is above \$840, this is a good sign for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I placed buy orders around \$845 for the next few minutes and exiting
below \$850 (obvious resistance), with intent to get back later in if it
breaks \$850 strongly. This went on for a few minutes, and I traded in
the range taking small profits twice, until the price broke to \$841.50,
which I stopped at a loss at around \$842.50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, noticing it's in a steady climb from then on, I entered a long
at \$845 again, with stop at \$841, for a longer trade. The price rose
to \$853.75, bounced back to \$850, and started dropping. I exited my
long at a small profit at \$849.50 on a retracement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES keeps dropping for those seconds until \$845.75 and bounced right
back to \$851. That was a good sign. I believe the initial \$850 break
and retracement was just a technical bounce. So I went in again at \$851
a bit later intending to ride it up to \$860.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That trade went as planned and I exited at \$858. I reversed and went
short at \$861 with a tight stop at \$863. The stop got hit and the
price went up to \$866.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to stop there since the trading screen didn't lean much to
on-the-spot analysis. I'm not asking for a full charting screen though,
that would be overkill for day trading. Simplicity is key. I'd be happy
if they had 1-min and 15 min candlestick charts with 2-line EMA, MACD,
Stochastic, and volume information. In the end, I'm \$162.50 richer in
paper money after 12 trades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it's a profitable session, I think I took way too many trades
to reach that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my trading platform is very basic and isn't meant for day trading,
I didn't even have a chart on the trading matrix. I just looked at the
price movements and occasionally flip back to the chart. However, I do
have one good indicator for use... which is the price of Goldman Sachs
(GS). Long story short, we're in a financial driven crisis and GS (along
with MS and others) is one of the two surviving investment banks (of
original 5) in this mess. GS were off the lows of the day and moving up
very slowly throughout the few minutes which I day traded. That was a
good enough bullish sign for me to go long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="ES Setup" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/2008-10-10-es.png?w=500" title="2008-10-10-es" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/2008-10-10-es.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="day trading"></category><category term="ES"></category></entry><entry><title>Reward Risk of Popular Index Futures</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/reward-risk-of-popular-index-futures/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-02-14:reward-risk-of-popular-index-futures/</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;                &lt;span class="o"&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ER2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class="o"&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;YM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class="o"&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class="o"&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;EMD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;10min ATR         2.7        32          4          2.6
  Daily ATR         26         341         42         25
  \$ / point        \$100.00   \$5.00      \$50.00    \$100.00
  &lt;strong&gt;Reward/Risk&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;9.63&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;10.66&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;10.5&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;9.62&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm using the intra-day ATR as a risk factor because I'm assuming them
as noise. I use 10 min. as the basis because that's about the time
period I use. The reward is the max daily swing, which is the daily ATR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
As you can see, the reward/risk is about the same for all the liquid
index futures. However, I'm leaning toward YM because of the smaller
contract size and it seems more stable lately. I'll watch the markets
closely from now on.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EMD"></category><category term="er2"></category><category term="ES"></category><category term="YM"></category></entry></feed>