<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/fslr_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2008-11-21T09:46:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>BOUGHT +1 FSLR 100 JAN 09 70 PUT @11.90</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-1-fslr-100-jan-09-70-put-1190/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-21T09:46:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-11-21:bought-1-fslr-100-jan-09-70-put-1190/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_833" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="First Solar"][&lt;img alt="First Solar" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-21-fslr.png" title="2008-11-21-fslr" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have covered my FSLR Jan09 70 put as planned. I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-1-fslr-100-jan-09-70-put-1320/"&gt;shorted it for
\$13.2&lt;/a&gt; and covered it for \$11.90. An overnight profit of \$130 after
commission. The share price was about \$92 at the time of this trade. It
is now at \$88 as I type a few minutes later. I covered at a good time,
right at the peak of this morning gap up rush. Frankly, I'm just glad I
can cover it at a profit. I would have done the same even if it's a
loss. Better be small than big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-1-fslr-100-jan-09-70-put-1320/"&gt;original reasons for going long&lt;/a&gt;
were sound for the &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; term, but I obtusely forget the fact that I
can't stand a huge potential drawdown. I am clearly still suffering from
this bottom-calling tendency. But at least I caught myself this time. I
think this is a good start to correct this costly habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the trend in this week's down leg indicate we can have a
downside to \$80 for ESLR. Entering long at yeseterday was a low
probability trade. I should have waited til \$80 or better yet, wait for
a confirmation for a rally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="First Solar" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-21-fslr.png" title="2008-11-21-fslr" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-21-fslr.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exit"></category><category term="FSLR"></category><category term="options"></category></entry><entry><title>SOLD -1 FSLR 100 JAN 09 70 PUT @13.20</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-1-fslr-100-jan-09-70-put-1320/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-20T16:34:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-11-20:sold-1-fslr-100-jan-09-70-put-1320/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_816" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 versus First Solar 1-min"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 versus First Solar
1-min" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-20-spx-fslr.png" title="2008-11-20-spx-fslr" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_817" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="First Solar weekly"][&lt;img alt="First Solar weekly" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-20-fslr.png" title="2008-11-20-fslr" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After breaking the 820 support on the S&amp;amp;P 500 2 days ago, the market
dived into the abyss today as I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-breakdown-of-a-major-multi-year-support-are-we-going-down-and-i-mean-really-down/"&gt;suggested this morning&lt;/a&gt;. Frankly, the
mid-day looked alright and I thought we wouldn't go down anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out I was wrong (I stayed on sideline as planned). The market
capitulated in the last hour. In particular, Citigroup sank to \$4.71.
My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-1-c-100-nov-08-5-call-325/"&gt;short call at \$8.20&lt;/a&gt; would have made a killing had I not get
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-1-c-100-nov-08-5-call-350/"&gt;stopped out&lt;/a&gt;. Oh well, I'm not complaining. Although my portfolio is
way down, I am just glad that I managed my risk and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-1-abb-100-nov-08-125-put-195/"&gt;covered all my
short puts&lt;/a&gt; a couple of days ago. In hindsight though, I really should
have &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-1-c-100-nov-08-5-call-325/"&gt;hedged my position&lt;/a&gt; more eagerly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to this entry. Why? After failing to pick the bottom so
many times, why the heck am I entering now? (This is going in my rule
book, &lt;strong&gt;no picking top/bottom&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I think this is the bottom for FSLR? I don't know. Why did I enter
this trade? Because if offers good risk/reward and probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upside: January 2009 expiry date with 50% probability of expiry for this
70 strike. Support is \$75 for FSLR set in 2007 but we never even came
close to it in this historic downleg in the market. Today marked a new
low of \$86. Thus, my 70 strike is a stink bid. And being paid \$13.20
for this stink bid? I compared this risk/reward to a few strong
companies I liked and this OTM put price is the highest (since I'm
shorting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resistance: \$100. But I don't really care since this is a stink bid and
I have limited upside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downside: If we do break \$75, then all hell breaks lose in this. We are
still in a severe and monumental market crash. I don't have cash to buy
the shares if this is put to me in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support: \$75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: This is a high probability trade. Stop is just below \$75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
**Update:** I am going to liquidate this position tomorrow. Bill from
[BillCara.com kindly shared his insight][] on this trade.

&gt; When you prepare for a trade like this, you want to look at the charts
&gt; of the peer group, look at their support levels as well. Then you need
&gt; some other set up to help you make a decision. Maybe the Stochastics
&gt; have bounced off zero for a couple of the peer group? Maybe the RSI-7
&gt; is well down for them all for the 10-minute, 60-minute and 1 day
&gt; chart? Something, other than guessing, has to be the primary factor.
&gt; Unhedged, I don't know I would have picked the January's though
&gt; because the market is still crashing, and I don't see enough of a set
&gt; up to cause me to put on that trade. I like the trade because you are
&gt; selling volatility and the time decay will eat up those put buyers,
&gt; but unhedged I probably would have extended the time frame a bit
&gt; unless it was my plan to have the stock put to me as part of an
&gt; acquisition strategy based on the company fundamentals and quants.

I also didn't think this thoroughly myself. I simply cannot stomach the
potential drawdown in FSLR. Even my own trendline analysis shows it can
go to \$80 on this down run. I should wait for confirmations of strength
before heading in at this point.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 versus First Solar 1-min" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-20-spx-fslr.png" title="2008-11-20-spx-fslr" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-20-spx-fslr.png
  [&lt;img alt="First Solar weekly" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-20-fslr.png" title="2008-11-20-fslr" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/2008-11-20-fslr.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FSLR"></category><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="options"></category></entry></feed>