<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/ftb_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2009-11-18T21:22:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Paper trade: Long USD/CHF @ 1.0122, SL 1.0060, TP 1.0225</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-10122-sl-10060-tp-10225/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-18T21:22:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-18:paper-trade-long-usdchf-10122-sl-10060-tp-10225/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seeing that this is my first commitment after the big drawdown, I'll
bring back my tradition of writing a post to log my rationale and market
conditions on this entry for later review. I sifted through the weekly
charts of all pairs on my watch-list tonight and found that USD/CHF long
is the most promising. Figure 1 shows my daily chart for the setup and
Figure 2 is a 3-hour chart with my entry timing. Let's talk about Figure
1 first. USD/CHF is making a triple bottom with a positive divergence as
shown. I have also marked the current major support at 1.0010. USD/CHF
has trade below it for about a week now but failed to break any lower.
Today is the first day when we've opened somewhat above it. Secondly,
note that we have broken above a descending channel as shown in Figure
1. USD/CHF has also tested the 1.0010 support twice already at both
sides of that channel. And accompanied with a positive divergence as I
said. The major caution as shown in Figure 1 is that we're still trading
below the 10-day ma. As for the entry timing, observe Figure 2. Notice
that USD/CHF just made a higher low outside and above the descending
fChannel (the two thicker brown lines). This is the signal for entry.
Note that the fChannel is my proprietary channel. This trade is
initiated according to my new Forex Trend Fading (FTF) setup. Position
size: &lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;,
50%&lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt; Entry: 1.0122,
from fRays signal. Stop: 1.0060, below major support Target: 1.0225,
first major resistance, ease off some at that point, add more above it.
Reward / Risk = 103 / 62 = 1.66 \&amp;lt; 3. Not not good enough for my usual
R/R target, but I've been considering lowering it to 1.5. So lets see if
an R/R of 1.5 is a good enough number. I would have been more
comfortable with a 2.0 though. Anyway, let's see how this goes. Update:
I took half of it off at breakeven because of the lower R/R and the new
setup. Only 50% in this trade now. I'm looking to add a EUR or JPY cross
for my other half allocation. Update 11/19: I'm stopped out of this
position @ 1.0150 for +27 pips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="USD/CHF"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF.png"&gt;USD/CHF&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF,
3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF_3h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF_3h.PNG"&gt;USD/CHF, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTB"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry></feed>