<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/ftc_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-02-17T21:58:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Paper trade: Long CADJPY @ 86.88, Stop 86.10, Target 88.0</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-cadjpy-8688-stop-8610-target-880/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-17T21:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-17:paper-trade-long-cadjpy-8688-stop-8610-target-880/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I entered CADJPY long at market for 86.88 just now. This is a
continuation of my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-1-0540-for-131-pips/"&gt;previous USDCAD short&lt;/a&gt; position. However, USDJPY
is on a run upward so I'm switching to go long on the loonie with yen
instead. Figure 1 shows the daily chart of CADJPY. Notice the imminent
MACD bullish crossover and the already in-play stochastic upturn. I like
it. My stop loss level is set at 86.10. It's the high of a previous peak
on February 3, two weeks ago. My target is the round number 88
resistance. 88.0 has been an important price level for CADJPY for the
past few months. So I'm setting my sight there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CADJPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_d.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows my timing for this entry. CADJPY is noticeably meeting
some resistance at 87.50. 87.50 is also the 61.8% Fibonacci level of a
recent down move. This is a cause for concern on my long position as we
could very well retrace here. However, the bullishness of CADJPY is
apparent in Figure 2. Prices have consistently been bought for the past
few days right on the short term moving average (teal line).
Furthermore, the intermediate term moving average (orange line) is about
to cross the long term moving average (red line) as I enter this
position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, gold price has taken a dive from 1130 to 1100. Meanwhile, crude
oil price is holding the 77 support nicely. Thus, this confirm my
previous view that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-change-of-wind-for-australian-dollar-shorted-audusd-0-9183-and-audcad-0-9546/"&gt;oil has better upside than gold&lt;/a&gt; in the
intermediate term. Which is why I've been trading the loonie these past
weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this particular CADJPY trade, I have another buy order waiting above
current support level to add to my long position. Let's see if CADJPY
can break decisively to the upside in the next 24 hours as US and
Canadian data comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CADJPY,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_4h.gif" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_4h.gif"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short USDCAD @ 1.0671, Stop 1.0756, Target 1.05761</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-10671-stop-10756-target-105761/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-09T18:56:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-09:paper-trade-short-usdcad-10671-stop-10756-target-105761/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Perhaps third times' the charm? I tried to short USDCAD twice last week
already. Both times I've been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-out-of-usdcad-short-1-0640-for-67-pips-re-entering-1-0680/"&gt;stopped out&lt;/a&gt; for a total of -0.2% of
account loss. My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;intermediate term analysis&lt;/a&gt; remains the same as
before. So I won't repeat myself here. Entry signal for this particular
short is shown in Figure 1. I'm just using the 4-hour chart as I have a
well defined (recent top) stop this time. I compensate with a smaller
position size to limit my risk to 0.1%. Reward / Risk = (1.05761 -
1.0671) / (1.0671 - 1.0756) = 1.11 [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="USD/CAD, 4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-09-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Stopped out of USDCAD short @ 1.0640 for -67 pips, re-entering @ 1.0680</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-out-of-usdcad-short-10640-for-67-pips-re-entering-10680/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-04T20:10:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-04:paper-trade-stopped-out-of-usdcad-short-10640-for-67-pips-re-entering-10680/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well this was awful. USDCAD continued on a rampage upward and I was
caught on the wrong side of the fence. Total loss for this was 0.12% of
my account. At least I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;was light in it&lt;/a&gt;. In retrospect, I broke my
own rule and didn't enter at one of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/4-fundamental-entry-signs-for-trading-and-why-they-are-not-that-important/"&gt;4 fundamental entry points&lt;/a&gt;.
However, after some bear rampage throughout the markets today
(Bloomberg: [Stocks Plunge on Concern Rising Debt, Job Losses Threaten
Global Recovery][]), USDCAD is at the top of my channel as shown in
Figure 1 below. So while my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/4-fundamental-entry-signs-for-trading-and-why-they-are-not-that-important/"&gt;previous entry&lt;/a&gt;
was early. USDCAD at this price is a good short. I will take it slow
this time by setting a limit order below current support on the 4-hour
at 1.0680, with a stop at 1.0750. And then adding a second chunk at
1.0640, my stopped out price. As is customarily lately, I am only
risking 0.1% of my account on the initial order. On a weekly chart,
1.0750 to 1.0810 is obviously a strong resistance for the USDCAD. It is
a congestion zone in 2007 and 2008. Then USDCAD spent the last quarter
of 2009 trying to break this resistance to no avail. But who knows,
perhaps USDCAD has had enough and it will break this resistance
decisively soon. That's why I'm only betting on this reversal with
limited risk. It's just a matter of wait and see now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-04-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Stocks Plunge on Concern Rising Debt, Job Losses Threaten Global
  Recovery]: http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=20601087&amp;amp;sid=a8ajRZqBemfs&amp;amp;pos=1&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short USD/CAD @ 1.0573, Stop 1.0640, Target 1.0415</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-10573-stop-10640-target-10415/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-02T22:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-02:paper-trade-short-usdcad-10573-stop-10640-target-10415/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Taking a first position in USD/CAD short here at 1.0573 on a 4-hour
moving averages cross-over (Figure 1). I've also placed a limit order to
add more at 1.0519 below Fibonacci support (shown in Figure 1). Reason
for this trade is that USD/CAD is moving away from an upper bound
channel with a overbought stochastic reading, as shown in the daily
chart of Figure 2. I've also considered going long AUD/USD, but AUD/CAD
trend remains bearish. So I chose to short USD/CAD instead. Secondly,
crude oil (and gold too) looks to be bouncing off an oversold level with
a rapid move in 2 days from 72.43 to 77.39. Coincidentally, INO.com
posted an intermediate term &lt;a href="http://www.ino.com/info/513/CD4184/&amp;amp;dp=0&amp;amp;l=0&amp;amp;campaignid=3"&gt;cyclical analysis video with a bullish
outlook&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link). They put out a better case than I do.
USD/CAD might make a short-term upward bounce here because of a
short-term oversold condition. However, there's evidently a lack of
buyers in the past few hours (Fig. 1). The price has been sitting on
support a bit too long in my view. Thus, I'm expecting it to break
without a meaningful retracement (hence the short entry). A confirmation
would be a break below 1.0530. Thus I have a limit order to short more
below that price. I am risking 0.1% of my account on this trade. As you
may have noticed, these charts are from Metatrader. I'm switching over
to the MT4 platform as of today. Having played with its charting
features for the past few hours, I'm quite satisfied with it so far.
Although my needs are low as I was fine with the Oanda platform too
(arguably the most simplistic platform out there). [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USD/CAD,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-02-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="USD/CAD, daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-02-usdcad.gif" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-02-usdcad.gif"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: GBPJPY @ 145.24, Stop 144.70, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-28T21:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-28:paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I've switched over to long EURJPY @ 125.40 as EURGBP's
downtrend seem to be running out of steam. Moreover, EURJPY looks better
on the daily chart with a clear support and an oversold reading. I'm
back in my long GBPJPY play at 145.24. The currency pair is breaking an
hourly resistance since consolidating around 145. I had a low ball offer
at 144.20 since &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;taking my profit last night at 146.42&lt;/a&gt;. But that bid
for never filled. So I'm re-entering on a short-term breakout. For this
entry, I am risking 0.1% of my account. This re-entry is a tough
decision. Almost all the respectable pros that I &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/Quantisan"&gt;follow on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
are on the other side of this trade via other currency pairs. However,
my long setup is valid as long as GBPJPY is above 144 level. So I'll
take this trade until proven otherwise. Although I must admit that my
confidence in this trade is very low. I also considered long CADJPY
instead as it seems to offer more upside potential. However, as I've
been following the GBPJPY pair this week, I'll stick with my plan. I
also have a limit order to add more at 145.81 as you can see in Figure 1
below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-28-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed GBPJPY @ 146.42 for +140 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-27T22:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-27:paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just closed my GBPJPY long at 146.42 for around +140 pips average gain,
or 0.4% in the account balance. Damn good for a 24 hours holding. Obama
just finished his State of The Union address at the moment. I am not
impressed. Still all talk of change but nothing concrete yet. Anyway,
that's beside the point in this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trade log&lt;/a&gt;. 146.50 price level for
GBPJPY is the 10 day moving average. It has also been a strong support
back in late December. This should be a good resistance level. My guess
is that GBPJPY should stall, or even retrace, here for a while. Thus I'm
taking profit at this price as shown in Figure 1 (yellow triangle). I
still believe my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-144-24-stop-143-60-target-148/"&gt;bullish setup from yesterday&lt;/a&gt; is still good. So I'll
be watching this pair for a re-entry. Update: I re-entered at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-145-24-stop-144-70-target-148/"&gt;145.24
the next day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBPJPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-27-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper Trade: Long GBPJPY @ 144.24, Stop 143.60, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-26T22:33:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-26:paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My previous &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;short-side setup on GBP/JPY&lt;/a&gt; played out beautifully. Yet
I wasn't able to ride it down because I got stopped out on a stop-hunt
counter-move before the dive, see Fig. 1. Now that GBP/JPY has reached
its other end. I am betting for it to go reverse with a long position. I
expect this move to be more fierce with more upside potential as it's in
the direction of the long term up trend. Some people are calling the top
has been printed in the markets and the wind is now blowing the other
way. I am not one to guess what the market is about to do. So it's
business as usual until the trendline is broken. What I really like
about this setup is that GBP/JPY is testing a double trendline cross on
the weekly, Fig. 2. Secondly, the 3-hour chart of Figure 1 is showing a
RSI positive divergence on this test of the long term support. I am
quite confident of this setup. However, I am not confident about the
timing as GBP/JPY is known to be a wild horse and volatility could very
well stop me out, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;like last time&lt;/a&gt;. With
British preliminary GDP number coming out in about 6 hours, it might
have been wiser to wait until the after that to enter. On top of that,
the markets have been on a stall for the last few days waiting for data
in the next 48 hours. End-of-week volatility this week is expected to be
significant. Anyway, I've put in a position already and will just let it
run. This a small initial position with 0.1% of my account at risk. I
have also placed limit orders above resistances to add to this position.
We'll how this turns out soon enough. Lastly, even though I said I've
been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/barred-from-trading-at-work-a-curse-or-a-gift/"&gt;cut off from trading at my day job&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn't mean I'm
completely out of the game. I just have to adapt my manual trading
strategy while my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated system&lt;/a&gt; is still in development.
Basically meaning that I'll trade with a slower timeframe for
longer-term moves. All the better, as longer term moves are generally
less deceptive. Update: I closed this at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;146.42 for +140 pips gain&lt;/a&gt;
the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="GBP/JPY, weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Closed EUR/CHF and GBP/CHF Shorts: Best. Trade. Ever.</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-22T15:36:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-22:closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I was saying earlier this week, I have been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;stockpiling in EUR/CHF
short&lt;/a&gt; in my demo account (Fig. 1). Aside from that, I've also stocked
up some GBP/CHF shorts this week (Fig. 2). Both positions are now closed
because of my adjusted stops. These positions have single-handedly
lifted me half way out of a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/work-harder-trade-fewer-in-a-long-and-excruciating-trading-drawdown/"&gt;deep drawdown&lt;/a&gt; in my demo account. These
trades netted me about 1.5% in my demo funds. Yes, you read that right,
a meager 1.5% gain and I'm calling these my best trades. No, it's not
like I haven't had &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/good-trade/"&gt;good trades&lt;/a&gt; in terms of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-eurjpy-135-00-500-1-pips/"&gt;money made&lt;/a&gt; or the
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/eurusd-95-pips-in-2-hours-an-example-of-swing-and-day-trade-convergence/"&gt;fastest pips&lt;/a&gt;. These shorts aren't even close from just looking at
the numbers. Heck, it would have been a lot more profitable if I shorted
Euro and Pound with a Dollar or Yen counter this week. So why? If you
read my post on &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/analysing-monthly-forex-trading-performance-in-changing-market-conditions/"&gt;measuring trading performance&lt;/a&gt;, you may recall that I
don't measure success by profit alone. It is performance &lt;em&gt;in terms of&lt;/em&gt;
amount risked that matters in trading. These shorts in EUR/CHF and
GBP/CHF are my best forex trades ever (in my 4 months of fx trading so
far) simply because I risked no more than 0.2% at any given time (most
of the time there were no explicit risk as my stops have locked in
profits) to make that 1.5%. 1.5% gained by risking maximum of 0.2% gives
a Reward/Risk ratio of 1.5/0.2 = 7.5! There were several occasions when
I had doubts to add to my position or were pondering about taking
profits to settle my worries. Despite all of that, I soldiered on,
managed my stops like they were my babies, and piled more into the
position according to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;my plan&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/FTC/"&gt;trading setup&lt;/a&gt; (Fig. 1). By the time I started scaling out, I have
built my biggest (non-scalp) position. That gave me a lot of freedom in
scaling out as you can see on my exits shown in Figure 1 (red dots).
This Reward/Risk ratio is the highest I have achieved in recent memory.
I have always read about 10x or even 20x trades at the &lt;a href="http://www.smbtraining.com/blog/"&gt;SMB Capital
blog&lt;/a&gt;. Those guys can achieve this type of reward/risk ratio day in
and day out (I'm not affiliated with them). I guess that's the
difference between the pros and me. This is definitely something I am
strifing to do myself. &lt;strong&gt;Executing consistently high reward/risk
trades.&lt;/strong&gt; How I might do that? By continuing to improve on my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/"&gt;trading
skills&lt;/a&gt; and my understanding of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;forex markets&lt;/a&gt;. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EUR/CHF,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-EURCHF_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="alignnone" width="580"
caption="GBP/CHF, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-GBPCHF_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-GBPCHF_3h.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="good trade"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>How to stockpile a trade position one step at a time</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-18T11:56:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-18:how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Arguably the single most important skill a trader needs to master in
trading any market is to &lt;strong&gt;cut your losses short and let your profits
run&lt;/strong&gt;. This is simply another saying of &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/risk-management/"&gt;managing risks&lt;/a&gt; and
maximizing opportunities. However, this is easier said than done. Ever
tried to cut your losses short but only to see the price run in your
favour soon afterward? Or, that you've built a sizable and profitable
position only to see it turn into a loss? As with much of other trading
skills, managing your trade is not an exact science. That is why you
need to have probabilities in your favour on every step. You enter a
trade because it is &lt;em&gt;likely&lt;/em&gt; to be profitable. You exit a trade when it
is not. If you can apply this axiom on every trade you do, it is
&lt;em&gt;likely&lt;/em&gt; that you will be profitable, with all things being equal. So
what does this have to do with cut your losses short and let your
profits run? In this post, I will discuss one &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;trading strategy&lt;/a&gt; which
I use to do exactly that. The key to this strategy is divide and
conquer. Instead of taking one trade for each position, consider taking
multiple smaller trades by scaling in and out of a position. That way,
you can have more freedom in your trade by using your position size to
your advantage. Here's the gist of the strategy and the rationale for
it. The rule is simple: increase a position by scaling in as the
probability of success increases; and decrease a position by scaling out
as the probability of success decreases. One way to do this is to add on
a position as the price breaks support on a faster timeframe. You keep
adding on this position as long as your trade setup (on a higher time
frame) is valid. At the same time, you limit your risk by &lt;em&gt;lowering the
stop&lt;/em&gt; of your previous trade to breakeven. That way, even though you are
stockpiling a position, the overall risk stays the same. This is an
essential step in the technique. Otherwise the risk would just multiply.
It is as much managing the entries as well as the stops/exits. Let's put
this into perspective with a real-world example. Figure 1 shows the
support levels for my EUR/CHF short on a 3-hour chart. I identified this
trade using my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/FTC"&gt;FTC setup&lt;/a&gt; on the daily chart. The failed break above
1.4800 on January 14 was the signal for entry. I took an initial short
position risking 0.20% of my account as EUR/CHF reverted back below
1.4800 (first support, not marked). Then I kept adding on to this
position below 1.4787, 1.4761, and 1.4742 supports as shown in Fig. 1
with the horizontal dashed red lines. On each subsequent new entry, I
move the stop on the previous entry to b/e. I only risk 0.1% on each of
these additions with half the position size after the initial entry. As
I keep adding, I keep moving the stops one step behind. So on my third
scale-in, my initial stop have locked in some profits at a price level
between my first and second entries. Figure 2 is the same chart but with
the actual filled orders (yellow triangles) and current stops (red
lines) marked. As you can see, I have effectively accumulated a sizable
position size in this short while limiting my risk to just a fraction
(0.2% versus 1.0%) if I were to enter my maximum size all at once.
Furthermore, my confidence and probability of this trade increase
gradually as I see the short-term support levels break one after
another. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURCHF,
3-hour, showing supports"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-18-EURCHF_3h.PNG" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EUR/CHF, 3-hour, showing
orders"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-18-EURCHF_3h_2.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-18-EURCHF_3h_2.PNG"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] There are limitations to this strategy.
First of all, this strategy is mostly suitable for trading setups with
an expected high reward/risk ratio. You might not want to use this for a
range trading strategy as there's probably not enough price move to
break the trade into steps. Secondly, this technique is mostly for an
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated system&lt;/a&gt; or longer term manual strategies (hours or more).
Just so you have sufficient time to manage all these extra work without
adding on an unnecessary amount of stress. Lastly, an obvious downside
to this approach is that your account will take a hit from the spreads
and commissions for each move. So do take those costs into account in
building your own adaptation to this concept. Now that I've discussed my
scaling-in technique, what do you think? &lt;strong&gt;Update January 22:&lt;/strong&gt; I've
closed this position and it turns out to be &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/"&gt;one of my best trade
ever&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="FTC"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I shorted CAD/JPY @ 88.57 instead of long USD/CAD @ 1.0251</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-shorted-cadjpy-8857-instead-of-long-usdcad-10251/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-15T09:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-15:why-i-shorted-cadjpy-8857-instead-of-long-usdcad-10251/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CAD/JPY failed a major resistance level at 90 and has edged out an
obvious intermediate-term downtrend (Fig 1). USD/CAD is also bouncing
off a major support at 1.0200 (Fig. 2). And crude oil is below \$80 on a
slippery slope. As such, shorting loonie seems like a good move at the
moment according to my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/FTC"&gt;FTC trading setup&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, here is why I am
opting to short CAD/JPY and not long the more popular USD/CAD currency
pair. Figure 3 shows a 5-year, weekly chart of CAD/JPY (top) and USD/CAD
(bottom). Evidently, the exchange rate of CAD/JPY is still in a
depressed mode since the fall of September 2008. It's also clear on this
chart that why I say 90 is a major resistance level. Beside from being a
nice round number, CAD/JPY has failed to break above 90 twice since
August 2009. As for USD/CAD, the picture isn't as clear. 1.0200 is
definitely a very strong support because it marks the top of a 6-month
range in the first half of 2008. Yet, the downward slope in the long
term since 2005 is not to be ignored. As such, I do not dare to bet on a
bounce on this pair at this price. Moreover, the intermediate-term move
on both of these pair is giving us a confirmation. CAD/JPY is now
testing a falling trendling (Fig. 1). Whereas USD/CAD is testing a
falling support. Thus, I am shorting CAD/JPY under pressure. Going long
on USD/CAD now would be like betting it to bounce on a slippery slope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="CAD/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-15-CADJPY_3h.PNG" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CAD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-15-USDCAD_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-15-USDCAD_3h.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="CAD/JPY and
USD/CAD, weekly chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-15-CADJPY-USDCAD.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-15-CADJPY-USDCAD.png"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry></feed>