<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/fundamental-analysis_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-03-18T09:44:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>How Greece bailout is affecting the Canadian markets</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-greece-bailout-is-affecting-the-canadian-markets/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-18T09:44:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-18:how-greece-bailout-is-affecting-the-canadian-markets/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Parity, parity, parity. That's all I hear about in Canada these days.
The &lt;a href="http://www.businessweek.com/news/2010-03-13/loonie-approaches-parity-on-bets-central-bank-to-increase-rates.html"&gt;media is saying&lt;/a&gt; (Businessweek) that the strength in loonie is
due to a higher than expected inflation data and so a possible rise in
our interest rate by the Bank of Canada this year is in the cards. But
that's just part of the story. As I was saying in my previous post,
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-should-i-care-about-other-markets-if-i-only-trade-___/"&gt;markets don't operate in a vacuum&lt;/a&gt;. The biggest news so far this year
on the global economy is the Greece bailout. Or more specifically, &lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/brussels/2010/03/18/is-there-a-greece-bailout/"&gt;is
there a bailout&lt;/a&gt; (WSJ) and &lt;em&gt;by whom&lt;/em&gt;? Greece is the 27th biggest
economy according to Wikipedia. Their GDP is 24% of Canada's. They are
by no means a small country. A default of this magnitude would have a
domino effect on the weak PIGS (Portugal, Ireland/Italy, Greece and
Spain) countries and beyond. Traders will lose confidence if Greece is
not saved. Then everyone will unload their holdings in those PIGS
countries and massive selling will drive their markets even further
down. A vicious cycle of downward spiral is thus formed in the short
term. Given that even a small time trader such as myself is aware of the
grim consequence, it is likely that Greece will be saved. So the next
question is, by whom? That is the big question which is still up in the
air and fiercely debated this month. The two candidates are the European
Central Bank (ECB) and the International Monetary Fund (IMF). As far as
we know, the ECB doesn't seem to want to take the burden upon itself.
The European Union isn't doing exactly well lately, in case you haven't
noticed. Its best performing country, Germany, doesn't want to penalize
their hardworking taxpayers for &lt;a href="https://www.cia.gov/library/publications/the-world-factbook/docs/notesanddefs.html?countryName=Greece&amp;amp;countryCode=gr&amp;amp;regionCode=eu#2116"&gt;the mistakes of Greece&lt;/a&gt; (CIA World
Factbook). So that leaves the IMF, the last line of defense for troubled
economies. If the IMF bails out Greece, that means the United States is
on the hook too as they are the biggest economy and backer of the IMF.
Europe's problem will become an American problem too. More bailouts for
the U.S. means more spending. Having spent &lt;a href="http://www.usdebtclock.org/"&gt;trillions already pumping up
the financial markets&lt;/a&gt; (U.S. debt clock) in the past couple of years,
this would tank the U.S. dollar into the abyss. Likewise, if the ECB
confirms that they will contain the problem and that IMF isn't involved.
The Euros will tank and the dollar will rise. But that's just guess work
for now. The one thing that's for sure is that a massive amount of money
will be spent to save Greece. Excessive money means inflation and higher
cost of commodities in the long run. Seeing that the Canadian market is
heavily commodity-related and that our loonie is even known as a
commodity currency, that is the reason behind why inflation is rising
fast and our economy is being propped up. Not necessarily because we are
doing terrific, but because we are sitting on a pile of gold and oil.
Real, tangible wealth in any kind of economy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bailout"></category><category term="Canada"></category><category term="fundamental analysis"></category><category term="Greece"></category></entry><entry><title>A lesson on the importance of fundamental awareness for a technical trader</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-lesson-on-the-importance-of-fundamental-awareness-for-a-technical-trader/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-31T16:27:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-31:a-lesson-on-the-importance-of-fundamental-awareness-for-a-technical-trader/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I paid a price last week in trading EURCHF for not knowing the
fundamental analysis about the currency pair. First of all, here's how
my trade played out. The support between 1.500 and 1.510 is apparent if
you look at Figure 1. So I went long as shown in Figure 2 (second blue
triangle from right) based on a positive divergence at a strong support
of 1.510. EURCHF stayed range bound for a over a day while my other
positions were having roller coaster rides. That's when I decided to
tighten up my stop on my EURCHF long from 1.508 to 1.5095 to limit my
risk exposure. As you can see in Figure 2, that was a bad decision. On
October 30, EURCHF made a swing downward to take out the nearby stops
and then launched upward right past my target. That would have been a
quick and low risk play if I hadn't micro-manged the trade and moved my
stop up while the daily setup was still sound. While getting stopped out
is part of the game, as there is never absolute certainty in a trade.
But in this case, the probability of this up move was substantially
greater than I would have guessed. The extra bit of information lies
outside of the chart. It seems that there is a well known secret that
the Swiss National Bank (SNB) has been intervening in the market to keep
the Swiss Franc from being even more overvalued. In particular, it's
well known that the SNB has their eyes on the 1.50 and 1.51 levels in
the EURCHF pair. SNB publicly announced their intention to intervene on
March 12. Immediately following the news, the EURCHF pair exploded up
470 pips in 20 minutes that day. If you look at Figure 1, you can see
that gigantic bar on March 12. The DailyFX has an article on this
&lt;a href="http://www.dailyfx.com/story/bio1/Swiss_Franc_Plunges_After_SNB_1236870114798.html"&gt;monumental event&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, the SNB has been coming to the rescue
of EURCHF in very obvious ways as shown in Figure 1 with the regular
spikes in prices. Prior to this October 30 move, EURCHF had an identical
price action exactly a month before on September 29, as shown in Figure
3. Back then, EURCHF also had a positive divergence on a test of support
at 1.5080. Then next thing you know, the pair popped over a 100 pips.
Obviously, the SNB is trying hard to paint the tape on the monthly chart
of EURCHF. As I was saying, the SNB is intervening in the market to keep
their currency from further over-valuation, which is hurting their local
economy. In both cases of Sept 29 and Oct 30, if the support was broken,
EURCHF would have stepped into a grave on the chart. Just look at that
huge vacuum below 1.50 on Figure 1. In this recent case on Oct 30, even
though I did go long because of the chart, I didn't have the edge of
knowing this information. Which led me missing this easy ride because I
didn't have as much conviction in this trade as I should have.
Coincidentally, as I have been aggravating to improve the win rates of
my trades, this came hitting me right on the head. So while I'm no
economist, I should at least be aware of the fundamental forces at play
in the currencies that I trade. At the end of the day, technical
analysis may provide guidelines to the mass psychology behind price
actions, but it is the fundamental and economic forces that are
ultimately driving the market. [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="580" caption="EURCHF"][&lt;img alt="EURCHF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-31-eurchf.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-31-eurchf.png"&gt;EURCHF&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption
id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURCHF,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="EURCHF, 3-hour" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-31-eurchf_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-31-eurchf_3h.png"&gt;EURCHF, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURCHF, 3-hour on Sept
30"][&lt;img alt="EURCHF, 3-hour on Sept 30" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-29-eurchf_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-29-eurchf_3h.png"&gt;EURCHF, 3-hour on Sept
30&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="fundamental analysis"></category></entry></feed>