<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/gbp_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-04-21T21:51:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>First QTD trade, 0.19% gain long EURGBP</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/first-qtd-trade-019-gain-long-eurgbp/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-21T21:51:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-04-21:first-qtd-trade-019-gain-long-eurgbp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My semi-automated trading system, Quantised Trading Desk, closed its
first trade this week. I was &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/"&gt;bullish EURGBP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/"&gt;USDJPY&lt;/a&gt;, and
bearish NZDUSD as per the previous discussions. The QTD system saved me
from the premature calls in both USDJPY and NZDUSD by not making any
trade this week. That, in and of itself, has made me very happy with
QTD's first week of live trading. Particular in light of how fierce that
USDJPY down move has been. As a bonus, QTD entered a long position in
EURGBP for a small 0.19% gain as illustrated below. My parameter were a
maximum of 0.25% risk per position. The gain could have been better if
it weren't for that 61% retracement. Not that I'm complaining as I
haven't even looked at the market this past couple of days while the
system is trading for me. USDJPY touched my threshold support price
80.70, my bullish sentiment needs to be reevaluated. NZDUSD just cracked
a higher high (marginally though), so I'm easing on the bear button for
now. EURGBP is testing some resistance to, so I'm not so eager to dive
in again. Overall, I've been 2/3 wrong. I've told you before that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/i-didnt-miss-a-boat-i-missed-a-freakin-rocket/"&gt;I'm
very bad at timing the market&lt;/a&gt;. That's why I developed QTD to trade
for me. Seeing that it's a long weekend, and I'll be way from town, I'm
just going to shut down my remote trade server in London until next week
when I can have some time to re-do my analysis. [caption
id="attachment_5361" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURGBP,
hourly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr-580x411.png" title="2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr-580x411.png" title="2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EUR"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="NZD"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Bullish EURGBP as hedge and Bearish NZDUSD as diversification</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-18T21:14:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-04-18:bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had more time to study the market tonight and is running a second
and a third instances of Quantised Trading Desk (QTD) to trade 3
currencies in total simultaneously. For my dollar bull sentiment, I'm
dividing between USDJPY long and NZDUSD short. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/"&gt;QTD still hasn't taken a
position in USDJPY in the past 24 hours&lt;/a&gt;. That's a good thing as
USDJPY is still drifting downward today even as the dollar is gaining
some ground. My line in the sand is at 80.70 for USDJPY and above 0.8100
for NZDUSD. EURGBP long is a hedge against my dollar longs. Again, I'm
not making any trade at this point but merely &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/quantised-trading-desk/"&gt;setting up QTD to wait
for the right moments to enter&lt;/a&gt;. A break below 0.8660 for EURGBP would
challenge my bullish bias. These three currencies should be my complete
market bias for a while. I'm just going to let QTD do its thing and
trade for me. Hopefully this will be the last you'll hear from me about
my market bias for a while. [caption id="attachment_5342"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="NZDUSD,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly-580x264.png" title="2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="attachment_5343"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURGBP,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly-580x264.png" title="2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly-580x264.png" title="2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly.png
  [&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly-580x264.png" title="2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="NZD"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: GBPJPY @ 145.24, Stop 144.70, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-28T21:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-28:paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I've switched over to long EURJPY @ 125.40 as EURGBP's
downtrend seem to be running out of steam. Moreover, EURJPY looks better
on the daily chart with a clear support and an oversold reading. I'm
back in my long GBPJPY play at 145.24. The currency pair is breaking an
hourly resistance since consolidating around 145. I had a low ball offer
at 144.20 since &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;taking my profit last night at 146.42&lt;/a&gt;. But that bid
for never filled. So I'm re-entering on a short-term breakout. For this
entry, I am risking 0.1% of my account. This re-entry is a tough
decision. Almost all the respectable pros that I &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/Quantisan"&gt;follow on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
are on the other side of this trade via other currency pairs. However,
my long setup is valid as long as GBPJPY is above 144 level. So I'll
take this trade until proven otherwise. Although I must admit that my
confidence in this trade is very low. I also considered long CADJPY
instead as it seems to offer more upside potential. However, as I've
been following the GBPJPY pair this week, I'll stick with my plan. I
also have a limit order to add more at 145.81 as you can see in Figure 1
below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-28-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed GBPJPY @ 146.42 for +140 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-27T22:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-27:paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just closed my GBPJPY long at 146.42 for around +140 pips average gain,
or 0.4% in the account balance. Damn good for a 24 hours holding. Obama
just finished his State of The Union address at the moment. I am not
impressed. Still all talk of change but nothing concrete yet. Anyway,
that's beside the point in this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trade log&lt;/a&gt;. 146.50 price level for
GBPJPY is the 10 day moving average. It has also been a strong support
back in late December. This should be a good resistance level. My guess
is that GBPJPY should stall, or even retrace, here for a while. Thus I'm
taking profit at this price as shown in Figure 1 (yellow triangle). I
still believe my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-144-24-stop-143-60-target-148/"&gt;bullish setup from yesterday&lt;/a&gt; is still good. So I'll
be watching this pair for a re-entry. Update: I re-entered at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-145-24-stop-144-70-target-148/"&gt;145.24
the next day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBPJPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-27-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper Trade: Long GBPJPY @ 144.24, Stop 143.60, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-26T22:33:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-26:paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My previous &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;short-side setup on GBP/JPY&lt;/a&gt; played out beautifully. Yet
I wasn't able to ride it down because I got stopped out on a stop-hunt
counter-move before the dive, see Fig. 1. Now that GBP/JPY has reached
its other end. I am betting for it to go reverse with a long position. I
expect this move to be more fierce with more upside potential as it's in
the direction of the long term up trend. Some people are calling the top
has been printed in the markets and the wind is now blowing the other
way. I am not one to guess what the market is about to do. So it's
business as usual until the trendline is broken. What I really like
about this setup is that GBP/JPY is testing a double trendline cross on
the weekly, Fig. 2. Secondly, the 3-hour chart of Figure 1 is showing a
RSI positive divergence on this test of the long term support. I am
quite confident of this setup. However, I am not confident about the
timing as GBP/JPY is known to be a wild horse and volatility could very
well stop me out, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;like last time&lt;/a&gt;. With
British preliminary GDP number coming out in about 6 hours, it might
have been wiser to wait until the after that to enter. On top of that,
the markets have been on a stall for the last few days waiting for data
in the next 48 hours. End-of-week volatility this week is expected to be
significant. Anyway, I've put in a position already and will just let it
run. This a small initial position with 0.1% of my account at risk. I
have also placed limit orders above resistances to add to this position.
We'll how this turns out soon enough. Lastly, even though I said I've
been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/barred-from-trading-at-work-a-curse-or-a-gift/"&gt;cut off from trading at my day job&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn't mean I'm
completely out of the game. I just have to adapt my manual trading
strategy while my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated system&lt;/a&gt; is still in development.
Basically meaning that I'll trade with a slower timeframe for
longer-term moves. All the better, as longer term moves are generally
less deceptive. Update: I closed this at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;146.42 for +140 pips gain&lt;/a&gt;
the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="GBP/JPY, weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Closed EUR/CHF and GBP/CHF Shorts: Best. Trade. Ever.</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-22T15:36:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-22:closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I was saying earlier this week, I have been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;stockpiling in EUR/CHF
short&lt;/a&gt; in my demo account (Fig. 1). Aside from that, I've also stocked
up some GBP/CHF shorts this week (Fig. 2). Both positions are now closed
because of my adjusted stops. These positions have single-handedly
lifted me half way out of a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/work-harder-trade-fewer-in-a-long-and-excruciating-trading-drawdown/"&gt;deep drawdown&lt;/a&gt; in my demo account. These
trades netted me about 1.5% in my demo funds. Yes, you read that right,
a meager 1.5% gain and I'm calling these my best trades. No, it's not
like I haven't had &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/good-trade/"&gt;good trades&lt;/a&gt; in terms of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-eurjpy-135-00-500-1-pips/"&gt;money made&lt;/a&gt; or the
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/eurusd-95-pips-in-2-hours-an-example-of-swing-and-day-trade-convergence/"&gt;fastest pips&lt;/a&gt;. These shorts aren't even close from just looking at
the numbers. Heck, it would have been a lot more profitable if I shorted
Euro and Pound with a Dollar or Yen counter this week. So why? If you
read my post on &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/analysing-monthly-forex-trading-performance-in-changing-market-conditions/"&gt;measuring trading performance&lt;/a&gt;, you may recall that I
don't measure success by profit alone. It is performance &lt;em&gt;in terms of&lt;/em&gt;
amount risked that matters in trading. These shorts in EUR/CHF and
GBP/CHF are my best forex trades ever (in my 4 months of fx trading so
far) simply because I risked no more than 0.2% at any given time (most
of the time there were no explicit risk as my stops have locked in
profits) to make that 1.5%. 1.5% gained by risking maximum of 0.2% gives
a Reward/Risk ratio of 1.5/0.2 = 7.5! There were several occasions when
I had doubts to add to my position or were pondering about taking
profits to settle my worries. Despite all of that, I soldiered on,
managed my stops like they were my babies, and piled more into the
position according to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;my plan&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/FTC/"&gt;trading setup&lt;/a&gt; (Fig. 1). By the time I started scaling out, I have
built my biggest (non-scalp) position. That gave me a lot of freedom in
scaling out as you can see on my exits shown in Figure 1 (red dots).
This Reward/Risk ratio is the highest I have achieved in recent memory.
I have always read about 10x or even 20x trades at the &lt;a href="http://www.smbtraining.com/blog/"&gt;SMB Capital
blog&lt;/a&gt;. Those guys can achieve this type of reward/risk ratio day in
and day out (I'm not affiliated with them). I guess that's the
difference between the pros and me. This is definitely something I am
strifing to do myself. &lt;strong&gt;Executing consistently high reward/risk
trades.&lt;/strong&gt; How I might do that? By continuing to improve on my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/"&gt;trading
skills&lt;/a&gt; and my understanding of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;forex markets&lt;/a&gt;. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EUR/CHF,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-EURCHF_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="alignnone" width="580"
caption="GBP/CHF, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-GBPCHF_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-22-GBPCHF_3h.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="good trade"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short GBPJPY @ 146.32, Target 143</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-14632-target-143/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-21T21:10:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-21:paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-14632-target-143/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GBP/JPY finally broke below an intermediate term wedge pattern formed
from Dec 30. See Figure 1 for the daily chart. I am noticeably late in
this GBP/JPY short entry because I was preoccupied with other positions
(e.g. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/closed-eurchf-and-gbpchf-shorts-best-trade-ever/"&gt;my EUR/CHF and GBPCHF shorts&lt;/a&gt;) today. In any case, this is an
intermediate term (a few days at least) play so there is no rush. My
first short was executed at 146.51 on obvious signs of short term pound
weakness versus the GBP/CHF pairs. GBP/JPY made some retracement on a
test of 146.00 but GBP/CHF kept on dropping, so I took a short position
once it touched the 146.50 resistance. My average price in this is
146.32. I have set my stop loss to lock in some profits already (which
might get taken out soon). Note that I just happened to be watching the
GBP/CHF currency pair as I have a position on shorting that too.
Otherwise EUR/GBP and GBP/USD would have been better for short-term
intermarket analysis because of higher liquidity. With regard to this
formation, as you can see on Figure 1, today's break of 147.50 gave way,
all the way, down to 143.00. This target price is estimated from the
height of the wedge pattern which it just broke through. The distance
from 147.50 to 143.00 is about the distance of the height of the wedge
(Dec 29th low to 30th high). Another reason for targeting this 143.00
price is because of my weekly chart of Figure 2. 142.50-143.00 is the
next support according to a long term trendline (lowest ascending white
line) as shown in Figure 2. GBP/JPY haven't seen these prices for a good
month, so hopefully the move down shouldn't be too difficult. As usual,
I will &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;stockpile my short position&lt;/a&gt; in this gradually to limit risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="GBP/JPY, daily
chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-21-GBPJPY_d.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="GBP/JPY, weekly
chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-21-GBPJPY_w.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-21-GBPJPY_w.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category></entry><entry><title>An example of how trading in fear is bad for your account</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-example-of-how-trading-in-fear-is-bad-for-your-account/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-18T19:25:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-18:an-example-of-how-trading-in-fear-is-bad-for-your-account/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having had &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-bad-eurusd-day-trading-and-what-to-do-about-it/"&gt;a hard time day trading the EUR/USD last week&lt;/a&gt;, things
haven't been well for me this week either with the market in a gridlock.
My one and only viable setup so far is &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftcs/"&gt;built for a trending market&lt;/a&gt;.
So this range-bound market is new territory for me as I experiment (in
hindsight, haphazardly) to come up with more profitable forex trading
setups. As you can imagine, trading without discipline is a recipe for
diaster. I have given back all the paper gain from this month by the
start of this week and is treading on thin ice with my demo account
dipping dangerously close to the November opening balance. Needless to
say, I do not want to see my account in the red for this month. But that
is what happened after today's string of failed trades. I am officially
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;in the red for this month&lt;/a&gt;, for now. While there are several mistakes
I made resulting in this mess, I think it all boils down to one flaw in
my trading this week. Yes, those day trading stints I did surely have
put a dent in my demo account, but what's worse is that I've
unconsciously have let those losses affect my trading mentality. These
losses were stuck in my mind and my mental "goal" for this week was
recovering from them. However, I have approached the problem in the
wrong way by not wanting to lose anymore in my account. In other words,
I was afraid of losing. So how did that materially affect my trading?
Here is a simple example as illustrated in my order history on the
GBP/JPY chart attached at the bottom of this post. The 3 yellow
triangles are my short entries and the 3 red dots marks the stopped
exits. According to my setup, my original entry at 149.50 had a stop at
150.50. But I moved my stop closer to 149.80 in the morning because I
didn't want to risk more. That got taken out easily as 149.80 is within
the congestion zone. Then I tried to short it a couple more times with
tight stops because I see the downside potential to be still intact.
Those were eaten up alive too and now I don't have a position because it
would have been more foolish to keep trying in vain. While just 3 trades
wouldn't have done much damage, I was doing the same thing across the
board in shorting CAD/JPY and EUR/CAD. A few here and a few there. They
add up to a bad day. As of this writing, it looks like these pairs are
finally moving in my direction. But instead of being patient with
reasonable stops, I thought I could do better and micro-managed my
positions to end up taking multiple small losses and with nothing left
on the table to ride the move. So what is the correct way of following
up on a dent in the account? I should have done the following instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce risk exposure by limiting trade size or overall opened
    positions until I am back up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on what I did wrong last week and stop doing that, i.e. no
    more day trading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recall my best trades and do more of that, i.e. my one and only
    finalized setup, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so coincidentally, now that I'm in the deepest drawdown ever, this
is as good as ever to put this emergency recovery procedure into
practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="GBP/JPY,
1-hour"][&lt;img alt="GBP/JPY, 1-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-GBPJPY_1h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-GBPJPY_1h.PNG"&gt;GBP/JPY, 1-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="drawdown"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="recovery"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short GBP/USD 50% @ 1.634, Out 1.645 (-110 pips)</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpusd-50-1634-out-1645-110-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-21T09:36:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-21:paper-trade-short-gbpusd-50-1634-out-1645-110-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, that descending trendline didn't last long for GBP/USD. I shorted
it when it was testing it and saw that the RSI was at a prior high too
(Fig. 1). I placed my order just below the short-term ascending support
to hope for a break to the downside, see Fig. 2. GBP/USD consolidated
around that short-term support for a few hours and has now broken upward
to a strong resistance at 1.6600. It's the top of a previous congestion
zone, highlighted rectangle in Fig. 1. GBP/USD at 1.666 is a very
tempting short, but never short a new high, as my rules say. So I'm
gonna wait for a few more hours with this and see how it goes. Position
size: 50% Entry: 1.634 Stop: 1.645, stopped out. Target: 1.6100 Reward /
Risk = 240 / 110 = 2.2 \&amp;lt; 3, so only 50% position. I think I'll stick
with the 3 factor as a limit. Even these 2+ trades aren't working so
well for me because my probability of success has been low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="GBP/USD"][&lt;img alt="GBP/USD" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-21-gbpusd.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-21-gbpusd.png"&gt;GBP/USD&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="GBP/USD, 3 hour"][&lt;img alt="GBP/USD, 3
hour" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-21-gbpusd_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-21-gbpusd_3h.png"&gt;GBP/USD, 3 hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Missed opportunity review: GBP/JPY spiked 500 pips in 24 hours</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/missed-opportunity-review-gbpjpy-spiked-500-pips-in-24-hours/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-15T22:40:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-15:missed-opportunity-review-gbpjpy-spiked-500-pips-in-24-hours/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It looks as though my analysis for &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-50-long-gbpjpy-in-142-861-stop-141-16/"&gt;GBP/JPY making a reversal&lt;/a&gt; was
correct. However, my short term entry needed to be improved for me to
profit on my intermediate term analysis. In particular, I should have
looked at a major short term resistance line instead of an arbitrary
weak resisitance line as I did when I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-50-long-gbpjpy-in-142-861-stop-141-16/"&gt;entered the long
previously&lt;/a&gt;. That didn't go so well as I was
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-out-gbpjpy-141-70-116-10-pips/"&gt;stopped out soon afterward&lt;/a&gt; when GBP/JPY was consolidating. In
hindsight, if I'm to try for a reversal, at least wait for the price to
break a strong short term resistance and then use the recent low as the
stop. The preferred resistance line for GBP/JPY in this missed trade can
be seen in Fig. 1, which I drew many days ago and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-50-long-gbpjpy-in-142-861-stop-141-16/"&gt;also can be
seen&lt;/a&gt; in my previous entry (Figure 2 on that
page, the higher of the 2 lines). New Figure 2 attached below shows the
bigger picture of GBP/JPY in a daily chart to see what could have
perspired. My target of 148 was spot on too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="GBP/JPY, 3-hour" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-15-gbpjpy_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-15-gbpjpy_3h.png"&gt;GBP/JPY, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="GBP/JPY"][&lt;img alt="GBP/JPY" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-15-gbpjpy.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/2009-10-15-gbpjpy.png"&gt;GBP/JPY&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="GBP"></category><category term="hindsight"></category><category term="JPY"></category></entry></feed>