<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/goal_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-01-18T07:30:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>One year down, nineteen more to go until I can trade for a living</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/one-year-down-nineteen-more-to-go-until-i-can-trade-for-a-living/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-18T07:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-01-18:one-year-down-nineteen-more-to-go-until-i-can-trade-for-a-living/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Early in 2010, I discussed about my plan to [grow my trading accounts
organically and eventually trade for a living][] (i.e. live and breath
in the market 24/7). Now that the first whole year of my long term plan
has passed, I can update my visualization table as shown. &lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2011-01-14-monetarygoal.png" /&gt; 2010 was
a good year. My starting capital for 2011 is 63% more than expected.
This is mostly due to the \$13,000 prize money from &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-interview-at-dukascopy-in-geneva/"&gt;winning six of nine
Dukascopy automated trading contests&lt;/a&gt;. On the contrary to my
fortuitous success, I revised some of my estimations noted in the table
to be even more conservative. In particular, I reduced my annual deposit
to reflect real bookkeeping data in 2010 and lowered my investment yield
expectation based on my performance data throughout the past 10 years of
my trading. To mitigate these reductions, I expect to continue
depositing funds while I receive a salaried income rather than stop
mid-way as originally proposed. The effect of inflation is deliberately
ignored in this table because I'm discounting its effect in my
investment yield estimate rather than adding more columns. It's all
guess work for now anyway. Nineteen years is indeed a long time. It is a
&lt;em&gt;worst case scenario&lt;/em&gt; assuming that I will grow my accounts organically
and not do anything else. I doubt I will need that much time as there
are means other than trading a personal account to achieve trading for a
living. I might discuss more about this later in the year once something
materialize. My focus this year is to finish developing my proprietary
Java trading platform with my partner and put it to good use in the
forex market. Nineteen years or not, the fact that trading for a living
is even possible for a self-taught amateur such as myself is testament
to these incredible times that we're living in. I fully intend to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-sign-that-you-are-truly-enjoying-what-you-do/"&gt;enjoy
every second of it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[grow my trading accounts organically and eventually trade for a
  living]: http://www.quantisan.com/visualize-and-grow-rich/&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="goal"></category><category term="trading for a living"></category></entry><entry><title>Visualize and Grow Rich</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/visualize-and-grow-rich/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-23T07:18:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-04-23:visualize-and-grow-rich/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just read &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1585424331?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=quantisan-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1585424331"&gt;Think and Grow Rich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=quantisan-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1585424331" /&gt; (affiliate) for the third time
last weekend. One of the key ideas presented in the book is to set
realistic long term goal and stick with it every single day. This
reminded me of something that I've done lately which I think is very
helpful in disciplining myself in my trading. That something is this
table below. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-04-20-monetarygoal.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-04-20-monetarygoal.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This is a table of my planned deposit and
return for my trading account. The table shows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the amount that I plan to deposit into my trading account each year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the accumulated principal at the end of each year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the expected yield, which is based on my historical trading
    performance from the past 10 years of trading, minus the [couple of
    blowups I've had][] (which is a reason why I am starting from
    scratch in this table)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimating future values is nothing new. What I find particularly useful
in this table is the fact that they show the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My minimum savings goal for each year (deposit column). So that I
    can project an annual budget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effect of compounding. A reminder that I don't need to perform
    exquisitely in my trading to reach my goal. This helps keep my
    trading expectation realistic and not over-trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can trade for a living after 16 years even with my conservative
    expectations. This is my ultimate goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can update this table at the end of each year with real data so
    that I can see where I stand with respect to my goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple and easy to do trading goal visualization. I visualize
this table often to remind myself what I need to do. Both in terms of
setting a bar above to push myself as well as limiting my expectations
to realism. A problem many new traders have, myself included, is the
need to perform, and in a big way (making it big in that one trade), or
conversely, afraid to miss opportunities. This table helps me keep a
realistic mentality just so I don't &lt;em&gt;back up the truck&lt;/em&gt; in any
particular trade. As the table clearly shows, I don't need to take
unnecessary risk to reach my goal of trading for a living. What is your
trading goal? What is your plan to achieve it? How do you keep yourself
motivated? These are some fundamental questions that this table can be
helpful in answering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="goal"></category><category term="trading for a living"></category></entry></feed>