<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/google-app-engine_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-03-03T21:19:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>First look at Google App Engine for automated trading and quant analysis on the cloud</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/first-look-at-google-app-engine-for-automated-trading-and-quant-analysis-on-the-cloud/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-03T21:19:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-03:first-look-at-google-app-engine-for-automated-trading-and-quant-analysis-on-the-cloud/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just spent the last few hours looking into Google App Engine to use it
for trading. Google App Engine (GAE) is a cloud computing development
and hosting platform for web applications. GAE is similar to the
well-known Amazon EC2 service but it is also very different. The main
difference between GAE and EC2 is that GAE is not as flexible as EC2 but
it is a lot easier to develop on. Think of it like using C++ (EC2) to
write your own trading platform to using EasyLanguage on TradeStation or
MQL on Metatrader (GAE). Another advantage for using Google App Engine
is that it is free! Well, to a certain extent. It is free for a limited
monthly usage. However, Google's free quota is known to be very generous
(think Gmail) and this is no exception. Based on the numbers, it looks
comparable to a typical \$20/month virtual private server (VPS) hosting
package. My guess is that you can run a decent personal quant program on
it if you keep the resources for yourself (private use). For more
information on the free quota, you can read the &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/appengine/docs/quotas.html"&gt;current GAE quota&lt;/a&gt;
web page or the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_App_Engine"&gt;Wikipedia page for GAE&lt;/a&gt;. You might be wondering how
did I spend a few hours just reading on GAE? The answer is that I've
done a brief research, planning, and assessment to see how GAE can be
put to use in terms of quantitative analysis for automated and
discretionary trading. Without going through all of my notes and logic,
here's the gist of my conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Automated Trading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since GAE is also a SDK, it has a restricted programming API. You can't
just plug in any custom library of your own (i.e. your broker's API)
into your program. That is its advantage and its disadvantage.
Furthermore, GAE only support HTTP and HTTPS. So you can't open a socket
for your connection either. These limitations won't be changing anytime
soon as GAE is designed to be like that for security reasons. Basically,
there's no way for your web application on GAE to connect with your
broker for trading. So much for that idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Discretionary Trading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things look brighter for discretionary trading though. A big bonus with
using Google App Engine is that it supports the Google Finance API.
Google Finance offers free real-time stock quotes. Combine it with the
programming capability of the Google App Engine and you have yourself a
free number cruncher in the cloud. However, GAE is definitely no match
for your personal computer, so why would you go through all that
trouble? One possible scenario in which this could be useful is for
traders that is often on the road or traders such as myself in which we
have a day job. In that case, you can set you quant analytics on GAE as
a private web application and then you can access it as a web page
anywhere on your mobile phone. One of the obvious limitation with using
GAE is that it has limited features for scientific computing. For
example, it doesn't support Numpy in the Python SDK. As such, I can't
imagine using GAE for anything more than simple technical analysis for
now. I certainly hope that GAE can include more powerful scientific
computing capabilities in the near future. Until then, I really can't
see Google App Engine offering much help aside from performing
algorithmic tasks to help with your trading analysis. Their open issues
log does announce that &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/googleappengine/issues/detail?id=190"&gt;Numpy is being integrated into GAE&lt;/a&gt; though. So
that's a great sign for things to come! I am very hopeful of GAE's
potential as a free cloud server to host my quant analytics on. We'll
just have to wait for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cloud computing"></category><category term="Google App Engine"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="VPS"></category></entry></feed>