<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/grid-computing_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-08-20T05:51:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Using your idling trading computer for a good cause</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/using-your-idling-trading-computer-for-a-good-cause/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-20T05:51:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-08-20:using-your-idling-trading-computer-for-a-good-cause/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, computing power is practically free for trading. It does not
take much processing power to trade or chart on your computer. The
situation is even more wasteful for many mechanical traders obligated to
keep their computers on all the time. So what can you do with all that
idling power? Through World Community Grid (non-profit), you can help
develop new cures for diseases or discover affordable solar energy.
According to Wikipedia, "&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_community_grid"&gt;World Community Grid&lt;/a&gt; (WCG) is an effort to
create the world's largest public computing grid to tackle scientific
research projects that benefit humanity." By joining WCG and installing
an open-source software, you are enabling your computer's idling cycles
to process data from various research projects as part of a cluster of
computers. From the &lt;a href="http://www.worldcommunitygrid.org/stat/viewGlobal.do"&gt;WCG statistics page&lt;/a&gt;, over half a million users
have signed up. It is one of the three biggest non-profit grid computing
efforts in the world (the other being SETI@home and folding@home). I
tried &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETI@home"&gt;SETI@home&lt;/a&gt; almost a decade ago to help search for E.T. But it
wasn't until the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folding@home"&gt;folding@home&lt;/a&gt; project started when grid computing
gained popularity. Tell people that you're leaving your computer on to
search for E.T. and people couldn't hold their laughs at you. But
telling people that you're leaving your computer on to find cures for
diseases ... then all of a sudden, it's philanthropic. The reasons why I
chose to devote my computer resources to WCG instead of the other two
are simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It offers more than one projects to choose. You can fold proteins,
    find energy efficient material, simulate climate change, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The projects offered have specific, realistic goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects do get completed (unlike SETI@home, for example, since no
    E.T. has been found yet after 10 years).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New projects are added as older ones finish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, that's just my personal choice. Take a look at the three
projects mentioned for more information. In addition, there's &lt;a href="http://itnomad.wordpress.com/2010/05/19/a-better-rice-for-the-world/"&gt;an
interview with a researcher using WCG&lt;/a&gt;. If you decide that WCG is
right for you, feel free to &lt;a href="%20http://www.worldcommunitygrid.org/reg/viewRegister.do?teamID=JQ7WNMDLX1"&gt;join Team Traders and start data crunching
together&lt;/a&gt;. (Warning: Like any software, use at your own risk)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://www.worldcommunitygrid.org/getDynamicImage.do?teamId=JQ7WNMDLX1&amp;amp;mnOn=true&amp;amp;stat=3&amp;amp;imageNum=1&amp;amp;rankOn=true&amp;amp;projectsOn=false&amp;amp;special=true" frameborder="0" name="di" scrolling="no" width="405px" height="145px"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="grid computing"></category><category term="WCG"></category></entry></feed>