<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/indicator_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-10-14T12:20:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Canadian VIX: TSX to have their own volatility index</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/canadian-vix-tsx-to-have-their-own-volatility-index/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-14T12:20:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-10-14:canadian-vix-tsx-to-have-their-own-volatility-index/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't know if anyone noticed, but in my previous post &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/three-obvious-reasons-to-watch-13000-on-the-tsx/"&gt;discussing the
TSX&lt;/a&gt;, I included a chart of VIX (S&amp;amp;P500 volatility index) versus S&amp;amp;P
500. VIX is one of the market indicators that I can't live without.
However, as much as the Canadian and the American equity markets are
correlated, they are still separate markets. So using the VIX vs. S&amp;amp;P500
on an analysis of the TSX is like borrowing salt from thy neighbour. But
there's no more need for that soon as TSX is finally getting its own
volatility index starting Monday (October 18)! This is to replace the MX
Implied Volatility Index (MVX) from the Montreal Exchange, which I
didn't have access to previously (aside from &lt;a href="http://www.m-x.ca/indicesmx_mvx_en.php"&gt;data published on their
website&lt;/a&gt;). One question I have is that the TSX VIX will be based on
TSX 60 index options activity according on their &lt;a href="http://www.standardandpoors.com/servlet/BlobServer?blobheadername3=MDT-Type&amp;amp;blobcol=urldata&amp;amp;blobtable=MungoBlobs&amp;amp;blobheadervalue2=inline%3B+filename%3D20101014_TSX-60-VIX_Volatility-Launch.pdf&amp;amp;blobheadername2=Content-Disposition&amp;amp;blobheadervalue1=application%2Fpdf&amp;amp;blobkey=id&amp;amp;blobheadername1=content-type&amp;amp;blobwhere=1243766536405&amp;amp;blobheadervalue3=UTF-8"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;, but
the TSX 60 index options isn't that active. So would the TSX VIX be as
efficient as the S&amp;amp;P500 VIX? An opportunity with the introduction of TSX
VIX on the Toronto Exchange is that I can now place bets on market
volatility in my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/ranking-investment-options-for-my-self-directed-rrsp/"&gt;self-directed RRSP trading account&lt;/a&gt;. Which is
arguably more predictable than the underlying index these days... In any
case, this will be a vital market indicator for Canadian market traders.
For more information on TSX VIX, see the &lt;a href="http://www.standardandpoors.com/indices/sp-tsx-60-vix/en/us/?indexId=sp-tsx-60-vix"&gt;product information page on
Standard &amp;amp; Poor's&lt;/a&gt;. And a hat tip to &lt;a href="http://optionmatters.ca/"&gt;Option Matters&lt;/a&gt; (Montreal
Exchange's blog on options) for this news.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="indicator"></category><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="VIXC.TO"></category></entry><entry><title>A leading indicator to spot financial market Black Swan Events?</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-leading-indicator-to-spot-financial-market-black-swan-events/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-16T10:37:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-12-16:a-leading-indicator-to-spot-financial-market-black-swan-events/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Black Swan Events or 4-sigma moves (e.g. 1987 Black Monday and 2008
crash) in the markets are by definition hard to predict. Hard, but not
impossible. Experienced traders utilize prudent risk management to
shield themselves from monstrous losses, and some can even &lt;a href="http://www.xtrenders.com/2008/10/dare-to-short-this.html"&gt;profit
immensely from them&lt;/a&gt;. However, for us average folks, is there some
kind of simple warning signs that could give us a heads up to these sort
of extraordinary moves? In this post, I will introduce a simple leading
indicator that seems to do the job quite well. I will talk about what it
is and why it seems to work. Of course, this is merely based on limited
observations and is not to be construed as a vigorous analysis. The
particular indicator I am referring to is the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/finance?q=GOOGLEINDEX_US:INVEST"&gt;Google Investing Index&lt;/a&gt;
(GII). Figure 1 below shows the GII vs. S&amp;amp;P 500 from 2004. The blue line
is the GII, the red line is the S&amp;amp;P 500. What I have observed is that
rapid (in a month's time) rise from a negative reading to +20% reading
of GII correspond with a shift in sentiment in the market rather well.
Referring to Figure 1 below, this condition occurred 4 times since 2004.
I marked these 4 occurrences on the graph with green dots. As you can
see, they correspond with the double top on S&amp;amp;P, first dive in the
crash, the big one in October 2008, and then even confirming the 666
reversal in March 2009. It seems to be a leading indicator for down
moves but lagging on upward reveral. Mostly noticeably though, is that
the GII gave extreme readings, and in the direction of our condition
(negative to positive jump), days before the big crash in October 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="Google Investing
Index vs. S&amp;amp;P 500 (green dots mark signals)"][&lt;img alt="Google Investing Index
vs. S&amp;amp;P 500" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-12-15-GoogInvIndex.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-12-15-GoogInvIndex.png"&gt;Google Investing Index vs. S&amp;amp;P 500&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] While this
can be mere coincidence, here is why I think this index holds some
truth. The GII measures the amount of search traffic for topics relating
to investing in the U.S. And with Google dominating the online searching
market (&lt;a href="http://www.comscore.com/Press_Events/Press_Releases/2009/11/comScore_Releases_October_2009_U.S._Search_Engine_Rankings"&gt;65% as of October 2009&lt;/a&gt; according to comScore), we can assume
GII to measure what the general public is interested in. Now, as we
probably know, market extremes are driven by irrational emotions.
There's an old saying that goes like this, on market highs, when even
the taxi driver is giving you stock advice, it's time to get out of the
market. When all the people have invested already, who's left to buy and
drive the price even higher? This is ultimately a supply and demand
effect. While we can't count heads in the market, we can estimate market
sentiment. The GII is just one more way of doing that. And it does so by
giving us a reading of the market sentiment according to the general
public. You know, the last ones in the party to pickup the mess the pros
have have left behind. That is exactly what sets the GII apart from the
plethora of existing market sentiment indicators. It is a market
sentiment indicator on mass psychology, but a crude one at that. Scoring
4 out of 4 positives is good, but the small sample size render this a
mere observation of interest. I do not recommend trading on this
indicator. However, it does seem promising to serve as an additonal
input to an analytical system... In summary, here is the condition of
this GIS (for &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;oogle &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;nvesting index for market &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;entiment)
indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the condition is true for a turn in the market when GII jumps from a
    negative to +20% or more within a month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, notice that the GII is still low at the moment while many are
calling the top is imminent, or even that it has happened at 1120 in
recent weeks. Thus, according to GIS indicator, this market rally is
still intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="black swan"></category><category term="indicator"></category><category term="market sentiment"></category></entry><entry><title>How to use FX futures to narrow down which forex pair to trade</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-use-fx-futures-to-narrow-down-which-forex-pair-to-trade/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-20T14:10:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-20:how-to-use-fx-futures-to-narrow-down-which-forex-pair-to-trade/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A problem I have is that once a currency pair shows a viable trading
setup, other related pairs often show the same setup too. A reason for
this phenomenon is that markets don't operate in a vacuum. When markets
really move, everything move together. So the highly correlated markets
can scream for entry at the same time. The real question though, is
which one should I put my chips in? There are limitless methods on how
you can approach this. The one I'll talk about in this post is a simple
method of comparing your candidates using the currency futures. Why use
the futures? Because they provide a standardized platform, which is
essential when comparing things. As a bonus, there is a US dollar index
futures to help with analysis of the dollar. Not a trivial process on
its own. I will explain my method by way of an example. This morning, I
was considering to go long in AUD/JPY, CAD/JPY, AUD/USD, or short
USD/CAD according to signals from my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC setup&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, I could have
just choose which one to trade based on the RSI rating or some other
indicator. But I don't put much faith in indicators for various reasons.
So a method I typical use is to just go through the charts to manulally
identify which has better reward/risk or better support/resistance. As
you can imagine, this is very time consuming. In practice, I only
compare AUD/JPY vs. CAD/JPY and AUD/USD vs. USD/CAD, and then compare
the winners of those two matches. Like in a tournament. Not that much of
a hassle but the issue with this approach is that I'm adding another
layer of uncertainty with all these unscientific comparisons. That could
have a significant negative impact on my trading. In a good trading
strategy, every step taken should be to improve your probability of
success or the reward/risk ratio. As such, it's better to keep my
process simple. This is where the currency futures indices is of value.
They provide a big picture perspective and serve as a standardized data
for comparison. Using my example, I needed to choose between shorting US
dollar or Japanese yen (I repeated the process for choosing AUD or CAD).
Figure 1 below shows the 4-hour chart of both currencies for the past 10
days. It's evident from the chart that the US dollar is in a range and
the Japanese yen (actually it's JPY/USD) is moving up. 1 point goes to
US dollar trade. Next, I identify the strength of the support/resistance
to estimate in the case that the trade goes against me, which would have
better cushioning. It's a crude form of risk estimation. From the figure
below, see that the dollar has a clear resistance just below 76 and it
is currently stretched away from the cyan-coloured moving average.
Whereas the yen is near a recent top with no prior occurence and it has
been sitting above the moving average for a while. Another point for
dollar short. USD 2 : JPY 0. Consequently, I went long AUD/USD this
morning instead of AUD/JPY. This is by no means a vigorous methodology.
I'm not saying that shorting US dollar is a good idea from this
simplistic comparative process. It's just that my setup tells me to go
long AUD/USD or AUD/JPY, this is just a quick and easy way to help me
decide which trade to take. Nothing more. As an aside, some people may
prefer to use currency ETF, UUP and FXY, instead. But I don't like to
use ETF as a data source as the price is noisier because they are
affected by other factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="504" caption="US dollar and
Japanese yen futures indices"]&lt;img alt="US dollar and Japanese yen futures
indices" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-20-DX-6J.PNG" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="indicator"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Option Pain (Max Pain) to estimate stock price</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/using-option-pain-max-pain-to-estimate-stock-price/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-28T13:50:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-10-28:using-option-pain-max-pain-to-estimate-stock-price/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB122518913601675675.html"&gt;market is sorting things out today&lt;/a&gt;, I'd like to document a
simple stock price predictor based on put/call activity called Option
Pain or Max Pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is widely believed that professional traders favour writing options.
Since trading options is a zero-sum game, it is in their best interest
if a majority of options expire worthless on expiration day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By observing the open interest of a stock at each strike price, we can
see at what price the Option Pain would occur. Of course, this is just
another tool for the trader to use, so do your own due diligence as
usual when trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
[caption id="attachment_500" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="SLW Nov08 Max Pain"][&lt;img alt="Nov '08 SLW Option Pain" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/slw-optionpain.jpg?w=500" title="slw-optionpain" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this chart from &lt;a href="http://www.optionpain.com/MaxPain/Max-Pain.php"&gt;Option Pain&lt;/a&gt;, we can see that the minimum
option total value of November SLW is at \$5. So our max pain price is
at \$5 for November's SLW. That is to say, if SLW settles at \$5, then
the most call option would expire worthless and most of the put option
would expire worthless. Such that the option sellers (the pros) can
pocket your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to use this information is to find the best Max Pain to
Current Price ratio among a list of stocks. For example, SLW closed at
\$2.59 yesterday. Its max pain is \$5 from the chart above. That is
almost a double. Note, however, that we haven't figured out the
probability of SLW reaching \$5. This would be something for me to look
into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, GOOG's max pain for November is at \$360. Its previous
closing price is 329.49. Based on these numbers, SLW is a better buy
than GOOG for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="Nov '08 SLW Option Pain" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/slw-optionpain.jpg?w=500" title="slw-optionpain" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/slw-optionpain.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="indicator"></category><category term="options"></category><category term="SLW"></category></entry><entry><title>Stock move estimation on expiration day based on option prices</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/stock-move-estimation-on-expiration-day-based-on-option-prices/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-15T18:03:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-10-15:stock-move-estimation-on-expiration-day-based-on-option-prices/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_387" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="SPX move estimation based on option prices"][&lt;img alt="SPX move
estimation based on option prices" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/option_est1.jpg?w=500" title="option_est1" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to document a useful technique I picked up today from Tom
Sosnoff on &lt;a href="http://shadowtrader.net/"&gt;ShadowTrader&lt;/a&gt;. It's based on the idea that option pricing
has become so efficient that it can be used to predict actual stock
move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it is expiration Friday this week, the Oct 08 index option are
expiring in two days. So for something like, SPX, the Oct 08 call/put
has only two days left. Thus, there's little time decay factored in the
price for these options with respect to the actual price. In other
words, SPX and SPX options prices are converging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if we take the price of the straddle and strangle strike on the
money, it should be the expected move for SPX for this Friday. For
example, SPX closed at 907.84 today. The price for a straddle at 905
strike is \$48.65. The price for a strangle at 900/910 strikes is
\$45.30. We'll average the two numbers (\$48.65 + \$45.30) / 2 = \$47.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the SPX is expected to move about 50 points this Friday either up or
down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="SPX move estimation based on option prices" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/option_est1.jpg?w=500" title="option_est1" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/option_est1.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="indicator"></category></entry><entry><title>Back to Basics: Market sentiment via 2-line EMA on S&amp;P500</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/back-to-basics-market-sentiment-via-2-line-ema-on-sp500/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-08T10:12:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-10-08:back-to-basics-market-sentiment-via-2-line-ema-on-sp500/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_303" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/sc_snp500.png?w=500" title="sc_snp500" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most, if not THE most, important theme in trading is
identifying if we're in a bull or bear market. It's easier to "ride with
the wave" than to fight against it. While there are an abundance of
work, studies, theories, or whatever, on calling out market sentiments,
I feel that the most useful way of doing it would be ones that stick to
the facts. And the only fact we can be certain of in the market is the
price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's the idea (definitely not original) for &lt;strong&gt;guessing&lt;/strong&gt; market
sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bull market = 50 dma &gt; 200 dma for S&amp;amp;P 500.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bear market = 50 dma \&amp;lt; 200 dma for S&amp;amp;P 500.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any indicator, this is not a law. It's just a signal to give you
a piece of information for you to &lt;strong&gt;intrepret&lt;/strong&gt; based on the
fundamentals and maybe other technical analysis tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/sc_snp500.png?w=500" title="sc_snp500" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2008/10/sc_snp500.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="indicator"></category><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="S&amp;amp;P 500"></category></entry><entry><title>Using new MA algorithm to rewrite old indicators</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/using-new-ma-algorithm-to-rewrite-old-indicators/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-06T00:56:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-01-06:using-new-ma-algorithm-to-rewrite-old-indicators/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seeing that many indicators use a MA for calculation. It may be possible
to use new MA algorithm to improve on their calculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the RS in RSI is something like RS = EMA(up days) /
EMA(down days). We could change it to RS = HMA(up days) / HMA(down
days). Since HMA is much faster, the resulting H-RSI may be faster too.
This can be useful in day trading strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More work needs to be done to test this idea.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EasyLanguage"></category><category term="indicator"></category></entry><entry><title>New moving average</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/new-moving-average/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-06T00:49:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2008-01-06:new-moving-average/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I downloaded Hull Moving Average, Adaptive Moving Average, and a Kalmann
Filter today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the figure, the blue/red is HMA(8), cyan is AMA(10), yellow is EMA(9)
as comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Vlx60iTPx5s/R4EXOvY4uYI/AAAAAAAAAE0/APxlgKxuETU/s400/3mas.jpg" /&gt;][] Notice that HMA is super fast and follows the price closely.
AMA lags more but does a good job of smoothing outt the noise. EMA is as
usual and very laggy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strategy I'm thinking of is to use 3 different MA's instead of only
EMA to improve the previously discussed 3EMA crossover strategy. The
problem with the 3 EMA crossover strategy is that EMA lags too much, so
it's not good for day trading so reaction time is the key to catching /
exiting the waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe using the HMA as the fast MA, AMA as the base, and something else
to verify the trend can work. As I've said before, remember to use
something to filter out the whipsaws. But don't use something laggy as
it would defeat the whole purpose of a fast indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, HMA can be used as a proxy to smooth out some inputs. i.e.
RSI(HMA(close, 8), 14) or HMA(RSI(close, 14), 8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Vlx60iTPx5s/R4EXOvY4uYI/AAAAAAAAAE0/APxlgKxuETU/s400/3mas.jpg" /&gt;]: http://bp1.blogger.com/_Vlx60iTPx5s/R4EXOvY4uYI/AAAAAAAAAE0/APxlgKxuETU/s1600-h/3mas.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EasyLanguage"></category><category term="indicator"></category></entry><entry><title>Trending and Ranging indicators</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/trending-and-ranging-indicators/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-21T15:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2007-12-21:trending-and-ranging-indicators/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;RSI and MACD makes them appropriate for trending markets. For
directionless, chopping markets, you need to use Stochastics and Wm%R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from &lt;a href="http://www.billcara.com/archives/2007/12/caras_commentary_community_cha_94.html"&gt;g034&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="indicator"></category></entry></feed>