<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/jpy_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-05-08T22:58:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Bearish USDJPY on 19th week of 2011</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bearish-usdjpy-on-19th-week-of-2011/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-05-08T22:58:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-05-08:bearish-usdjpy-on-19th-week-of-2011/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am going bearish on USDJPY this week using my QTD system. No position
is opened at this point. I am merely entering my sentiment into &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/quantised-trading-desk/"&gt;the
system to trade for me&lt;/a&gt;. Figure 1 is a daily chart of USDJPY. Notice
it's lack of life despite the USD making headlines last week. Figure 2
shows the move with a US dollar index, USDX, daily chart. Furthermore,
according to the order book on USDJPY, there are massive bullish
positions in the red (at a loss) which make this pair ripe for some bull
squeeze. I am going short on NZDUSD as a hedge on this move. It is my
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/"&gt;favourite long USD pair these days&lt;/a&gt;. [caption id="attachment_5405"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USDJPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDJPY-580x383.png" title="2011-05-08-USDJPY" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="attachment_5406"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="U.S. dollar index futures,
USDX"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDX-580x288.png" title="2011-05-08-USDX" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDJPY-580x383.png" title="2011-05-08-USDJPY" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDJPY.png
  [&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDX-580x288.png" title="2011-05-08-USDX" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDX.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="JPY"></category><category term="NZD"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>First QTD trade, 0.19% gain long EURGBP</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/first-qtd-trade-019-gain-long-eurgbp/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-21T21:51:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-04-21:first-qtd-trade-019-gain-long-eurgbp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My semi-automated trading system, Quantised Trading Desk, closed its
first trade this week. I was &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/"&gt;bullish EURGBP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/"&gt;USDJPY&lt;/a&gt;, and
bearish NZDUSD as per the previous discussions. The QTD system saved me
from the premature calls in both USDJPY and NZDUSD by not making any
trade this week. That, in and of itself, has made me very happy with
QTD's first week of live trading. Particular in light of how fierce that
USDJPY down move has been. As a bonus, QTD entered a long position in
EURGBP for a small 0.19% gain as illustrated below. My parameter were a
maximum of 0.25% risk per position. The gain could have been better if
it weren't for that 61% retracement. Not that I'm complaining as I
haven't even looked at the market this past couple of days while the
system is trading for me. USDJPY touched my threshold support price
80.70, my bullish sentiment needs to be reevaluated. NZDUSD just cracked
a higher high (marginally though), so I'm easing on the bear button for
now. EURGBP is testing some resistance to, so I'm not so eager to dive
in again. Overall, I've been 2/3 wrong. I've told you before that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/i-didnt-miss-a-boat-i-missed-a-freakin-rocket/"&gt;I'm
very bad at timing the market&lt;/a&gt;. That's why I developed QTD to trade
for me. Seeing that it's a long weekend, and I'll be way from town, I'm
just going to shut down my remote trade server in London until next week
when I can have some time to re-do my analysis. [caption
id="attachment_5361" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURGBP,
hourly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr-580x411.png" title="2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr-580x411.png" title="2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EUR"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="NZD"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Bullish USDJPY on week of April 17, 2011</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-17T21:50:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-04-17:bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have unofficially launched my Quantised Trading Desk (QTD) expert
system this weekend as the system is ready for live trading after almost
a year in development. You can't miss the announcement if you visit the
new frontpage of this blog. So, I won't talk about it anymore here. The
purpose of this post is to discuss my forex trade. It's been over 7
months since I've traded on the forex market. I have been working on QTD
during all these months to improve my overall trading. Anyway, let's
dive right to it for my first trade back into forex. I am bullish on the
U.S. dollar this week. Why? The Financial Times is letting on &lt;a href=""&gt;rumours
that the US Fed is signalling an end to quantitative easing&lt;/a&gt;.
Coincidentally, the U.S. dollar appears to be testing supports across
all major currencies. Secondly the US equities market hasn't been able
to make higher highs even as the dollar is marking new lows. Still, I'm
not one to call a bottom, nor am I hunting for one. This is merely a
good risk-reward trade to gun for an obvious move. In particular, USDJPY
appears to be the best of the bunch as its been holding well over the
past few months while the dollar crumbled. The fact that Europe and US
are rumoured to be lighting up on the money printing whereas Japan's
money printing press is on full steam for the quake reconstruction (Yen
bearish) is a decent excuse to place some chips on USDJPY. You might
have noticed, I haven't specified my entry price, amount, or stop loss
price as usual. This is because I am relying on the Quantised Trading
Desk expert system to trade USDJPY for me. QTD will monitor the market
for me and execute trade entries and exits as it sees fit to accumulate
a long position in USDJPY. All the risk management and quant analysis
are built into the system. So I don't have a position yet because I'm
waiting for QTD to do the grunt work. [caption id="attachment_5332"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USDJPY weekly
chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly-580x333.png" title="2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;http:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bcad7330-691a-11e0-9040-00144feab49a.html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly-580x333.png" title="2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Short 0.015 CADJPY @ 81.78, Stop 82.00</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/short-0015-cadjpy-8178-stop-8200/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-23T21:40:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-09-23:short-0015-cadjpy-8178-stop-8200/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Edit: I was stopped out overnight for a loss of 0.37%. I am taking a
dabble at shorting oil via CAD/JPY. Here are where things stand.
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CAD/JPY
"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-09-23-CADJPY.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570"
caption="USD/CAD"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-09-23-USDCAD.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-09-23-USDCAD.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Crude
Oil"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-09-23-CL.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-09-23-CL.png"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] CAD/JPY is forming a wedge on the 4 hour
chart. I am shorting it at resistance and in-line with the downtrend. A
break below 81.50 would signal a confirmation for even lower prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risk is about 0.4% of account with a CAD\$15,000 position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="JPY"></category></entry><entry><title>Lucky exit for CAD/JPY long yesterday, downtrend resumes now?</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/lucky-exit-for-cadjpy-long-yesterday-downtrend-resumes-now/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-22T22:33:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-22:lucky-exit-for-cadjpy-long-yesterday-downtrend-resumes-now/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-all-cadjpy-long-88-40-for-152-pips/"&gt;booked my profit on my CAD/JPY long&lt;/a&gt; last night mere pips away from
the top. It was a lucky move, that's all. Now it looks as though CAD/JPY
will do one of the following: &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break down from here. A break below 86.50 will confirm an
    intermediate term downtrend. However, I don't expect CAD/JPY to spin
    on a dime right after testing an obvious resistance. So I think #2
    is more likely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;False breakdown to above 86.50, retrace to 88.00, and hang around
    this range for a few more days then initiate an intermediate term
    price fall (#1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although unlikely, case #3 is still possible. CAD/JPY can remain
    suppressed at this 87 price level and creep upward deviously to test
    89.30.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between #1 and #2 could be subtle. But I couldn't bank
on either one yet because the reward/risk isn't favourable at this
moment. So I'm going to stay on the sideline and wait for a better price
or for the signs to be clearer. On another note, I'm still keeping an
eye on gold and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/AUD/"&gt;Aussie&lt;/a&gt;. There should be a big one soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CAD/JPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-22-cadjpy_d.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="market analysis"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed all CADJPY long @ 88.40 for +152 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-all-cadjpy-long-8840-for-152-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-21T19:39:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-21:paper-trade-closed-all-cadjpy-long-8840-for-152-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CAD/JPY reached my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-cadjpy-86-88-stop-86-10-target-88-0/"&gt;target of 88.00 last Friday&lt;/a&gt;. It broke through
88.00 nicely and tested 88.50 on Tokyo open just now. I decided to book
my profit in the demo account on this CAD/JPY long position entered at
86.88 and 87.87. See Figure 1 for the 3-hour chart with the entries and
exits marked. Main reason for my cold feet is that there's a lot of
resistance on CAD/JPY above 88.50, all the way to 90.70, from the daily
chart (not shown). I couldn't tell if CAD/JPY will continue pushing
upward or retrace. So I'm booking my profit now to observe the price
action from the sideline. This position has turned out +40 pips more
than I expected, so I'm trying not to be too greedy in this volatile
time. The net profit on this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper trade&lt;/a&gt; amounts to +0.3% of my demo
account. The yellow triangle in Figure 1 shows my exit. I risked 0.1% on
the initial entry (first blue triangle). Then added 70% more to the
position above a weak resistance level (second blue triangle) and moved
the stop on the initial size to breakeven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CAD/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-21-cadjpy_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Long CADJPY @ 86.88, Stop 86.10, Target 88.0</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-cadjpy-8688-stop-8610-target-880/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-17T21:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-17:paper-trade-long-cadjpy-8688-stop-8610-target-880/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I entered CADJPY long at market for 86.88 just now. This is a
continuation of my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-1-0540-for-131-pips/"&gt;previous USDCAD short&lt;/a&gt; position. However, USDJPY
is on a run upward so I'm switching to go long on the loonie with yen
instead. Figure 1 shows the daily chart of CADJPY. Notice the imminent
MACD bullish crossover and the already in-play stochastic upturn. I like
it. My stop loss level is set at 86.10. It's the high of a previous peak
on February 3, two weeks ago. My target is the round number 88
resistance. 88.0 has been an important price level for CADJPY for the
past few months. So I'm setting my sight there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CADJPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_d.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows my timing for this entry. CADJPY is noticeably meeting
some resistance at 87.50. 87.50 is also the 61.8% Fibonacci level of a
recent down move. This is a cause for concern on my long position as we
could very well retrace here. However, the bullishness of CADJPY is
apparent in Figure 2. Prices have consistently been bought for the past
few days right on the short term moving average (teal line).
Furthermore, the intermediate term moving average (orange line) is about
to cross the long term moving average (red line) as I enter this
position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, gold price has taken a dive from 1130 to 1100. Meanwhile, crude
oil price is holding the 77 support nicely. Thus, this confirm my
previous view that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-change-of-wind-for-australian-dollar-shorted-audusd-0-9183-and-audcad-0-9546/"&gt;oil has better upside than gold&lt;/a&gt; in the
intermediate term. Which is why I've been trading the loonie these past
weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this particular CADJPY trade, I have another buy order waiting above
current support level to add to my long position. Let's see if CADJPY
can break decisively to the upside in the next 24 hours as US and
Canadian data comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CADJPY,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_4h.gif" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_4h.gif"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: GBPJPY @ 145.24, Stop 144.70, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-28T21:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-28:paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I've switched over to long EURJPY @ 125.40 as EURGBP's
downtrend seem to be running out of steam. Moreover, EURJPY looks better
on the daily chart with a clear support and an oversold reading. I'm
back in my long GBPJPY play at 145.24. The currency pair is breaking an
hourly resistance since consolidating around 145. I had a low ball offer
at 144.20 since &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;taking my profit last night at 146.42&lt;/a&gt;. But that bid
for never filled. So I'm re-entering on a short-term breakout. For this
entry, I am risking 0.1% of my account. This re-entry is a tough
decision. Almost all the respectable pros that I &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/Quantisan"&gt;follow on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
are on the other side of this trade via other currency pairs. However,
my long setup is valid as long as GBPJPY is above 144 level. So I'll
take this trade until proven otherwise. Although I must admit that my
confidence in this trade is very low. I also considered long CADJPY
instead as it seems to offer more upside potential. However, as I've
been following the GBPJPY pair this week, I'll stick with my plan. I
also have a limit order to add more at 145.81 as you can see in Figure 1
below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-28-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed GBPJPY @ 146.42 for +140 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-27T22:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-27:paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just closed my GBPJPY long at 146.42 for around +140 pips average gain,
or 0.4% in the account balance. Damn good for a 24 hours holding. Obama
just finished his State of The Union address at the moment. I am not
impressed. Still all talk of change but nothing concrete yet. Anyway,
that's beside the point in this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trade log&lt;/a&gt;. 146.50 price level for
GBPJPY is the 10 day moving average. It has also been a strong support
back in late December. This should be a good resistance level. My guess
is that GBPJPY should stall, or even retrace, here for a while. Thus I'm
taking profit at this price as shown in Figure 1 (yellow triangle). I
still believe my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-144-24-stop-143-60-target-148/"&gt;bullish setup from yesterday&lt;/a&gt; is still good. So I'll
be watching this pair for a re-entry. Update: I re-entered at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-145-24-stop-144-70-target-148/"&gt;145.24
the next day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBPJPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-27-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper Trade: Long GBPJPY @ 144.24, Stop 143.60, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-26T22:33:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-26:paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My previous &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;short-side setup on GBP/JPY&lt;/a&gt; played out beautifully. Yet
I wasn't able to ride it down because I got stopped out on a stop-hunt
counter-move before the dive, see Fig. 1. Now that GBP/JPY has reached
its other end. I am betting for it to go reverse with a long position. I
expect this move to be more fierce with more upside potential as it's in
the direction of the long term up trend. Some people are calling the top
has been printed in the markets and the wind is now blowing the other
way. I am not one to guess what the market is about to do. So it's
business as usual until the trendline is broken. What I really like
about this setup is that GBP/JPY is testing a double trendline cross on
the weekly, Fig. 2. Secondly, the 3-hour chart of Figure 1 is showing a
RSI positive divergence on this test of the long term support. I am
quite confident of this setup. However, I am not confident about the
timing as GBP/JPY is known to be a wild horse and volatility could very
well stop me out, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;like last time&lt;/a&gt;. With
British preliminary GDP number coming out in about 6 hours, it might
have been wiser to wait until the after that to enter. On top of that,
the markets have been on a stall for the last few days waiting for data
in the next 48 hours. End-of-week volatility this week is expected to be
significant. Anyway, I've put in a position already and will just let it
run. This a small initial position with 0.1% of my account at risk. I
have also placed limit orders above resistances to add to this position.
We'll how this turns out soon enough. Lastly, even though I said I've
been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/barred-from-trading-at-work-a-curse-or-a-gift/"&gt;cut off from trading at my day job&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn't mean I'm
completely out of the game. I just have to adapt my manual trading
strategy while my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated system&lt;/a&gt; is still in development.
Basically meaning that I'll trade with a slower timeframe for
longer-term moves. All the better, as longer term moves are generally
less deceptive. Update: I closed this at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;146.42 for +140 pips gain&lt;/a&gt;
the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="GBP/JPY, weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry></feed>