<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/long_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-11-16T12:14:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Bought 200 LLL.TO @ 47.04, Stop 46.50</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-200-lllto-4704-stop-4650/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-16T12:14:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-11-16:bought-200-lllto-4704-stop-4650/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Market is tanking (Figure 1). Lots of pessimism in the news. Time for me
to load on some growth stocks. I'm passing the goldminers in this move
as the dollar seem to be rising from the dead and gold may be
consolidating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX, 12500 looks
like a fine support, doesn't it?"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-11-16-TSX.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I'm picking a growth stock, Lululemon (LLL.TO). Lululemon is
holding well in this down move. Furthermore, the intraday test of
support at 46.50 looks promising as there were few sellers at that price
level. The recent break above long-term resistance at 48 is good too. So
is the 19.6% short float... Anyway, you get the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Lululemon
(LLL.TO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-11-16-LLL.TO.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-11-16-LLL.TO.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Risk is (\$47.04 - \$46.50) * 200 =
\$108 + \$9.90 commission = \$117.9 = 1.2% of account. Update:
Woodshedder's post today explains &lt;a href="http://ibankcoin.com/woodshedderblog/2010/11/15/the-sky-is-falling/"&gt;his current view of the market&lt;/a&gt;,
which happens to coincide with mine at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="LLL.TO"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="RRSP"></category></entry><entry><title>Bought 300 VEN.TO @ 8.95, Stop 8.80</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-300-vento-895-stop-880/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-19T16:12:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-10-19:bought-300-vento-895-stop-880/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Update Oct 20: I raised my stop to 9.10 this moring. It got stopped out
2 minutes before the close for a small profit. Following the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-350-hgd-to-10-84-profit-2/"&gt;covering
of my short side play this morning&lt;/a&gt;, I sneaked back in to the gold bug
camp. In particular, I bought some of my recent favourite gold miner,
Ventana Gold Corp. (VEN.TO), a few minutes before the close. Gold held
on to the 1330 support as I've discussed this morning (see &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-350-hgd-to-10-84-profit-2/"&gt;gold chart
in this morning's post&lt;/a&gt;). I
also watched the closing 30 minutes of the market and VEN.TO respected
its 8.90 support level too. See Figure 1. There was a brief touch below
8.90 but it pushed back up quickly (not shown). This is a play inline
with the direction of the recent rally. Just riding the trend. Nothing
fancy. Hard stop is \$8.80. Mental stop is \$8.88. Maximum risk is
(\$8.95 - \$8.80) * 300 = \$45 + \$9.90 commission = \$54.90 = 0.5% of
account. There's a risk of another gap down open tomorrow. So my
position is small in case the market runs away overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Ventana Gold
Corp. (VEN.TO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-10-19-VEN.TO.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="gold"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="Mining"></category><category term="RRSP"></category><category term="VEN.TO"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed all CADJPY long @ 88.40 for +152 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-all-cadjpy-long-8840-for-152-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-21T19:39:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-21:paper-trade-closed-all-cadjpy-long-8840-for-152-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CAD/JPY reached my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-cadjpy-86-88-stop-86-10-target-88-0/"&gt;target of 88.00 last Friday&lt;/a&gt;. It broke through
88.00 nicely and tested 88.50 on Tokyo open just now. I decided to book
my profit in the demo account on this CAD/JPY long position entered at
86.88 and 87.87. See Figure 1 for the 3-hour chart with the entries and
exits marked. Main reason for my cold feet is that there's a lot of
resistance on CAD/JPY above 88.50, all the way to 90.70, from the daily
chart (not shown). I couldn't tell if CAD/JPY will continue pushing
upward or retrace. So I'm booking my profit now to observe the price
action from the sideline. This position has turned out +40 pips more
than I expected, so I'm trying not to be too greedy in this volatile
time. The net profit on this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper trade&lt;/a&gt; amounts to +0.3% of my demo
account. The yellow triangle in Figure 1 shows my exit. I risked 0.1% on
the initial entry (first blue triangle). Then added 70% more to the
position above a weak resistance level (second blue triangle) and moved
the stop on the initial size to breakeven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CAD/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-21-cadjpy_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Long CADJPY @ 86.88, Stop 86.10, Target 88.0</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-cadjpy-8688-stop-8610-target-880/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-17T21:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-17:paper-trade-long-cadjpy-8688-stop-8610-target-880/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I entered CADJPY long at market for 86.88 just now. This is a
continuation of my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-1-0540-for-131-pips/"&gt;previous USDCAD short&lt;/a&gt; position. However, USDJPY
is on a run upward so I'm switching to go long on the loonie with yen
instead. Figure 1 shows the daily chart of CADJPY. Notice the imminent
MACD bullish crossover and the already in-play stochastic upturn. I like
it. My stop loss level is set at 86.10. It's the high of a previous peak
on February 3, two weeks ago. My target is the round number 88
resistance. 88.0 has been an important price level for CADJPY for the
past few months. So I'm setting my sight there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CADJPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_d.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows my timing for this entry. CADJPY is noticeably meeting
some resistance at 87.50. 87.50 is also the 61.8% Fibonacci level of a
recent down move. This is a cause for concern on my long position as we
could very well retrace here. However, the bullishness of CADJPY is
apparent in Figure 2. Prices have consistently been bought for the past
few days right on the short term moving average (teal line).
Furthermore, the intermediate term moving average (orange line) is about
to cross the long term moving average (red line) as I enter this
position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, gold price has taken a dive from 1130 to 1100. Meanwhile, crude
oil price is holding the 77 support nicely. Thus, this confirm my
previous view that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-change-of-wind-for-australian-dollar-shorted-audusd-0-9183-and-audcad-0-9546/"&gt;oil has better upside than gold&lt;/a&gt; in the
intermediate term. Which is why I've been trading the loonie these past
weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this particular CADJPY trade, I have another buy order waiting above
current support level to add to my long position. Let's see if CADJPY
can break decisively to the upside in the next 24 hours as US and
Canadian data comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CADJPY,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_4h.gif" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_4h.gif"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: GBPJPY @ 145.24, Stop 144.70, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-28T21:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-28:paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I've switched over to long EURJPY @ 125.40 as EURGBP's
downtrend seem to be running out of steam. Moreover, EURJPY looks better
on the daily chart with a clear support and an oversold reading. I'm
back in my long GBPJPY play at 145.24. The currency pair is breaking an
hourly resistance since consolidating around 145. I had a low ball offer
at 144.20 since &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;taking my profit last night at 146.42&lt;/a&gt;. But that bid
for never filled. So I'm re-entering on a short-term breakout. For this
entry, I am risking 0.1% of my account. This re-entry is a tough
decision. Almost all the respectable pros that I &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/Quantisan"&gt;follow on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
are on the other side of this trade via other currency pairs. However,
my long setup is valid as long as GBPJPY is above 144 level. So I'll
take this trade until proven otherwise. Although I must admit that my
confidence in this trade is very low. I also considered long CADJPY
instead as it seems to offer more upside potential. However, as I've
been following the GBPJPY pair this week, I'll stick with my plan. I
also have a limit order to add more at 145.81 as you can see in Figure 1
below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-28-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed GBPJPY @ 146.42 for +140 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-27T22:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-27:paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just closed my GBPJPY long at 146.42 for around +140 pips average gain,
or 0.4% in the account balance. Damn good for a 24 hours holding. Obama
just finished his State of The Union address at the moment. I am not
impressed. Still all talk of change but nothing concrete yet. Anyway,
that's beside the point in this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trade log&lt;/a&gt;. 146.50 price level for
GBPJPY is the 10 day moving average. It has also been a strong support
back in late December. This should be a good resistance level. My guess
is that GBPJPY should stall, or even retrace, here for a while. Thus I'm
taking profit at this price as shown in Figure 1 (yellow triangle). I
still believe my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-144-24-stop-143-60-target-148/"&gt;bullish setup from yesterday&lt;/a&gt; is still good. So I'll
be watching this pair for a re-entry. Update: I re-entered at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-145-24-stop-144-70-target-148/"&gt;145.24
the next day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBPJPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-27-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper Trade: Long GBPJPY @ 144.24, Stop 143.60, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-26T22:33:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-26:paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My previous &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;short-side setup on GBP/JPY&lt;/a&gt; played out beautifully. Yet
I wasn't able to ride it down because I got stopped out on a stop-hunt
counter-move before the dive, see Fig. 1. Now that GBP/JPY has reached
its other end. I am betting for it to go reverse with a long position. I
expect this move to be more fierce with more upside potential as it's in
the direction of the long term up trend. Some people are calling the top
has been printed in the markets and the wind is now blowing the other
way. I am not one to guess what the market is about to do. So it's
business as usual until the trendline is broken. What I really like
about this setup is that GBP/JPY is testing a double trendline cross on
the weekly, Fig. 2. Secondly, the 3-hour chart of Figure 1 is showing a
RSI positive divergence on this test of the long term support. I am
quite confident of this setup. However, I am not confident about the
timing as GBP/JPY is known to be a wild horse and volatility could very
well stop me out, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;like last time&lt;/a&gt;. With
British preliminary GDP number coming out in about 6 hours, it might
have been wiser to wait until the after that to enter. On top of that,
the markets have been on a stall for the last few days waiting for data
in the next 48 hours. End-of-week volatility this week is expected to be
significant. Anyway, I've put in a position already and will just let it
run. This a small initial position with 0.1% of my account at risk. I
have also placed limit orders above resistances to add to this position.
We'll how this turns out soon enough. Lastly, even though I said I've
been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/barred-from-trading-at-work-a-curse-or-a-gift/"&gt;cut off from trading at my day job&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn't mean I'm
completely out of the game. I just have to adapt my manual trading
strategy while my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated system&lt;/a&gt; is still in development.
Basically meaning that I'll trade with a slower timeframe for
longer-term moves. All the better, as longer term moves are generally
less deceptive. Update: I closed this at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;146.42 for +140 pips gain&lt;/a&gt;
the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="GBP/JPY, weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>EUR/USD +95 pips in 2 hours: An example of swing and day trade convergence</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/eurusd-95-pips-in-2-hours-an-example-of-swing-and-day-trade-convergence/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-29T16:42:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-29:eurusd-95-pips-in-2-hours-an-example-of-swing-and-day-trade-convergence/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had my best day-trading day this quarter on November 27. I made 95
pips in two hours at the open with only two trades. This post is a
review of my trades that day for my future reference. To save you and
myself from reading, the two reasons for this good run are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convergence of intermediate term signals with day trading signals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring my bearish sentiment (Dubai news) and traded what I saw
    from the prices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before moving on, let's start by setting the stage with some background
information to summarize what conditions were like that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The news on November 25 after NY close of &lt;a href="http://www.marketwatch.com/story/dollar-and-yen-buoyed-by-safe-haven-flows-2009-11-27"&gt;Dubai World delaying their
debt repayments&lt;/a&gt; sent the dollar and yen soaring. I made &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/audjpy-short-81-3777-17-anatomy-of-my-first-400-pips-trade/"&gt;my first
400+ pips trade&lt;/a&gt; by being at the right place and time on this panic
wave. The U.S. market was closed that day but FTSE sold off more than 3%
the day after the news. So the expectation was for US to do a catch-up
sell off when it opens again on Friday 27th. Risk aversion (equities
down, yen and dollar up) was the talk of the day. Figure 1 below shows
the charts of ES futures (e-mini S&amp;amp;P500). Left is a 1-min. from midnight
of 27th to that morning's NYSE opening. Right is an hourly showing the
move overnight from 26th to 27th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="ES Futures
(e-mini S&amp;amp;P 500)"][&lt;img alt="ES Futures (e-mini S&amp;amp;P 500)" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-29-ES.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-29-ES.png"&gt;ES Futures (e-mini
S&amp;amp;P 500)&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Intermediate term signal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows my intermediate term signal. EURUSD has been printing an
uptrend on the daily (not shown). Figure 2 shows that EURUSD was testing
the bottom of my channel so I should consider going long. Notice that
this is the same channel that called for the 1.5150 top on 25th. At
least it has proven itself useful once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURUSD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="EURUSD, 3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-27-EURUSD_3h.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-27-EURUSD_3h.png"&gt;EURUSD, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Short term signals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the short term signal, we need to go back to Figure 1 for the ES
charts. ES tanked 40 points over the holiday with very low volume. It
made it all the way to 1067 just before 3am on 27th. Then it lifted all
the way to 1080 at 9am. 1080 is the line in the sand for the bulls and
bears. So retracing all the way to that level before opening is
significant. This pre-open strength in ES was the sign of oversold for
me. This is the short-term confirmation I needed. I entered my first
position to long EURUSD @ 9:09 am to test the water. Then I watched both
EURUSD and ES closely for the next half hour. Once NYSE opened. I
noticed that the TICK was relatively mellow with readings around -250 to
-500. It's unusually good for a -20 points open drop on S&amp;amp;P 500. One
would expect at least -800 readings for a strong negative sentiment. So
after watching EURUSD, ES, and TICK for about 10 minutes, I entered a
second position on a weak retracement at 9:39 am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The exits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my exit, I took profit at 1.5180 because it's the 50% Fibonacci
level and it's also the top of another of my channel (Figures 2 and 3).
After about 10 minutes of watching the 1M bars, EURUSD failed to clear
that resistance, so I took profit on the second half to go flat in this
pair just before 11 am because it's an early-closing Friday (NYSE
closing at 1pm). The gains were +95 and +93 pips for +0.27% and +0.28%
in my demo account total. Not bad for holding for 2 hours. Update:
Thanks to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jlcnuke"&gt;Jeff on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for the question. I updated Figure 3 with
the Fib. levels and showed the top and bottom used to draw it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURUSD, 30
min."][&lt;img alt="EURUSD, 30 min." src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-27-EURUSD_30min.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-27-EURUSD_30min.png"&gt;EURUSD, 30 min.&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, I started with an intermediate term setup that aligns with
the major trend. I observed the reaction of the markets on an important
news. Identified an oversold condition from the short-term charts for a
short-term positive divergence signal. Scaled in a position. Then added
more with another confirmation. I scaled out when the target was hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recommendation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, I could have been more aggressive on this trade. As shown in
Figure 3, 1.4920-4930 was a short-term resistance. I could have added
more to my position when that level broke, with a stop at 1.4900.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="day trading"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="good trade"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Long AUD/JPY @ 81.22, SL 80.99, TP 82.50</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-audjpy-8122-sl-8099-tp-8250/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-19T10:49:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-19:paper-trade-long-audjpy-8122-sl-8099-tp-8250/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several major pairs are testing their support on this market correction
with a 20 points drop in the S&amp;amp;P500 before 10 am. This is a short term
capitulation scenario. From looking at the major pairs, the long term
trend still seem to be intact. In particular, I am interested in
shorting Yen because I'm seeing &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC setups&lt;/a&gt; across the board in JPY
crosses. I compared AUD/JPY, CAD/JPY, EUR/JPY, GBP/JPY, and USD/JPY
pairs to decide which one to go long with. Seeing that I already have a
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-1-0122-sl-1-0060-tp-1-0225/"&gt;USD/CHF long position&lt;/a&gt;, USD/JPY is out. Then EUR/JPY is out too
because of recent Euro weakness from my observations of intraday price
actions. I haven't had much luck with British Pounds, so GBP/JPY is out
too. That leaves me with my two favourites, CAD/JPY and AUD/JPY. So I
checked with USD/CAD and AUD/USD charts to see which has better
support/resistance. USD/CAD has a lot of resistance above 1.06, so going
with CAD/JPY long seem like to be less risky. However, from looking at
the 3-hour chart, I changed my mind to go with AUD/JPY long because it
is showing a positive divergence there. From the daily chart of AUD/JPY
shown in Figure 1, we can see that the up-trend is losing steam. The
price action is expected to be choppy. Long term condition, up and
choppy. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="AUD/JPY"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY.png"&gt;AUD/JPY&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Figure 2 shows the
3-hour chart of AUD/JPY, this is where things get more clear. Notice
that AUD/JPY is testing the lower fChannel the third time in a month
with the lowest RSI. This is a clear positive divergence. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY,
3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY_3h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY_3h.PNG"&gt;AUD/JPY, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] However, the strong short-term
down move is making this long entry very dangerous. Thus, I am using the
NYSE intraday sentiment (Fig. 3) to pin point my entry. Notice the
extreme negative open and then the intraday positive divergence as shown
by the S&amp;amp;P500 and TICK. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="NYSE intraday sentiment"][&lt;img alt="NYSE intraday sentiment" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-intraday.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-intraday.PNG"&gt;NYSE
intraday sentiment&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] As part of my analysis for this trade, I
compared the current scenario with earlier this month. Figure 4 is the
hourly chart of AUD/JPY when I entered this trade. Figure 5 is the
hourly chart of AUD/JPY from Nov 1st - 4th, when AUD/JPY last tested the
lower fChannel. I noticed that AUD/JPY had a tendency to break below my
fChannel by about 50 pips before reversing. With the fChannel at 81.80
today, AUD/JPY should fall to 81.30. I watched that level closely this
morning and timed my entry with the intraday sentiment as described
above. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY,
1-hour"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY, 1-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY_1h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-19-AUDJPY_1h.PNG"&gt;AUD/JPY, 1-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="AUD/JPY November 1st-4th,
1-hour"][&lt;img alt="AUD/JPY November 1st-4th, 1-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-04-AUDJPY_1h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-04-AUDJPY_1h.PNG"&gt;AUD/JPY November
1st-4th, 1-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Position size: 100% Entry: 81.22, entered
based on intraday sentiment. Stop: 80.99, below round number support.
Target: 82.50, previous congestion and near top of channel. Reward /
Risk = 128 / 23 = 5.57 &gt; 3. A risky trade with great potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="AUD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Long USD/CHF @ 1.0122, SL 1.0060, TP 1.0225</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-10122-sl-10060-tp-10225/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-18T21:22:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-18:paper-trade-long-usdchf-10122-sl-10060-tp-10225/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seeing that this is my first commitment after the big drawdown, I'll
bring back my tradition of writing a post to log my rationale and market
conditions on this entry for later review. I sifted through the weekly
charts of all pairs on my watch-list tonight and found that USD/CHF long
is the most promising. Figure 1 shows my daily chart for the setup and
Figure 2 is a 3-hour chart with my entry timing. Let's talk about Figure
1 first. USD/CHF is making a triple bottom with a positive divergence as
shown. I have also marked the current major support at 1.0010. USD/CHF
has trade below it for about a week now but failed to break any lower.
Today is the first day when we've opened somewhat above it. Secondly,
note that we have broken above a descending channel as shown in Figure
1. USD/CHF has also tested the 1.0010 support twice already at both
sides of that channel. And accompanied with a positive divergence as I
said. The major caution as shown in Figure 1 is that we're still trading
below the 10-day ma. As for the entry timing, observe Figure 2. Notice
that USD/CHF just made a higher low outside and above the descending
fChannel (the two thicker brown lines). This is the signal for entry.
Note that the fChannel is my proprietary channel. This trade is
initiated according to my new Forex Trend Fading (FTF) setup. Position
size: &lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;,
50%&lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt; Entry: 1.0122,
from fRays signal. Stop: 1.0060, below major support Target: 1.0225,
first major resistance, ease off some at that point, add more above it.
Reward / Risk = 103 / 62 = 1.66 \&amp;lt; 3. Not not good enough for my usual
R/R target, but I've been considering lowering it to 1.5. So lets see if
an R/R of 1.5 is a good enough number. I would have been more
comfortable with a 2.0 though. Anyway, let's see how this goes. Update:
I took half of it off at breakeven because of the lower R/R and the new
setup. Only 50% in this trade now. I'm looking to add a EUR or JPY cross
for my other half allocation. Update 11/19: I'm stopped out of this
position @ 1.0150 for +27 pips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580"
caption="USD/CHF"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF.png"&gt;USD/CHF&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USD/CHF, 3-hour"][&lt;img alt="USD/CHF,
3-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF_3h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-USDCHF_3h.PNG"&gt;USD/CHF, 3-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CHF"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTB"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry></feed>