<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/market-analysis_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-10-14T12:20:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Canadian VIX: TSX to have their own volatility index</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/canadian-vix-tsx-to-have-their-own-volatility-index/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-14T12:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-10-14:canadian-vix-tsx-to-have-their-own-volatility-index/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't know if anyone noticed, but in my previous post &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/three-obvious-reasons-to-watch-13000-on-the-tsx/"&gt;discussing the
TSX&lt;/a&gt;, I included a chart of VIX (S&amp;amp;P500 volatility index) versus S&amp;amp;P
500. VIX is one of the market indicators that I can't live without.
However, as much as the Canadian and the American equity markets are
correlated, they are still separate markets. So using the VIX vs. S&amp;amp;P500
on an analysis of the TSX is like borrowing salt from thy neighbour. But
there's no more need for that soon as TSX is finally getting its own
volatility index starting Monday (October 18)! This is to replace the MX
Implied Volatility Index (MVX) from the Montreal Exchange, which I
didn't have access to previously (aside from &lt;a href="http://www.m-x.ca/indicesmx_mvx_en.php"&gt;data published on their
website&lt;/a&gt;). One question I have is that the TSX VIX will be based on
TSX 60 index options activity according on their &lt;a href="http://www.standardandpoors.com/servlet/BlobServer?blobheadername3=MDT-Type&amp;amp;blobcol=urldata&amp;amp;blobtable=MungoBlobs&amp;amp;blobheadervalue2=inline%3B+filename%3D20101014_TSX-60-VIX_Volatility-Launch.pdf&amp;amp;blobheadername2=Content-Disposition&amp;amp;blobheadervalue1=application%2Fpdf&amp;amp;blobkey=id&amp;amp;blobheadername1=content-type&amp;amp;blobwhere=1243766536405&amp;amp;blobheadervalue3=UTF-8"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;, but
the TSX 60 index options isn't that active. So would the TSX VIX be as
efficient as the S&amp;amp;P500 VIX? An opportunity with the introduction of TSX
VIX on the Toronto Exchange is that I can now place bets on market
volatility in my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/ranking-investment-options-for-my-self-directed-rrsp/"&gt;self-directed RRSP trading account&lt;/a&gt;. Which is
arguably more predictable than the underlying index these days... In any
case, this will be a vital market indicator for Canadian market traders.
For more information on TSX VIX, see the &lt;a href="http://www.standardandpoors.com/indices/sp-tsx-60-vix/en/us/?indexId=sp-tsx-60-vix"&gt;product information page on
Standard &amp;amp; Poor's&lt;/a&gt;. And a hat tip to &lt;a href="http://optionmatters.ca/"&gt;Option Matters&lt;/a&gt; (Montreal
Exchange's blog on options) for this news.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="indicator"></category><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="VIXC.TO"></category></entry><entry><title>Three obvious reasons to watch 13,000 on the TSX</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/three-obvious-reasons-to-watch-13000-on-the-tsx/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-13T14:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-10-13:three-obvious-reasons-to-watch-13000-on-the-tsx/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Talks of QE2 (WSJ: &lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/source/2010/10/13/qe2-or-titanic/"&gt;QE2 or Titanic&lt;/a&gt; and Econbrowser: &lt;a href="http://www.econbrowser.com/archives/2010/10/why_is_the_fed.html"&gt;Why is the Fed
doing this?&lt;/a&gt;) and earnings season are pushing the market higher and
higher. Gold is still pushing to new all time high and the dollar is
breaking to new lows. The TSX, in particular, is testing 12,700 today.
13,000 is just around the corner. 13,000 price level is the line in the
sand for the commodity-heavy TSX for three obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It marks the breakdown support level back in the 2008 crash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the bottom of a prolonged congestion zone in much of 2007 and
    2008 before that crash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And most importantly, #1 and #2 are very easy to spot on the chart
    (potentially self-fulfilling).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is likely that the TSX will be reaching 13,000 shortly in this
earnings season. However, what happens afterward is anyone's guess. At
this point, I am neither long or short for the long term. The
reward/risk isn't good for going long at this point with that much
uncertainty. And the threat of QE2 and earnings release isn't good for
going short either. I am watching the forex market closely for signs of
a direction as that is a driver of the equity market these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="S&amp;amp;P
TSX"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-10-13-TSX.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570"
caption="CBOE Market Volatility Index (VIX) vs. inverse
S&amp;amp;P500"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-10-13-VIX.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-10-13-VIX.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>To hell and back? A review of TSX after a V-day</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/to-hell-and-back-a-review-of-tsx-after-a-v-day/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-06T20:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-05-06:to-hell-and-back-a-review-of-tsx-after-a-v-day/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As every trader knows already, the Dow tanked 1,000 points (about 9%) in
like 15 minutes today. But what's more amazing is that all the indices
made their way back just as quickly. Figure 1 below is today's chart of
TSX Composite (blue) and S&amp;amp;P 500 (red). So what does this mean for TSX?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-05-06-TSX-SPX.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="TSX Composite and S&amp;amp;P 500" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-05-06-TSX-SPX.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Let's zoom
out to take a look at the big picture. Figure 2 is a weekly chart of
TSX. The top indicator is the percentage of TSX traded issues above
their 200 day moving average. The overlay indicator is the percentage of
TSX traded issues above their 50 day moving average. The lower indicator
is the percentage of issues above 200 MA divided by the percentage above
their 50 MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX
Composite"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-05-06-TSX-200-50.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TSX index is an aggregate of prices from a handful of companies. But
there are over three thousand issues trading on the TSX. This view of
Figure 2 provides another perspective of where the market stands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question to be answered is this, how much technical damage did
today's sell-off produce?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, both the 200 and 50 numbers are at their respective
support after the close. This is as low as we have been in the past 9
months or so. However, they are still hanging high above according to
the 200 percentage. There are still 56.5% of companies above their 200
day moving average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the shorter term though, the 50 number is pretty low at 30%. Only 30%
of companies are above their 50 day moving average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referring to the historical pattern as shown on Figure 2. Typically
numbers 30 or below means that the down move is exhausting. Since most
(70%) companies are trading low already, so there's not much room for
big dives until the market can reload. It is interesting that we touched
30% this week yet the TSX index is still not down that much in the big
picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, I am still bearish on the market in the long run.
But I don't think today's move is the beginning of &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; dive. Since
volatility has contracted to a recent record low, this move is just a
shake-out of the bulls. Is this the end of this down move? I don't know.
But I expect to see at least an opposite shake-out of the bears soon
before any real move can materialize. Control your risks in expectation
of big ups and downs in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's just too good to be true for the bears that the market makes a
U-turn and head straight down after congesting below a support level for
weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my trading, I'm all cash today. So it was fun to watch the
move with no strings attached. I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-12-cve-to-puts-2-90-mark-27-50-10-gain/"&gt;covered my CVE.TO shorts yesterday&lt;/a&gt;
at a decent price. CVE.TO broke down further today during the panic but
ended up closing slightly higher. So my exit was good as I couldn't have
covered during that rapid breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Mish offers &lt;a href="http://globaleconomicanalysis.blogspot.com/2010/05/trader-error.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+MishsGlobalEconomicTrendAnalysis+%28Mish%27s+Global+Economic+Trend+Analysis%29"&gt;a good brief on today's extraordinary move&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>Lucky exit for CAD/JPY long yesterday, downtrend resumes now?</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/lucky-exit-for-cadjpy-long-yesterday-downtrend-resumes-now/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-22T22:33:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-22:lucky-exit-for-cadjpy-long-yesterday-downtrend-resumes-now/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-all-cadjpy-long-88-40-for-152-pips/"&gt;booked my profit on my CAD/JPY long&lt;/a&gt; last night mere pips away from
the top. It was a lucky move, that's all. Now it looks as though CAD/JPY
will do one of the following: &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break down from here. A break below 86.50 will confirm an
    intermediate term downtrend. However, I don't expect CAD/JPY to spin
    on a dime right after testing an obvious resistance. So I think #2
    is more likely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;False breakdown to above 86.50, retrace to 88.00, and hang around
    this range for a few more days then initiate an intermediate term
    price fall (#1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although unlikely, case #3 is still possible. CAD/JPY can remain
    suppressed at this 87 price level and creep upward deviously to test
    89.30.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between #1 and #2 could be subtle. But I couldn't bank
on either one yet because the reward/risk isn't favourable at this
moment. So I'm going to stay on the sideline and wait for a better price
or for the signs to be clearer. On another note, I'm still keeping an
eye on gold and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/AUD/"&gt;Aussie&lt;/a&gt;. There should be a big one soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CAD/JPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-22-cadjpy_d.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="market analysis"></category></entry><entry><title>On reactive trading and why I don't make market forecasts anymore</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/on-reactive-trading-and-why-i-dont-make-market-forecasts-anymore/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-17T08:54:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-17:on-reactive-trading-and-why-i-dont-make-market-forecasts-anymore/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that the popular trading blogs have one thing in common.
They all make some form of forecasts about the market, or even better,
calling out to a particular stock or currency pair. My guess is that
there's a lot more people looking for trading ideas for quick profits
than actually interested in the mundane mechanics of trading. Well, that
and because of the fact that some of these blogs are written by
respectable professionals that do provide good insights (my
recommendations are linked to in my blogroll, near bottom of the sidebar
to the right). I used to publish my predictions on the market on a
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/weekly-review/"&gt;frequent basis&lt;/a&gt;. It was my way of taking notes and keeping record for
the week or month. Ever since my embarrassing, and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/4-errors-lessons-being-long-just-before-the-october-2008-crash/"&gt;costly&lt;/a&gt;, attempt
to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-sign-this-financial-bloodbath-is-ending-soon/"&gt;call for the bottom in October 2008,&lt;/a&gt; I have learned to keep my
views to myself for the following reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suck at forecasting, terribly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wouldn't want anyone to trade on my guesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are plenty of other, much wiser, traders posting their views
    online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I changed my strategy by trading on reactions and not predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point #4 is what I'd like to discuss in this post. The main problem I
have with making forecasts is that I get stuck to one perspective. Say
if after a weekend analyzing session, I conclude that the market is up
for next week. I would keep looking for opportunities to go long in the
market the following week. That works well if I am right. Yet, as I
always say, I am wrong just as often as anyone. So the chance of success
is at best 50-50. On an equal chance that if I am wrong. I lose not once
but twice. First from being in the wrong side of the price move. Second
from missing that opposite and correct move. As such, I have since
adapted to a reactive &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;trading strategy&lt;/a&gt; rather than a predictive one.
Essentially, I analyze the markets to come up with conditions for
different scenarios (usually just three cases: up, down, and no idea)
that will play out. For example, if &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-145-24-stop-144-70-target-148/"&gt;GBP/JPY is above 144.50, I go
long&lt;/a&gt;. One of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/"&gt;trading skills&lt;/a&gt; I am still struggling to execute
consistently is to be deliberately one step slower than most people on
entering a trade. Being reactive is simplistically being a step slower
than everyone to ride an obvious setup. It goes like this ideally. When
the writings are on the wall and more aggressive traders have taken
their position, I wait even more. Then once those trades are still left
standing (i.e. not stopped out), that's when I would strike. On the
other hand, if the signs are not clear as crystal, I need to have the
discipline to step to the sideline. This strategy has been very useful
to me as I have recorded some &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/good-trade/"&gt;good trades&lt;/a&gt; because of it. My ideal
strategy certainly is less glamourous than a buy low, sell high motto.
Yet, having been through a few too many ups and downs in my account over
the years, I have learned to appreciate the art of not gunning for every
penny out there but aiming to keep every penny in my pocket. Much like
how you would survive in a battle, the secret is to not be the first one
out the line and then only go for the easy kills. Cowardly, yes. But
unlike war, being brave in trading does not earn you any medal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="reactive trading"></category></entry><entry><title>How Goldman Sachs Robbed You and Me of $3 Billions in 3 Months</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-goldman-sachs-robbed-you-and-me-of-3-billions-in-3-months/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-17T10:54:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-17:how-goldman-sachs-robbed-you-and-me-of-3-billions-in-3-months/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After watching the videos below, and from months of observation of this
latest global financial debacle, I am suddenly awashed with a feeling of
hopelessly powerless to this gross unfairness. In which the average,
hard working citizens are pouring money into the pockets of the filthy
and uber rich. If you don't know what I'm talking about here, watch the
video attached below for the tip of the ice berg in this on-going
problem. While Goldman is arguably the best at "legalized stealing" from
the moms and pops, they aren't the only crook on the block. Governments
around the world (not just the U.S.) were handing out money publicly
left and right in the past few months. And many still are. The whole
system is rigged as &lt;a href="http://www.caracommunity.com"&gt;Bill Cara&lt;/a&gt; has opined countless times in the last
few years. Bill's ingenious move to relocate his operation to the
Bahamas is only starting to shine in these months (to me). In addition
to voting with your ballot (which is useless if the whole system is
rigged), we can vote with our tax money by relocating our financial
operation. However, for those of us that still rely on a day job, this
is not an option. The best I can do right now is to become adequate with
managing our own money instead of depending on the financial salesmen.
This doesn't seem enough for me as the balance of power appears to be
getting worse by the day. Our government grossly tax us on one hand and
hand them out to the rich and well connected in the other. What have
others done/plan to do with regard to this unfair trap us working bees
are stuck in? The first video is Ratigan explaining how Goldman Sachs
made \$3 billions in 3 months (tipped by Stop Investing blog). The
second video is an interview with Michael Moore and Ratigan about where
all these loots are going now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;iframe height="339" width="425" src="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/22425001/vp/33346455#33346455" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

Visit msnbc.com for [Breaking News][], [World News][], and [News about
the Economy][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;iframe height="339" width="425" src="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/22425001/vp/33323945#33323945" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

Visit msnbc.com for [Breaking News][], [World News][], and [News about
the Economy][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="GS"></category><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="tax"></category></entry><entry><title>Inter-market analysis after a new 2009 high in the equity market</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/inter-market-analysis-after-a-new-2009-high-in-the-equity-market/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-08-22T18:45:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-08-22:inter-market-analysis-after-a-new-2009-high-in-the-equity-market/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The market made a new high for the year on Friday. There's no doubt that
the current trend is very bullish with the recent relentless climb since
March. See Figure 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, why was 1025 on the S&amp;amp;P500 (for example) so hard to break?
Since the market doesn't operate in a vacuum. Here's a look at S&amp;amp;P500
ETF (SPY) v. the U.S. dollar (Figure 2) and v. Gold (Figure 3) for some
insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To invest in the U.S. market is a bet on the U.S. market (well
obviously) as well as the U.S. dollar. Because we're trading with U.S.
dollar in the U.S. market, its fluctuation will affect your return too.
Figure 2 is a chart of SPY divided by the U.S. dollar index (an
aggregate of the U.S. dollar v. other major currencies). In effect, it's
a normalized SPY chart with regards to the global currencies (and thus,
more or less the economies). As you can see, we just broke through a
long term resistance at 1.30 but is testing a Fibonacci level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the value of Gold is often used as a metric for currencies.
i.e. how much money is actually worth. Figure 3 is a chart of SPY
divided by the price of Gold. In effect, a normalized SPY chart with
regards to the real value of the U.S. dollar (since price of Gold is in
U.S. dollar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 is more telling. Although we've been moving higher and higher
in the raw SPY, you can clearly see that SPY/\$GOLD has been hitting a
ceiling since July. In other words, the market is going up because the
value of U.S. dollar is going down versus the companies these equities
represent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there's been much &lt;a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/32506152/ns/business-stocks_and_economy/"&gt;talk of economic recovery&lt;/a&gt; and a new &lt;a href="http://online.barrons.com/article/SB125089288451150335.html"&gt;bull
market&lt;/a&gt; is already with us, I still am not convinced just yet. True,
the bears might be MIA. But all signs say that this bull we're seeing is
standing on thin ice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1711" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-21-spy.png" title="2009-08-21-SPY" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1712" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="SPY (S&amp;amp;P500 ETF) / \$USD (US Dollar Index)"][&lt;img alt="SPY (S&amp;amp;P500 ETF)
/ \$USD (US Dollar Index)" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009_08_21_spy-usd.png" title="2009_08_21_SPY-USD" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1714" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="SPY (S&amp;amp;P500 ETF) / Gold"][&lt;img alt="SPY (S&amp;amp;P500 ETF) /
Gold" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009_08_22_spy-gold.png" title="2009_08_22_SPY-GOLD" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-21-spy.png" title="2009-08-21-SPY" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-21-spy.png
  [&lt;img alt="SPY (S&amp;amp;P500 ETF) / \$USD (US Dollar Index)" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009_08_21_spy-usd.png" title="2009_08_21_SPY-USD" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009_08_21_spy-usd.png
  [&lt;img alt="SPY (S&amp;amp;P500 ETF) / Gold" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009_08_22_spy-gold.png" title="2009_08_22_SPY-GOLD" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009_08_22_spy-gold.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category></entry><entry><title>A technical analysis of 80 years of S&amp;P500</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-technical-analysis-of-80-years-of-sp500/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-08-07T14:43:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-08-07:a-technical-analysis-of-80-years-of-sp500/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the earlier popular post on this site is my view on the
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tested-the-pre-2000-tech-bubble-14-year-old-trendline-last-week/"&gt;pre-tech-bubble trendline from before year 2000&lt;/a&gt;. However, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/20-year-sp-500-trendline-actually-broken-months-ago/"&gt;that
trendline was broken in October 2008&lt;/a&gt; as I've noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the recent actions in the market has often been compared with the
Great Depression, I've decided to chart S&amp;amp;P500 all the way back to that
era. See the monthly chart of Figure 1 below from 1928 to today for the
S&amp;amp;P500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1677" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 Index"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 Index" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-07-spx.png" title="2009-08-07-SPX" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, as evident in Figure 1, the market dropped a lot more in
1929-1932 than what we've been seeing in 2008-2009 so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, notice the channel bounded by the two outer white lines? The
channel drawn have been bounding the market pretty well. Moreover, if we
compare the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_recessions_in_the_United_States"&gt;list of recessions in the U.S.&lt;/a&gt;with Figure 1, you can see
that as a rule of thumb, the economy is in boom if the market is in the
upper half of the channel, and the economy is struggling if the market
is in the lower half of the channel. The middle white line marks the
middle of the channel for easier observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the above, the follow years are in the upper range, with some
rounding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1932-1940, 8 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1954-1973, 19 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1986-2008, 22 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and the follow years are in the lower range:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1940-1954, 14 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1973-1986, 13 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2008-????&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my knowledge on modern history is abysmal, I can't comment on what
happened in these eras to verify this superficial categorization. This
is certainly worth further researching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Thirdly, and this one is a positive remark, is that the RSI has only
gone below 25 three times in the last 80 years, and the two times that
it occurred in the past (1932, 1974), it is when the market/economy has
reached a major bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, zooming to the current few years in Figure 2. You can see that
we've managed to push above the 200 month moving average this month.
That isn't much on its own, the challenge now is to see if we can stay
above it (1000 on the S&amp;amp;P500) by end of August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1678" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 Index"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 Index" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-07-spx_zoom.png" title="2009-08-07-SPX_zoom" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 Index" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-07-spx.png" title="2009-08-07-SPX" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-07-spx.png
  [&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 Index" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-07-spx_zoom.png" title="2009-08-07-SPX_zoom" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/08/2009-08-07-spx_zoom.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category></entry><entry><title>Weekly Market Review: July 24, 2009</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/weekly-market-review-july-24-2009/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-07-24T15:35:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-07-24:weekly-market-review-july-24-2009/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After touching the neckline on the head &amp;amp; shoulder formation last week,
the market has been steaming upward at an unstoppable pace. Retracements
have been shallow throughout this upward climb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're now testing 980 and the market just closed a hair beneath it on
Friday. Today's (Friday) volume has been intriguingly low. However, it
bears remarkable resemblance to last Friday's action wherein we were
also testing a significant resistance (950) on both Thursday and Friday
and then the Friday closed near the top but with very little volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the lackluster retracements lately, one wonder what happened to all
the bears out there. And where is the profit-taking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm afraid I don't have much to say in way of analysis now. This market
is just beyond me as of late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1622" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-spy.png" title="2009-07-24-SPY" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1623" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-spy_prop.png" title="2009-07-24-SPY_prop" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GICS Sectors Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1624" align="aligncenter" width="499"
caption="6 months: XLE XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU"][&lt;img alt="6 months:
XLE XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-6m_sectors.png" title="2009-07-24-6m_sectors" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1625" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="1 month: XLE XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU"][&lt;img alt="1 month:
XLE XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-1m_sectors.png" title="2009-07-24-1m_sectors" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1626" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="5 days: XLE XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU"][&lt;img alt="5 days: XLE
XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-5d_sectors.png" title="2009-07-24-5d_sectors" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-spy.png" title="2009-07-24-SPY" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-spy.png
  [&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-spy_prop.png" title="2009-07-24-SPY_prop" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-spy_prop.png
  [&lt;img alt="6 months: XLE XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-6m_sectors.png" title="2009-07-24-6m_sectors" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-6m_sectors.png
  [&lt;img alt="1 month: XLE XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-1m_sectors.png" title="2009-07-24-1m_sectors" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-1m_sectors.png
  [&lt;img alt="5 days: XLE XLB XLI XLY XLP XLV XLF XLK IYZ XLU" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-5d_sectors.png" title="2009-07-24-5d_sectors" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-24-5d_sectors.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="weekly review"></category></entry><entry><title>Weekly Market Review: July 10, 2009</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/weekly-market-review-july-10-2009/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-07-12T08:49:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-07-12:weekly-market-review-july-10-2009/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We finally broke below the well-known support of 880 for the S&amp;amp;P500
(Figure 1). However, I don't think we should short aggressively just yet
for the following reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of volume in the breakdown of support. As I said, we need some
    momentum to break our trading range. Even though the price has shown
    us the card of the market, the volume is simply lacking to show us
    any momentum. Figure 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volatility is still below 30, Figure 3. Which means we're
    experiencing a systematic move and not a dive just yet. So do expect
    some choppiness as we go downward to stop out the retail traders as
    usual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, it's obvious to everyone that the bears are in control now.
However, we need to maintain nimble positions as with these past few
months because this downward move is expected by everyone and it won't
be a free ride downward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
I'll preferably ease in the shorts in a controlled fashion rather than
betting the farm on it. However, don't discount the scenario where we
have a sudden and violent down move all of a sudden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1572" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spy.png" title="2009-07-12-SPY" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1573" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spy_prop.png" title="2009-07-12-SPY_prop" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1574" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF"][&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spx_vix.png" title="2009-07-12-SPX_VIX" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spy.png" title="2009-07-12-SPY" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spy.png
  [&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spy_prop.png" title="2009-07-12-SPY_prop" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spy_prop.png
  [&lt;img alt="S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spx_vix.png" title="2009-07-12-SPX_VIX" /&gt;]: http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/07/2009-07-12-spx_vix.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="weekly review"></category></entry></feed>