<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/mb-trading_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-02-12T14:07:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>In a forex brokers and trading platforms jumble</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/in-a-forex-brokers-and-trading-platforms-jumble/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-12T14:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-12:in-a-forex-brokers-and-trading-platforms-jumble/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, I was a happy forex student. I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper traded&lt;/a&gt; on
Oanda for a few months and even opened a live account with them. Then my
work place tightened up our internet firewall at work. I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/what-to-do-when-life-gets-in-your-way-of-trading/"&gt;couldn't
access market data anymore&lt;/a&gt; during the day. Fortunately, Dukascopy at
the time said that they'll be &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-am-staying-with-oanda-a-while-longer-before-moving-to-dukascopy/"&gt;enabling micro-lot trading&lt;/a&gt;. So I moved
to practice with Dukascopy. Then last weekend, Dukascopy said &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/no-micro-lot-trading-at-dukascopy-metatrader-4-accounts/"&gt;no
micro-lot trading on their Metatrader 4 accounts&lt;/a&gt;. I move to another
broker again. My last stop (so far) is at MB Trading. However, after
practicing with them for a week, I remembered why I didn't go with them
in the first place. They don't offer Canadian denominated account
currency! Fortunately, they do say that they're in the process of
enabling more account currencies. But who knows how long that might
take? My head is spinning from all this mess. I don't think I am asking
too much from a forex broker. I just want five features from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;good reputation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;micro-lot trading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metatrader platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;free API access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canadian dollar denominated account currency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all! Why am I being shut out everytime just when I am about to
open a live account? On top of that trouble, there's the question of
which trading platform to use. Over the past few months, I have tried
many forex brokers and their forex trading platforms. From proprietary
ones like FXTrade (Oanda), JForex (Dukascopy), and Dealbook 360 (GFT) to
the popular, third-party Metatrader 4 platform. I decided to settle with
Metatrader 4 because its charting is sufficient and scripting on it is
fairly easy. I learned MQL4 (MT4's scripting language) in a few hours
and wrote my first EA in a few days. The problem with Metatrader 4
though, is Metatrader 5. Scripts written for MT4 is incompatible on MT5.
As I intend to trade semi-automatically via expert advisors, this is a
huge problem for me. I don't want to start developing for MT4 and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-am-not-a-big-fan-of-mql4-or-trading-platform-scripting/"&gt;only
to have to convert everything again&lt;/a&gt;. I thought I could evade this
MT4-MT5 dilemma with a non-American forex broker (&lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt;) as
they're more likely to stay with MT4. But now that I can't trade with
them anymore, my best potential broker is MB Trading. Which is probably
upgrading to MT5 once it's out. Note: MT5 is built for new NFA
regulations, so American brokers probably have to upgrade. I think I
have had enough moves for now. So screw this all! I will focus on
learning Python programming for the next few weeks. While waiting for MB
Trading to adopt Canadian dollar accounts (or I come across a new
broker), and the duel between Metatrader 4 and 5 is settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dukascopy"></category><category term="mb trading"></category><category term="metatrader"></category><category term="oanda"></category></entry></feed>