<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/metatrader_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-02-12T14:07:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>In a forex brokers and trading platforms jumble</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/in-a-forex-brokers-and-trading-platforms-jumble/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-12T14:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-12:in-a-forex-brokers-and-trading-platforms-jumble/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, I was a happy forex student. I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper traded&lt;/a&gt; on
Oanda for a few months and even opened a live account with them. Then my
work place tightened up our internet firewall at work. I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/what-to-do-when-life-gets-in-your-way-of-trading/"&gt;couldn't
access market data anymore&lt;/a&gt; during the day. Fortunately, Dukascopy at
the time said that they'll be &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-am-staying-with-oanda-a-while-longer-before-moving-to-dukascopy/"&gt;enabling micro-lot trading&lt;/a&gt;. So I moved
to practice with Dukascopy. Then last weekend, Dukascopy said &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/no-micro-lot-trading-at-dukascopy-metatrader-4-accounts/"&gt;no
micro-lot trading on their Metatrader 4 accounts&lt;/a&gt;. I move to another
broker again. My last stop (so far) is at MB Trading. However, after
practicing with them for a week, I remembered why I didn't go with them
in the first place. They don't offer Canadian denominated account
currency! Fortunately, they do say that they're in the process of
enabling more account currencies. But who knows how long that might
take? My head is spinning from all this mess. I don't think I am asking
too much from a forex broker. I just want five features from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;good reputation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;micro-lot trading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metatrader platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;free API access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canadian dollar denominated account currency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all! Why am I being shut out everytime just when I am about to
open a live account? On top of that trouble, there's the question of
which trading platform to use. Over the past few months, I have tried
many forex brokers and their forex trading platforms. From proprietary
ones like FXTrade (Oanda), JForex (Dukascopy), and Dealbook 360 (GFT) to
the popular, third-party Metatrader 4 platform. I decided to settle with
Metatrader 4 because its charting is sufficient and scripting on it is
fairly easy. I learned MQL4 (MT4's scripting language) in a few hours
and wrote my first EA in a few days. The problem with Metatrader 4
though, is Metatrader 5. Scripts written for MT4 is incompatible on MT5.
As I intend to trade semi-automatically via expert advisors, this is a
huge problem for me. I don't want to start developing for MT4 and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-am-not-a-big-fan-of-mql4-or-trading-platform-scripting/"&gt;only
to have to convert everything again&lt;/a&gt;. I thought I could evade this
MT4-MT5 dilemma with a non-American forex broker (&lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt;) as
they're more likely to stay with MT4. But now that I can't trade with
them anymore, my best potential broker is MB Trading. Which is probably
upgrading to MT5 once it's out. Note: MT5 is built for new NFA
regulations, so American brokers probably have to upgrade. I think I
have had enough moves for now. So screw this all! I will focus on
learning Python programming for the next few weeks. While waiting for MB
Trading to adopt Canadian dollar accounts (or I come across a new
broker), and the duel between Metatrader 4 and 5 is settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dukascopy"></category><category term="mb trading"></category><category term="metatrader"></category><category term="oanda"></category></entry><entry><title>No micro-lot trading at Dukascopy Metatrader 4 accounts</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/no-micro-lot-trading-at-dukascopy-metatrader-4-accounts/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-07T20:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-07:no-micro-lot-trading-at-dukascopy-metatrader-4-accounts/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Update: It doesn't look as though Dukascopy will proceed with using MT4.
So you might as well look for another broker if you need MT4 or [learn
to use JForex][] if you plan on sticking with Dukascopy. Just received
the following news from [Dukascopy][] (attached below) regarding their
Metatrader accounts. Basically, they are raising their minimum lot-size
on MT4-enabled accounts to a mini-lot (10k). Micro-lot (1000 units)
trading remains exclusive to their basic (JForex only) accounts. Well,
why do bad news keep coming to me just when I'm about to go live with a
forex broker? First it was Oanda (although the problem was at my end
with them), then Dukascopy. There's no way I'm able to trade with a
mini-lot because of my strict [risk management][] rules. So I would be
stuck with the JForex platform for a while if I'm going to trade with
them. I like the JForex platform. It is simple, clean, easy to use, and
powerful. However, Metatrader is just substantially more popular. There
are hundreds of free scripts, indicators, and expert advisers published
at MQL4.com for me to edit to my liking. If I go with JForex, I'd have
to write everything from scratch. The whole point of me using a built-in
editor is to save time. So I might as well program in Python and use an
API if I need to go through learning JForex scripting, programming, and
testing. As much as I like [Dukascopy][] (35% commission rebate
affiliate link), ~~I may not be going through to trade with them
anymore. Unfortunate, really.~~

&gt; Dear BetaTester, Starting from Sunday 07.02.2010 Dukascopy (Suisse) SA
&gt; SWFX MetaTrader 4 platform will no longer support the 0.01 fractional
&gt; position trading. Minimum Trading amount on MT4 platform will be
&gt; 10,000 (0.10) units of Base Currency on all available Currency Pairs.
&gt; All positions with amounts less than minimum requirement - will be
&gt; closed by Dukascopy (Suisse) SA Staff at market rate. If you would
&gt; like to close those positions yourself please do so before 22:00 GMT
&gt; 05.02.2010. In the future for trading on LIVE and DEMO MetaTrader4
&gt; accounts the minimal amount will remain as 10,000 units of base
&gt; currency. Dukascopy (Suisse) SA will continue to offer minimum trading
&gt; amount of 1,000 units for traders who are using only JForex platform
&gt; (without possibility of trading on MT4 platform). If you will have any
&gt; further questions please do not hesitate to [contact us][Dukascopy]
&gt; for assistance. Regards, Dukascopy (Suisse) SA ICC, Route de Pre-Bois
&gt; 20 1215 Geneva 15 Switzerland

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dukascopy"></category><category term="metatrader"></category><category term="oanda"></category></entry></feed>