<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/mistake_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-04-23T20:16:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>I just made a grave fundamental mistake in my CVE.TO trade</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/i-just-made-a-grave-fundamental-mistake-in-my-cveto-trade/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-23T20:16:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-04-23:i-just-made-a-grave-fundamental-mistake-in-my-cveto-trade/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cenovus Energy (CVE.TO) tested 27.50 support and then bounced back to
break the short-term downtrend line above 28.50 or so, see Figure 1.
Naturally, I don't want to turn a profitable trade into a losing one. So
I wanted to sell &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-3-cve-to-10jul17-puts-30-00-mx-2-45-mark-28-64/"&gt;my puts options on CVE.TO&lt;/a&gt; while I can still exit at
near breakeven. However, as I am new to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;Questrade&lt;/a&gt; and unfamiliar
with their interface, I made the careless mistake of buying six more
contracts instead of selling the six that I have!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Cenovus Energy
(CVE.TO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-04-23-CVE-TO.png" /&gt;][][/caption] I realized my mistake soon afterward from
checking my account. Imagine my surprise to find that I am an owner of
12 puts contracts on CVE.TO. So I wanted to cut my losses immediately.
Unfortunately, the energy sector (XLF) and crude oil just broke above
some key resistances and CVE.TO bumped up a few more points. The right
thing to do is to ignore my unfortunate losses and just exit the
position, as that was what I intended to do. But I didn't. I decided to
not panic and analyze the stock yet another time. CVE.TO is definitely
weak. It is lagging behind others in the sector. Other energy companies
are breaking above resistance levels but CVE.TO is still below its 29.50
resistance. Yet, the fact is that the trend in the sector is upward.
Which is very bad for me. I am still holding this short CVE.TO position
over the weekend as it hasn't broken my 29.50 mental stop yet. I can
give my bearish reasons here upon observing the tape this afternoon
(e.g. Goldman Sachs Canada is dumping shares), but they would just be
excuses under the current circumstances. In any case, this is an
embarrassing confession as I've violated one of the most &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/"&gt;basic rules of
trading&lt;/a&gt;. This position is near breakeven on paper as of the close.
But who knows what can happen over the weekend. Rather than risking 3%,
which is already too much, I am now risking a &lt;em&gt;maximum&lt;/em&gt; of 10% on this
trade. What have I done... The high commission in trading options is
affecting my decision. If this were a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;forex&lt;/a&gt; position, I would have
dumped it all without giving it a second thought. This is a sign for me
to stop trading options altogether. It is better to stay with a
long-only equity strategy in my RRSP than get eaten up by commissions or
take excessive risks as I am doing now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CVE.TO"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="mistake"></category><category term="options"></category></entry></feed>