<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/modern-portfolio-theory_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-03-01T07:21:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Just because it's math does not mean it's not without its caveats</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/just-because-its-math-does-not-mean-its-not-without-its-caveats/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-01T07:21:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-03-01:just-because-its-math-does-not-mean-its-not-without-its-caveats/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am more than half way through my first speed run of the CFA level 1
material. This chapter discusses portfolio management. In particular, I
just read the Markovitz Efficient Frontier. What strikes me most about
this chapter is that these mathematical material are presented so
matter-of-factly. Recalling in chapter 1, Ethics, the idea of prudence
and due diligence was evident. This was exemplified later in the
Financial Statement chapter. Methods of drafting balance sheet, income
statement, and cash flow statement were presented in excrutiating
details before a discussion about ways to analyze them. Just so we can
understand the mechanics of it to spot bias, pitfalls,
misrepresentation, and outright frauds. In fact, a good portion of the
section were reserved for discussing the caveats in financial statement
analysis. As boring as it was to sit through the accounting details,
that was good prudence and good due diligence. Fast forward to this
discussion on Modern Portfolio Theory (MPT), it is simply explained in
the text that expected risk of a portfolio with individual asset
correlations less than 1 will be less than its weighted average risk.
Where are the billboard-sized warnings and neon-red danger signs?
Perhaps &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modern_portfolio_theory#Criticism"&gt;criticisms of MPT&lt;/a&gt; will be discussed later or perhaps I
simply missed it with my \~200 pages/day scanning pace (in which case,
just ignore me). But if I don't see a caveat lector on MPT in bold,
underlined, and boxed fonts later, then I am surely going to be very
disappointed. This is a big deal because of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-volatile-week-and-no-sign-of-the-bull-yet/"&gt;historic events of
2008&lt;/a&gt;. In which we witnessed the havoc caused by countless funds that
blindedly rely on MPT's validity (i.e. diversification of risks on the
naive basis of constant correlations and normally distributed returns),
and &lt;a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/77bf5f98-4441-11e0-931d-00144feab49a.html"&gt;other risk models&lt;/a&gt;, go under. There can be no worse mistake than
underestimating your risk in trading. Let me repeat that, there can be
no worse mistake than underestimating your risk in trading. &lt;em&gt;Careless
use of MPT&lt;/em&gt; (not MPT, per se) leads to exactly that. The problem is that
people take these financial theories to heart too much without reading
the fine prints. Just because it is presented in mathematical formulas
does not mean a theory is law. The least the CFA text can do is to
broaden financial prudence from not only dissecting financial statements
but to encompass other important intellectual matter related to the job
too. I am appalled by the fact that thousands of CFA level 1 hopefuls
might actually believe that you can always reduce portfolio risk and
identify an efficient asset mix from mere correlations and standard
deviations (which in and of themselves are flawed in the real world),
with no strings attached. "Science is the belief in the ignorance of the
experts", Richard Feynman.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CFA"></category><category term="Modern Portfolio Theory"></category></entry></feed>