<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/monthly-review_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-10-01T10:11:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Third Quarter 2010 Trading Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/third-quarter-2010-trading-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-01T10:11:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-10-01:third-quarter-2010-trading-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Markets hitched a one-way train in the third quarter. TSX opened in July
at 11200. It closed September at 12368. A whopping 10% jump in three
months! S&amp;amp;P500 made a similarly impressive 9.7% jump. We simply don't
get 10% moves even in most &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt;. I made fewer trades this quarter but
held each one for longer to ride the trend. However, I am not as
successful as I'd hope. In particular, my worst trade this quarter was
in &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/ven.to/"&gt;Ventana Gold&lt;/a&gt; (VEN.TO). The position &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-350-ven-to-10-50-profit-0-8-re-bought-250-ven-to-10-67/"&gt;was profitable&lt;/a&gt;, but the
money made was only a quarter as what I should have made. I was too
aggressive to go long when &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-400-ven-to-10-70-breakeven/"&gt;VEN.TO was heading into a brick wall&lt;/a&gt;.
Ironically, my best trade this quarter was one that didn't make money.
In hindsight, I was wrong in the direction of a position but managed to
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-4-mfc-11jan-puts-14-00-1-74-mark-12-96-loss-0-1/"&gt;escape with just a scratch&lt;/a&gt;. If I had been stubborn in &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-4-mfc-jan-2010-puts-14-00-1-70-mark-13-25/"&gt;this failed
Manulife short&lt;/a&gt;, my profit this quarter would have been wiped out. It
was a close call (technically, it was a put contract). It looks as
though I did &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-whole-year-two-hundred-and-six-posts-later/"&gt;learn something in the past year&lt;/a&gt;. My main focus this
quarter has been the backend of my trading work. Namely in &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/"&gt;quantitative
finance study and development&lt;/a&gt;. My automated strategy performed well
in the &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143/"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt; JForex contest. I won sixth place in July and first
place in August. My win streak (I also won in April) garnered the
attention from the people at Dukascopy and they kindly invited me to the
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-interview-at-dukascopy-in-geneva/"&gt;Geneva Forex Event for a TV interview&lt;/a&gt;. By far the most impressive
thing that happened to me this quarter was &lt;a href="../pictures-from-geneva/"&gt;this trip to Geneva&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;Quarterly Metric Q3 Q2&lt;/strong&gt; Sarting Fund \$9,404.87 \$8,000.00 End of
Quarter Fund \$9,630.75 \$9,404.87 Total Net Profit \$225.88 \$1,404.87
Gross Profit \$381 \$1,800 Gross Loss -\$155 -\$395 Profit Factor 2.45
4.56 Net Profit % 2.40% 17.56% Max. Drawdown % 0.85% 3.36% Total
Commission 121.1 \$155.1 Commission / Net Return 53.61% 11.04% I've said
this in the last quarter, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/june-and-second-quarter-2010-trading-review/"&gt;commissions are the bane of my trading&lt;/a&gt;.
Last quarter it took away 11% of my total return. This time it's 54%!
The structure of my equities commission requires that I trade less but
punch hard. This isn't my style. My intention is to trade less by being
more picky in my RRSP trading account. The 0.85% max. drawdown this
quarter is impressive though. I sometimes lose more than that in a
single position. Sterling Ratio 0.22 1.44 Excess Return 2.29% 17.46%
SDev Return per Trade 1.01% 2.21% Kurtosis 1.89 -0.93 Skewness 1.65 0.72
Despite my modest 2.4% return this quarter, it's not a good number in
light of the market liftoff. My low &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/analysing-monthly-forex-trading-performance-in-changing-market-conditions/"&gt;modified Sterling Ratio&lt;/a&gt; says so.
On the other hand, the statistics from my trades improved. I achieved
consistency by lowering the standard deviation of my trades and skewed
my trade returns more to the positive. Yet another thing to caution is
my high kurtosis value. Which means my total returns are due to big
profits from a couple of trades. Other than these, there is not much to
add about the rest of the data. 95th Percentile P&amp;amp;L \$193.49 \$421.15
5th Percentile P&amp;amp;L -\$50.37 -\$102.13 Net Profit Mid 90% Only -\$60.56
\$824.07 Total # of Trades 9 14 Percent Profitable 28.57% 61.54% # of
Winning Trades 2 8 # of Losing Trades 5 5 # of Break-even Trades 2 1
Average Trade Profit % 0.27% 1.18% Average Winning % 2.01% 2.59% Average
Losing % -0.32% -0.83% Ratio Win% / Loss% 6.25 3.12 Max. Conseq. Winners
3 5 Max. Conseq. Losers 3 3 Largest Winning Trade \$228.25 \$464.05
Largest Losing Trade -\$58.19 -\$116.75 Avg. Time Held [days] 8.30 5.17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal for the Fourth Quarter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/june-and-second-quarter-2010-trading-review/"&gt;goal from the previous quarter&lt;/a&gt; is to learn and build my first indicator in JForex. I achieved
that just this week. However, I plan to change direction in my work by
using less JForex and using more custom tools. My goal for the next
quarter is to learn R programming and
&lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;implement a JForex to R
data exchange system&lt;/span&gt; (done, good old CSV files).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>June and Second Quarter 2010 Trading Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/june-and-second-quarter-2010-trading-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-30T14:11:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-06-30:june-and-second-quarter-2010-trading-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Market volatility continues in June. I took a more aggressive approach
this month and executed more trades in my RRSP trading account. The
monthly return is excellent but I noticed a few issues with my trading.
These will be the main topic of this post. Let's go over some
performance data. Seeing that it is the end of the second quarter, I
will do a quarterly statistical report. I couldn't do &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/january-2010-trading-performance-review/"&gt;a monthly review
like I used to&lt;/a&gt; because I trade much less frequently now. Note that
the October data is from last year's forex trading. That was the best
month I've had. I am attaching the data here just for comparison.
&lt;strong&gt;Quarterly Metric Q2 October&lt;/strong&gt; Sarting Fund \$8,000.00 End of Quarter
Fund \$9,404.87 Total Net Profit \$1,404.87 Gross Profit \$1,800 Gross
Loss -\$395 Profit Factor 4.56 1.75 Net Profit % &lt;strong&gt;17.56%&lt;/strong&gt; 4.19% Max.
Drawdown % 3.36% 2.32% Total Commission \$155.1 Commission / Net Return
&lt;strong&gt;11.04%&lt;/strong&gt; This highlight the bane of my problem trading my RRSP.
Although &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;Questrade&lt;/a&gt; offers the best commission in Canada as far as I
know, it is still much higher than those offered by brokers in the
states. However, this is a self-directed RRSP trading account, so it's
not like I can just switch broker. I will just have to stop being so
active in my trading for this particular account. Sterling Ratio 1.44
0.65 Excess Return 17.46% 4.14% SDev Return per Trade 2.21% 0.79%
Kurtosis -0.93 8.53 Skewness 0.72 2.49 These statistics above show my
second problem. Although I am very profitable so far, my return per
trade is not consistent. The distribution is too flat and not skewed
enough to the positive for my liking. A standard deviation less than 1%,
a slightly positive kurtosis, and a skewness above 1.0 would be ideal.
95th Percentile P&amp;amp;L \$421.15 \$70.11 5th Percentile P&amp;amp;L -\$102.13
-\$33.60 Net Profit Mid 90% Only \$0.29 \$46.34 Total # of Trades 14 34
Percent Profitable 61.54% 44.12% # of Winning Trades 8 15 # of Losing
Trades 5 19 # of Break-even Trades 1 0 Average Trade Profit % 1.18%
0.12% Average Winning % 2.59% 0.66% Average Losing % -0.83% -0.30% Ratio
Win% / Loss% 3.12 2.21 Max. Conseq. Winners 5 4 Max. Conseq. Losers 3 6
Largest Winning Trade \$464.05 \$171.79 Largest Losing Trade -\$116.75
-\$44.17 Most of my winning are due to &lt;a href="../sold-12-cve-to-puts-2-90-mark-27-50-10-gain/"&gt;this Cenovus short in May&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="../sold-6-cm-10oct-put-74-00-6-60-mark-70-70-8-0/"&gt;this CIBC short in June&lt;/a&gt;. Avg. Time Held 5.17 days 2.18 hours Aside
from trading my RRSP account, I have finally opened a live &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143/"&gt;forex
account at Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt;. My time remains split between developing
automated strategies for trading forex and manual equity trading as
usual. My JForex contest strategy in June ends up near the bottom again
as I took the wrong side of the move on USD/CAD. The JForex contest will
start with a new set of rules for July. Namely that strategies need to
be fully automated and winnings from each trade cannot be excessive
(50%) to prevent an all-in approach that's been dominating the contest.
My revised strategy is ready. It is now version 2.14 since the first
release in April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal for July&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal for July is to learn the indicators part of the JForex API and
to program my first custom JForex indicator from my other collection. I
will be away in Hong Kong for two weeks in July for some family matter.
So there's not much time to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>May 2010 Trading Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/may-2010-trading-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-04T11:21:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-06-04:may-2010-trading-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;May 6th was a historical day in the market. The [Dow tanked 9% in
minutes but climbed back up near the end of the day][]. We have since
closed below that level later in the month. The bears seem to have
finally awoken. I closed two trades in May totalling a decent gain of
10% in my RRSP trading account. The first was &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-12-cve-to-puts-2-90-mark-27-50-10-gain/"&gt;shorting CVE.TO&lt;/a&gt;, which
made me 10%. The second was &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-110-tck-b-to-36-03-stopped-out-at-breakeven/"&gt;long TCK/B.TO&lt;/a&gt;, which ended in breakeven.
I took the second half of the month off for my wedding in Dominican
Republic. I opened two positions before leaving for vacation. I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-3-cm-to-10oct-puts-5-00-mark-74-02/"&gt;shorted
CM.TO&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-380-hnd-to-7-25-stop-7-00/"&gt;bought some HND.TO&lt;/a&gt;. The market made a roller coaster
run up and then down while I was away. So I wasn't able to cash in on
the move. As for my forex endeavour, I bombed the JForex contest this
month. I started well with a 60% gain in the first week but I got greedy
and tried to go for higher. My contest account (demo only, not real
cash) whipsawed around breakeven a few times afterward. Then I just gave
up on this month's contest. I verified with the official that my
startegy wouldn't have qualified anyway because I was manually
intervening too many times. Nevertheless, I updated my automated trading
strategy for June before going on vacation. I will be back at it again
competing in June. But not until my wife and I can settle down in our
new home first. We are still unpacking, buying furnitures, and tidying
up our new place as of this first weekend in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Dow tanked 9% in minutes but climbed back up near the end of the
  day]: ../to-hell-and-back-a-review-of-tsx-after-a-v-day/&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>April 2010 Trading Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/april-2010-trading-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-03T12:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-05-03:april-2010-trading-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I made my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-3-cve-to-jul-30-puts-1-75-mark-30-10/"&gt;first RRSP trade to short Cenovus Energy (CVE.TO) using
puts&lt;/a&gt; in April. I also made my first careless mistake in my RRSP by
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/i-just-made-a-grave-fundamental-mistake-in-my-cve-to-trade/"&gt;buying more contracts instead of closing the CVE.TO position&lt;/a&gt; as I
intended. As of this writing, I am still holding my puts options as the
slow decline seem to be underway. &lt;a href="http://uk.reuters.com/article/idUKTRE6421BP20100503"&gt;China's decision to hike reserve
ratio&lt;/a&gt; is also helping by strengthening the dollar and putting another
warning on recent risk appetite. Despite putting my real money on the
line, my main focus lately has been the Dukascopy JForex Strategy
Contest. According to their rankings page, I finished at 4th place for
April's contest. Which means I may receive a USD \$1,000 credit to my
&lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143/"&gt;trading account at Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt;. Even if I were to trade a \$5,000
account as I have done in my paper trading, I couldn't have earned 20%
in a single month &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;based on my past performance&lt;/a&gt;. This contest is a
great way for me to fill my forex account with no monetary risk.
Frankly, I was just &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/to-gamble-or-not-to-gamble/"&gt;hoping to squeeze in a top 10&lt;/a&gt; because I started
late in the April contest. So I am very happy to finish at such a good
position and receive (hopefully) a decent sum of prize money! For anyone
interested, I have discussed about &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-explanation-of-my-keltner-channel-and-candlestick-hybrid-setup/"&gt;my winning automated strategy&lt;/a&gt;
previously. Feel free to take a look at it to see what got me a 4th
place finish. I will be away on vacation in the last two weeks of May. I
don't expect much to happen with my trading this month as I'm inundated
with personal matters. My primary focus is still the JForex Strategy
Contest. I will be using a new semi-automated strategy this time. My
goal is to finish in the top 6 again.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>March 2010 Trading Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/march-2010-trading-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-01T07:37:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-04-01:march-2010-trading-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is that time of the month again when I do my trading performance
review. However, I did not make any trade this month. Not because I was
procrastinating, but I spent all of my time this month to work on my
quantitative projects. This review will be a recap of my backend trading
development. I said in my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/february-2010-trading-performance-review/"&gt;last month's performance review&lt;/a&gt; that my
goal for March is "to write a rudimentary data analysis and
visualization program for historical forex data." Well, I finished &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/"&gt;half
of it&lt;/a&gt; and then realized that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/from-object-oriented-programming-to-object-oriented-design/"&gt;I need a better design for the
software&lt;/a&gt;. So I studied yet another programming book (finished 3
programming books this month), on object oriented design and analysis.
The other major event for me this month is that I finally opened a
self-directed RRSP account at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;Questrade&lt;/a&gt; because the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/considering-investment-options-for-my-first-rrsp/"&gt;tax benefit is
too good to pass&lt;/a&gt;. Consequently, I am starting to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-first-analysis-of-the-sptsx-60-index/"&gt;study the Canadian
stock market&lt;/a&gt; for trading with a conservative, intermediate-term
manner (not buy and hold though). Lastly, it seems that I might be back
to trading forex sooner than I have thought. I signed up for an
automated trading contest at &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week. Since they
are offering a cash prize, I thought I might as well reschedule and work
on my forex stuff now. I will write more on this topic at another time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>February 2010 Trading Performance Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/february-2010-trading-performance-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-02T08:14:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-02:february-2010-trading-performance-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I barely traded this month. The total number of trades in February for
my forex demo account is ten. That's far from my regular 150 - 250
trades a month. Ever since my trading system was broken because of
technical difficulties, I've &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/what-to-do-when-life-gets-in-your-way-of-trading/"&gt;changed my priorities&lt;/a&gt; in trading. I
spent most of my time in February learning a new programming language to
ramp up my quant and automated trading projects. I also tried a few
longer term trades this month. The results haven't been uplifting. I am
about breakeven by the end of the month with a net gain of .... \$2 in a
\$5550 demo account. As you can see, there's really not much point in me
continuing paper trading at this stage. It is taking valuable time away
from me to fix what's broken so that I can use my previously profitable
trading system again. As such, I'm going to put near 100% of my effort
to program a semi-automated trading system for the coming weeks, or
probably months. On another note. Seeing that it is tax season here in
Canada. I thought about my tax situation and considered &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;opening a
Questrade TFSA trading account&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link) to legitimately
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/not-pay-trading-income-taxes-through-a-tfsa-trading-account/"&gt;avoid income taxes from trading&lt;/a&gt;. But after considering the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/is-a-5000-questrade-tfsa-trading-account-cost-effective-part-1/"&gt;cost and
benefit&lt;/a&gt; of such a move, I concluded that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/is-a-5000-questrade-tfsa-trading-account-cost-effective-%e2%80%93-part-4/"&gt;a TFSA trading account
isn't cost effective for me&lt;/a&gt; at the moment. As I've spent most of the
month doing backend work, there isn't very much to review for my trading
this month. So let's just dive right into my statistics for the record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly Metric February (January)&lt;/strong&gt; Sarting Fund \$5,550.02 End of
Month Fund \$5,551.99 Total Net Profit \$1.97 (-\$67.42) Gross Profit
\$37 (\$375) Gross Loss -\$35 (-\$442) Profit Factor 1.06 (0.85) Net
Profit % 0.04% (-1.20%) Max. Drawdown % 0.50% (3.95%) Sterling Ratio
0.00 (-0.15) Excess Return -0.02% (-1.26%) SDev Return per Trade 0.15%
(0.11%) Kurtosis -1.36 (1.85) Skewness 0.79 (1.01) With only ten trades
this month, I don't have enough samples to make meaningful calculations
for the above statistics. 95th Percentile P&amp;amp;L \$12.55 (\$12.23) 5th
Percentile P&amp;amp;L -\$6.60 (-\$8.43) Net Profit Mid 90% Only -\$4.75
(-\$117.84) Interestingly, I noticed that my typical top and bottom 5th
percentile profit/loss are quite consistent. Total # of Trades 10 (186)
Percent Profitable 40.00% (41.45%) # of Winning Trades 4 (63) # of
Losing Trades 6 (89) # of Break-even Trades 0 (34) My percent
profitable trades seem to be near 40% month to month. That's good to
know as it's useful to calculate my statistical return expectancy as
I've done in my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/is-a-5000-questrade-tfsa-trading-account-cost-effective-%e2%80%93-part-3/"&gt;TFSA trading cost-benefit analysis&lt;/a&gt;. Average Trade
Profit % 0.00% (-0.01%) Average Winning % 0.17% (0.11%) Average Losing %
-0.11% (-0.09%) Ratio Win% / Loss% 1.59 (1.20) By being more
discriminating in my trades, I've effectively increased my win/loss
ratio. That's good. Max. Conseq. Winners 3 (8) Max. Conseq. Losers 5
(20) Largest Winning Trade \$13.81 (\$22.66) Largest Losing Trade
-\$7.08 (-\$14.30) Avg. Time Held [hrs] 1.67 (0.73) Avg. max. unrealized
profit/ Realized profit (11.59)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal for March&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal from January is &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/january-2010-trading-performance-review/"&gt;to learn MQL4&lt;/a&gt;. I changed my plan since then
due &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-am-not-a-big-fan-of-mql4-or-trading-platform-scripting/"&gt;my lack of faith with using a proprietary scripting language&lt;/a&gt;. I
learned Python programming this month and is now learning to use
specialized libraries to serve my trading needs. My goal for March is to
write a rudimentary data analysis and visualization program for
historical forex data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>January 2010 Trading Performance Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/january-2010-trading-performance-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-01T12:03:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-01:january-2010-trading-performance-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;2010 didn't begin well for me. I experienced my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/first-2010-trading-drawdown-analysis-on-the-verge-of-a-new-record/"&gt;biggest drawdown&lt;/a&gt; so
far at -3.95% (see Figure 1 for my account balance graph) in my demo
account. Given that I only risk 0.2% per trade, this is a relatively
substantial setback. Ironically, I was in the process of filling paper
work to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-am-staying-with-oanda-a-while-longer-before-moving-to-dukascopy/"&gt;open a live account&lt;/a&gt; when this performance setback hit me.
Change of plan. Now I'll have to postpone live trading until I can at
least recover my demo account balance. To do that, I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/work-harder-trade-fewer-in-a-long-and-excruciating-trading-drawdown/"&gt;tightened up&lt;/a&gt; my
risk exposure and focused on playing only &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/FTC"&gt;my best setup&lt;/a&gt;. By the
close of the month, my demo account is sitting at -1.2% for January. At
least I have made it some way from the bottom with a few &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/good-trade/"&gt;good
trades&lt;/a&gt;. This is also the first negative month for me since beginning
trading forex in September, just 4 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="January 2010
Demo Account Balance"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/january_2010_account_balance.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from my performance, a notable change this month for my trading is
the fact that I've been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/barred-from-trading-at-work-a-curse-or-a-gift/"&gt;barred from trading during the day&lt;/a&gt;. This
forced me to trade less, which is a good thing. On the other hand, I'm
not able to manage my stops as often as I would have liked. As such,
I've been helpless at times and watched some profitable positions &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-144-24-stop-143-60-target-148/"&gt;turn
sour&lt;/a&gt;. Whereas before, I would have at least moved my stops to
breakeven when the price moved away enough. Obviously, this calls for a
drastic change to my current trading strategy. For one, I'm looking at
higher timeframes for my trading now to catch slower moves. Secondly, my
top priority for the next few months is to develop some &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;trading bots&lt;/a&gt;
to manage my risks while I'm away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly Metric January (December)&lt;/strong&gt; Sarting Fund \$5,617.44 End of
Month Fund \$5,550.02 Total Net Profit -\$67.42 (\$148.33) Gross Profit
\$375 (\$591) Gross Loss -\$442 (-\$443) Profit Factor 0.85 (1.34) Net
Profit % -1.20% (2.71%) Max. Drawdown % 3.95% (1.91%) Sterling Ratio
-0.15 (0.41) Excess Return -1.26% (2.66%) SDev Return per Trade 0.11%
(0.12%) Kurtosis 1.85 (17.38) Skewness 1.01 (3.30) 95th Percentile P&amp;amp;L
\$12.23 (\$11.97) 5th Percentile P&amp;amp;L -\$8.43 (-\$5.73) Net Profit Mid
90% Only &lt;strong&gt;-\$117.84&lt;/strong&gt; (-\$46.96) Total # of Trades 186 (276) Percent
Profitable 41.45% (40.77%) # of Winning Trades 63 (95) # of Losing
Trades 89 (138) # of Break-even Trades 34 (43) Average Trade Profit %
-0.01% (0.01%) Average Winning % 0.11% (0.11%) Average Losing % -0.09%
(-0.06%) Ratio Win% / Loss% 1.20 (1.94) Max. Conseq. Winners 8 (9) Max.
Conseq. Losers 20 (18) Largest Winning Trade \$22.66 (\$47.44) Largest
Losing Trade -\$14.30 (-\$11.64) Avg. Time Held [hrs] 0.73 (0.26)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal for February&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/december-2009-trading-performance-review/"&gt;goal from the previous month&lt;/a&gt; is to think more and trade less.
Well, I managed the latter part but the former still requires work as
evident by my negative return this month. For February, my strategy is
to keep trading with half the risk exposure (i.e. 0.1% per trade) to
recover my account back to its all-time high in beginning of January.
I'm just about 2% away at this moment. My goal for February is to get
acquinted with MQL4 so that I can begin to develop expert advisors to
manage my risks during the day and overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>December 2009 Trading Performance Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/december-2009-trading-performance-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-04T12:16:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-04:december-2009-trading-performance-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/november-2009-trading-performance-review/"&gt;set 2 goals back in November&lt;/a&gt; for December. 1) Think more,
trade less; and 2) Be more aggressive on winners. With 276 trades in
December, I have failed miserably for goal #1. I couldn't meet my
second goal either as I've missed most of the big moves from failing to
recognize the bigger picture. Nonetheless, I ended up the month +2.71%
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;in my demo account&lt;/a&gt; by picking pennies here and there and with the
help of some&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/4-fundamental-entry-signs-for-trading-and-why-they-are-not-that-important/"&gt;decent risk management&lt;/a&gt; to limit my risks. Overall, it
was a bad month for me because of too much time spent trading with
little reward to show. I noticed my over-trading tendency early in the
month. My solution was to [limit myself to the longer timeframe to
reduce moving in and out of trades][] too frequently. Reviewing that
particular post, I was spot on with identifying my problem. However, my
over-trading problem lingered on for the rest of the month (i.e.
"staring at the trading screen too much once I am in a position and
tried to micro-manage my trades to minimize my risk"). While this can be
attributed to the more volatile market in December (discussed later),
the real downside of my over-trading can be seen in Figure 1 showing my
demo account balance graph for December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="December 2009
Account Balance"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/december_2009_account_balance.png" /&gt;][][/caption] Notice the following
characteristics in Figure 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two up-spikes in the month (around the 8th and 17th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a slow, barely-upward grind in the middle of the month (from 9th to
    16th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a marching drawdown at the start and end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#1 was mostly luck. I was in the right position at the right time. #2
was the grind as it should be. I intend to delegate this type of trading
to my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated trading system&lt;/a&gt; once it's developed (haven't even
started yet though). But for the moment, it's all manual. What's most
concerning is #3. Sometimes it's just better to not trade at all. That
is something which I still need to learn to do. Evidently, I still need
to work on narrowing my trading setup to filter out these erroneous
trades. I outlined the new steps for that [in my previous post][limit
myself to the longer timeframe to reduce moving in and out of trades]
already. I just need discipline to follow my own advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly Metric December (November)&lt;/strong&gt; Sarting Fund \$5,469.11 End of
Month Fund \$5,617.44 Total Net Profit \$148.33 (\$166.90) Gross Profit
\$591 (\$598) Gross Loss -\$443 (-\$431) Profit Factor 1.34 (1.39) Net
Profit % 2.71% (3.15%) Max. Drawdown % 1.91% (3.44%) The above stats
look consistent with the previous month's data in brackets. My maximum
drawdown actually improved significantly down to 1.91% from 3.44%. That
is due to the fact that I took a lot more small trades to rake in
pennies rather than bet big on big moves. Frankly, I would prefer the
latter strategy as I don't typically have so much time. Sterling Ratio
0.41 (0.41) Excess Return 2.66% (3.10%) SDev Return per Trade 0.12%
(0.19%) Kurtosis 17.38 (3.45) Skewness 3.30 (1.54) Comparing my
performance statistics using &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/analysing-monthly-forex-trading-performance-in-changing-market-conditions/"&gt;my new modified Sterling ratio&lt;/a&gt;, it's
coincidentally exactly the same as November. My maximum drawdown
improved but its benefit in the equation is cancelled out by the
increased volatility in December. My ultimate target is to achieve a
consistent monthly modified Sterling Ratio of 0.50 or above. The
kurtosis and skewness statistics got a lot worse this month. These are
expected from the large number of small trades and the few big
profitable trades as seen in Figure 1. However, what's alarming is the
data below. 95th Percentile P&amp;amp;L \$11.97 (\$23.20) 5th Percentile P&amp;amp;L
-\$5.73 (-\$10.31) Net Profit Mid 90% Only -\$46.96 (\$33.82) As you can
see, it would have been a losing month if it weren't for the outlier
trades. This is definitely the most worrisome statistic this month. &lt;strong&gt;I
need to stop picking pennies and concentrate on bigger moves.&lt;/strong&gt; Total #
of Trades 276 (153) Percent Profitable 40.77% (46.36%) # of Winning
Trades 95 (70) # of Losing Trades 138 (81) # of Break-even Trades 43
(2) As I've said before, I took the most number of trades this month
since my short forex career. My percent profitable drifted farther below
50% to 40.77%. I might as well throw random dart to make my pick. This
has once again proven that I over-traded and didn't spent enough time
with my analysis. The large number of break-even trades is also a
sore-sight in the data. Average Trade Profit % 0.01% (0.02%) Average
Winning % 0.11% (0.16%) Average Losing % -0.06% (-0.10%) Ratio Win% /
Loss% 1.94 (1.61) Max. Conseq. Winners 9 (12) Max. Conseq. Losers 18
(14) Largest Winning Trade \$47.44 (\$41.88) Largest Losing Trade
-\$11.64 (-\$20.34) Avg. Time Held [hrs] 0.26 (0.56)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal for January&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's only one goal for me for January and it's the same as
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/november-2009-trading-performance-review/"&gt;November&lt;/a&gt;'s. &lt;strong&gt;Think more and trade
less&lt;/strong&gt;! Refer to my post on &lt;a href="../focusing-on-trading-my-timeframe-to-reduce-over-trading/" title="Permanent Link to Focusing on trading my timeframe to reduce over-trading"&gt;Focusing on trading my timeframe to reduce
over-trading&lt;/a&gt; to see my plan to achieve that.&lt;a href="../focusing-on-trading-my-timeframe-to-reduce-over-trading/" title="Permanent Link to Focusing on trading my timeframe to reduce over-trading"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="_mcePaste" style="overflow: hidden; position: absolute; left: -10000px; top: 981px; width: 1px; height: 1px;"&gt;
Monthly Metric December Sarting Fund \$5,469.11 End of Month Fund
\$5,617.44 Total Net Profit \$148.33 Gross Profit \$591 Gross Loss
-\$443 Profit Factor 1.34 Net Profit % 2.71% Max. Drawdown % 1.91%
Sterling Ratio 0.41 Excess Return 2.66% SDev Return per Trade 0.12%
Kurtosis 17.38 Skewness 3.30 95th Percentile P&amp;L \$11.97 5th Percentile
P&amp;L -\$5.73 Net Profit Mid 90% Only -\$46.96 Total \# of Trades 276
Percent Profitable 40.77% \# of Winning Trades 95 \# of Losing Trades
138 \# of Break-even Trades 43 Average Trade Profit % 0.01% Average
Winning % 0.11% Average Losing % -0.06% Ratio Win% / Loss% 1.94 Max.
Conseq. Winners 9 Max. Conseq. Losers 18 Largest Winning Trade \$47.44
Largest Losing Trade -\$11.64 Avg. Time Held [hrs] 0.26

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[limit myself to the longer timeframe to reduce moving in and out of
  trades]: http://www.quantisan.com/focusing-on-trading-my-timeframe-to-reduce-over-trading/&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>November 2009 Trading Performance Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/november-2009-trading-performance-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-01T22:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-12-01:november-2009-trading-performance-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month has been a roller coaster in both the markets and my account
balance (see Figure 1). Here's a quick recap of my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper trades&lt;/a&gt; in
the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;forex markets&lt;/a&gt; for November. I started out by cashing the carried
over long yen and dollar positions from October. Those trades could have
been better as I have &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-good-trade-that-could-have-been-great-a-lesson-to-take-profit-at-target/"&gt;lamented in a post&lt;/a&gt;. Nevertheless, it was a
good start for the month. Then, things went downhill for me; literally,
as you can see from my account balance at the first half of the month in
Figure 1. I tried my luck &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-bad-eurusd-day-trading-and-what-to-do-about-it/"&gt;day trading EUR/USD with horrible results&lt;/a&gt;.
I marked this particular period of drawdown from these EUR/USD day
trades on Figure 1 with a red band. The fear lingered on and I gave up
all the initial gain of the month to scrap just below the opening
balance. Fortunately, I was able to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-example-of-how-trading-in-fear-is-bad-for-your-account/"&gt;realize my problem&lt;/a&gt; and clean up
my act. I recuperated by documenting &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-usdchf-1-0122-sl-1-0060-tp-1-0225/"&gt;each&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-audjpy-81-22-sl-80-99-tp-82-50/"&gt;of my&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-out-audjpy-longs-81-3-7-pips-and-81-29-28-pips/"&gt;entry&lt;/a&gt; like I
used to to force myself to think more and trade less. The turnaround
didn't happen immediately. Not until I became even more stringent on
myself and stuck with using only my best setup, the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC setup&lt;/a&gt;. I
marked this period on Figure 1 with the green bar and arrow. As you can
see, I happened to be in the right markets and at the right times to
make a full recovery back to the top. In fact, I made &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/audjpy-short-81-3777-17-anatomy-of-my-first-400-pips-trade/"&gt;my first 400+
pips trade&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/eurusd-95-pips-in-2-hours-an-example-of-swing-and-day-trade-convergence/"&gt;my best EUR/USD day trade&lt;/a&gt; during this comeback. I
thought I could finish the month above the critical \$5500 level (10%
gain). But a couple small losers on the last day pulled my account below
it yet again. However, one lesson I became even more aware of from the
draw-down is to forget about your account balance. Focus on making good
trades, manage your risks, and the money will take care of itself.
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="November 2009
trades graph"][&lt;img alt="November 2009 trades graph" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-12-01-account_graph.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-12-01-account_graph.png"&gt;November 2009 trades
graph&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached below are my performance statistics for November. The first
number is this month's and the second number in bracket is from October
for comparison. I will highlight and comment on the few discrepancies
that I find important. Sarting Fund \$5,089.06 End of Month Fund
\$5,302.21 Total Net Profit \$166.90 (\$213.15) Gross Profit \$598
(\$499) Gross Loss -\$431 (-\$285) Profit Factor 1.39 (1.75) Net Profit
% 3.15% (4.19%) Max. Drawdown % &lt;strong&gt;3.44%&lt;/strong&gt; (2.32%) This draw-down is
horrible to say the least. Kurtosis &lt;strong&gt;3.45&lt;/strong&gt; (8.53) Skewness &lt;strong&gt;1.54&lt;/strong&gt;
(2.49) Sharpe Ratio &lt;strong&gt;16.64&lt;/strong&gt; (5.21) The kurtosis and skewness are
surprisingly good. A low, but not near-zero numbers are preferable. The
Sharpe ratio is also surprisingly good too. This isn't because my return
is good, is just that the standard deviation return of my trades have
been very consistent. Ironically, that's mostly because of steady small
losses (see Figure 1). 95th Percentile P&amp;amp;L \$23.20 (\$70.11) 5th
Percentile P&amp;amp;L -\$10.31 (-\$33.60) Net Profit Mid 90% Only &lt;strong&gt;\$33.82&lt;/strong&gt;
(\$46.34) I failed to meet &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/october-2009-trading-performance-review/"&gt;my goal from last month&lt;/a&gt; to increase my
mid-90% return. It would have been easily met if I didn't go crazy with
the day trades and loose a bundle. Total # of Trades &lt;strong&gt;153&lt;/strong&gt; (34)
Percent Profitable 47.06% (44.12%) # of Winning Trades 72 (15) # of
Losing Trades 81 (19) I started to make use of scaling in and out of a
trade. So sometimes one trade would be counted as 2 or 3 small ones.
Still, I made too many trades this month. Even if I consider a 2 for 1
ratio of trades (i.e. 153 / 2 = 76), it is still more than twice as many
as last month. My net profit is lower too. Wasted time and effort for
lower return. &lt;strong&gt;Lesson for the month is clearly to think more and trade
less&lt;/strong&gt;. Average Trade Profit % 0.02% (0.12%) Average Winning % &lt;strong&gt;0.16&lt;/strong&gt;%
( 0.66%) Average Losing % &lt;strong&gt;-0.10&lt;/strong&gt;% (-0.30%) Ratio Win% / Loss% 1.57
(2.21) This could be the most worrisome statistics for me this month. My
average winning percentage from a trade is significantly less. &lt;strong&gt;I need
to be more aggressive when I am right to reap the most reward from it&lt;/strong&gt;.
Stash in the cash as the position gets greener! Max. Conseq. Winners 12
(4) Max. Conseq. Losers 14 (6) Largest Winning Trade \$41.88 (\$171.79)
Largest Losing Trade -\$20.34 (-\$44.17) Avg. Time Held [hrs] 0.56
(2.18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal for Next Month&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start by saying what I did well this month. I think my comeback
was phenomenal, but definitely with luck on my side. I approached my
huge draw-down systematically and rationally by reducing position size,
trading less, and restricted myself by using my best &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-signal/"&gt;trading setup&lt;/a&gt;
only. Then when the time was right, I was able to pound on the winning
positions. I will need to remember this the next time I'm experiencing a
draw-down (hopefully not as much as this month's). On the other hand, I
made many trading mistakes this month. Most were just short-term
problems and I have already written about them in my lessons. Upon
further review of my performance this month, two major problems are
evident as discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think more and trade less. Limit my trades to approximately one a
    day and know when to NOT trade at all. Not even with tiny positions
    to "test the water" as I like to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be more aggressive when the position is right. Achieve this by
    improving on my scaling in and out strategy by accelerating the
    scaling in and decelerating on the scaling out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div id="_mcePaste" style="overflow: hidden; position: absolute; left: -10000px; top: 867px; width: 1px; height: 1px;"&gt;
Sarting Fund \$5,089.06 \$5,302.21 End of Month Fund \$5,302.21
\$5,469.11 Total Net Profit \$213.15 \$166.90 Gross Profit \$499 \$598
Gross Loss -\$285 -\$431 Profit Factor 1.75 1.39 Net Profit % 4.19%
3.15% Max. Drawdown % 2.32% 3.44% Kurtosis 8.53 3.45 Skewness 2.49 1.54
Sharpe Ratio 5.21 16.64 95th Percentile P&amp;L \$70.11 \$23.20 5th
Percentile P&amp;L -\$33.60 -\$10.31 Net Profit Mid 90% Only \$46.34 \$33.82
Total \# of Trades 34 153 Percent Profitable 44.12% 47.06% \# of Winning
Trades 15 72 \# of Losing Trades 19 81 Average Trade Profit % 0.12%
0.02% Average Winning % 0.66% 0.16% Average Losing % -0.30% -0.10% Ratio
Win% / Loss% 2.21 1.57 Max. Conseq. Winners 4 12 Max. Conseq. Losers 6
14 Largest Winning Trade \$171.79 \$41.88 Largest Losing Trade -\$44.17
-\$20.34 Avg. Time Held [hrs] 2.18 0.56

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry><entry><title>October 2009 Trading Performance Review</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/october-2009-trading-performance-review/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-31T21:20:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-10-31:october-2009-trading-performance-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;October is the first full month in which I traded forex. Naturally, this
is the first of my monthly trading performance review. Note that all the
trades were on a demo account with imaginary money only. But I still
took this seriously. My goal is to double this demo account starting
from CAD\$5000. Once that is accomplished, I will start live trading
with real money. Who knows how long this might take. Hopefully by then,
I will have a respectable set of &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-signal/"&gt;trading setups&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;strategies&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tools"&gt;quant tools&lt;/a&gt; developed. Anyway, let's get on with the monthly review.
As this is only my first month trading currencies after spending 8 years
in &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/stocks/"&gt;stocks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/futures/"&gt;futures&lt;/a&gt;, my trading this month is marked by a lot
of experimentation. As can be seen in my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trading log&lt;/a&gt;, I performed
abysmally for the first couple of weeks. The last of my bad string ended
when I took an uncalled for trade &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-undisciplined-trade-shorted-eurusd-1-499-stopped-1-505-62-pips/"&gt;based on what I thought rather than
what I saw&lt;/a&gt;. Not all is lost this month as I managed to write out the
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftcs/"&gt;first of my forex trading setups&lt;/a&gt; from the trials and errors. Since
then, I had a string of winners to push my monthly tally deeper into the
positive. While this is definitely good, I am cautious and doubtful to
my initial success because I am just at the right place, at the right
time. Because we might very well be witnessing the printing of the top
from this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/inter-market-analysis-after-a-new-2009-high-in-the-equity-market/"&gt;epic V-shaped rally since March&lt;/a&gt;. The moves in the markets
were very strong and very rapid this last week. I just happen to be on
the right side of the trades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance Statistics Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, I'll get down to business with discussing the performance
statistics below. On first sight, the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sharpe_ratio"&gt;Sharpe ratio&lt;/a&gt; at 5.25 is
impressive for this month. However, looking a few lines below, see that
if we account for only the middle 90th percentile profits and losses,
the net profit is reduced by a magnitude. (So as to see what would
happen if we truncate the biggest (un)lucky wins and losses.) That means
much of my profit for this month was because of a few big trade. In
fact, it was &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-eurjpy-135-00-500-1-pips/"&gt;this lucky trade when I made +500 pips&lt;/a&gt; in one week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal for Next Month&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I've learned from analyzing these numbers is that I lack
consistency (like all new traders), and was perhaps just lucky. So the
goals for the coming months are simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;achieve consistency by bringing up this mid 90% net profit value;
    and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain good Sharpe ratio rating by improving my risk management
    techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance Statistics for October 2009&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total Net Profit \$213.15 Gross Profit \$499 Gross Loss -\$285 Profit
Factor 1.75 Net Profit % 4.19% Max. Drawdown % -2.32% Sharpe Ratio 5.25
95th Percentile P&amp;amp;L \$70.11 5th Percentile P&amp;amp;L -\$33.60 Net Profit Mid
90% Only \$46.34 Total # of Trades 34 Percent Profitable 44.12% # of
Winning Trades 15 # of Losing Trades 19 Average Trade Profit % 0.12%
Average Winning % 0.66% Average Losing % -0.30% Ratio Win% / Loss% 2.21
Max. Conseq. Winners 4 Max. Conseq. Losers 6 Largest Winning Trade
171.79 Largest Losing Trade -44.17 Avg. Time Held [hrs] 2.18 Avg. max.
unrealized profit/ Realized profit 3.15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="monthly review"></category></entry></feed>