<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/natural-language-processing_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-02-15T07:30:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Social media: The fourth dimension in market data</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/social-media-the-fourth-dimension-in-market-data/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-15T07:30:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-02-15:social-media-the-fourth-dimension-in-market-data/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It looks as though the first hedge fund utilizing social media data is
about to &lt;a href="http://www.cnbc.com/id/41251767/"&gt;launch in April&lt;/a&gt;. This "Twitter hedge fund" is based on the
work of Bollen et al., "&lt;a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/arXiv:1010.3003"&gt;Twitter mood predicts the stock market&lt;/a&gt;,"
Journal of Computational Science, 2011. In more general terms, this is
an example use of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing"&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/a&gt; (NLP) to assess the
semantic of tweets relating to the stock market. NLP, or more
specifically semantic search, has been the holy grail of search engine
companies since people realized that you can make a boatload of money by
providing good search results. Semantic search improve search accuracy
by understanding the seacher's &lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;contextual meaning&lt;/em&gt;
rather than going on the vocabulary alone (see Nature: &lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/news/2011/110215/full/news.2011.95.html"&gt;Quiz-playing
computer system could revolutionize research&lt;/a&gt;). What Bollen et al. are
proposing is a subset of the grander NLP problem, in that they are only
concerned with the "mood states" rather than the whole meaning of the
tweets. In other words, sentiment analysis. NLP is not new. R, for
example, has a &lt;a href="http://cran.r-project.org/web/views/NaturalLanguageProcessing.html"&gt;Natural Language Processing task view&lt;/a&gt;. Python has a
&lt;a href="http://www.nltk.org"&gt;Natural Language Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;. Wikipedia has a good &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_natural_language_processing_toolkits"&gt;list of NLP
toolkits&lt;/a&gt; for other languages. Traders understand that the market is
driven by people, and people are ultimately driven by emotions. So far,
there hasn't been a method to directly evaluate the emotions of market
participants. Would social media provide a glimpse to the emotions of
the masses? According to Bollen et al., yes. At any rate, data is king
in quantitative trading. I have no idea would their particular
implementation of data mining social media work or not. What's true is
that as more and more people publish their lives on the internet, all
these non-quantitative information are just waiting to be exploited.
Ethics and privacy issues aside, look at what Facebook is doing with
their ads as an example. In addition to time, volume, and price, data
mining social media may provide us with a fourth dimension to market
data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Natural Language Processing"></category></entry></feed>