<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/object-oriented_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-03-22T07:22:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>From Object Oriented Programming to Object Oriented Design</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/from-object-oriented-programming-to-object-oriented-design/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-22T07:22:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-22:from-object-oriented-programming-to-object-oriented-design/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The good news is that I have finished my data scraping module for
extracting all the company data listed on the two Toronto Stock
Exchanges (TSX and TSV). I presented an &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/"&gt;alpha version of this data
scraping module&lt;/a&gt; last week. I added the functionality to download all
the historical quotes from Yahoo for all the companies. These data are
stored locally in a cool HDF5 format with PyTables. I am very happy
about that part. The bad news is that my module looks more like a hacked
job than a piece of software. There is no defined structure for my
underlying codes. It is obvious to me that this module would be
difficult to extend, which is the whole point of my project. In
programming jargon, my &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_smell"&gt;code smells&lt;/a&gt; (Wikipedia). Then it finally
dawned on me. I am &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; behind in my programming skills. For the past
few years, my quant work has been confined to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/starting-to-use-matlab-for-quantitative-finance/"&gt;MatLab&lt;/a&gt; or some
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/4-automated-trading-development-platforms-for-beginner-to-advanced-traders/"&gt;proprietary trading platforms&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote scripts. Not programs. My
problem with programming is that I am still stuck in a procedural
programming mentality because that is what I've always used. Even though
I updated my knowledge recently by learning Python, learning to program
with an object oriented programming language is only the first step. (I
am also familiar with C++ and Java from way back) To use an analogy,
programming a software is like constructing a building. The actual
coding itself is akin to the construction work. I got that part. But
coding without a well designed plan can only go so far. It is now clear
to me that if I am to build the trading software to complement my
trading as I have envisioned it, I need to step it up with my &lt;em&gt;software
design&lt;/em&gt; ability. Consequently, I am now catching up on object oriented
design and analysis, as well as software design patterns with a couple
of books. I will try not to get too carried away with these though. My
main focus is trading. But this will be very beneficial for my trading
in the long run if I can build a more robust trading software that can
easily grow with my future needs. I have many big plans for this side
project of mine. I posted a UML diagram showing an &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/what-is-your-trading-process/"&gt;architectural
overview of my project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="object oriented"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry></feed>