<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/over-trading_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2009-12-08T09:57:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Focusing on trading my timeframe to reduce over-trading</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/focusing-on-trading-my-timeframe-to-reduce-over-trading/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-08T09:57:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-12-08:focusing-on-trading-my-timeframe-to-reduce-over-trading/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/november-2009-trading-performance-review/"&gt;last month's performance review&lt;/a&gt;, I said that one of my goals
for this month is to think more and trade less. But in my first week of
December, I have racked up 53 trades already... Average for October (a
normal month) was only 34, for the entire month. Now that we're in the
second week, I can clearly see my over-trading problem from my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trading
log&lt;/a&gt; and say to myself that enough is enough. In terms of my account
balance, I'm experiencing a 1% drawdown because of these
"testing-the-water" trades. They are small positions that I micro-manage
to minimize the exposed risks by moving the stops every so often. But
the facts speak for itself, 53 trades in the first week, 23 winning
trades (acceptable), 1 % drawdown (bad). The problem with this hit and
miss approach is that it is taking too much of my time with no result to
show. It's true that a single week makes no difference in the long run.
But this just isn't my style of trading. It doesn't fit with my trading
strategy. This is over-trading. Why do people over-trade? Lack of
discipline. Desire to catch major moves. Afraid to miss a run.
Addiction. Boredom. and so on. Over-trading has been a major problem for
me back in the days when I tried &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/day-trading-report-jan-30-2008-560/"&gt;day trading index futures&lt;/a&gt;. I
haven't had this problem for a couple of years now. Which is great. But
this bad habit is creeping back up on me. This time, it's because I am
staring at the trading screen too much once I am in a position and tried
to micro-manage my trades to minimize my risk. This obsession with
tightening my stops backfired and I took more trades because of it and
get stopped out more often before any sizable move can materialize. A
lose-lose situation. Since realizing that my arch-nemesis is back in
business, finding a solution to restrain myself is simple. I studied my
trading journal in the past few weeks to review my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/good-trade/"&gt;best trades&lt;/a&gt;. The
solution to improve my performance and restrain myself from over-trading
is actually both sides of the same coin. I just need to focus on trading
my best timeframe. What do I really mean by that? Different players and
factors affect different timeframes in the markets. Thus, prices behave
differently in different timeframes. &lt;a href="http://traderfeed.blogspot.com/"&gt;Dr. Steenbarger&lt;/a&gt; has an
excellent post titled &lt;a href="http://traderfeed.blogspot.com/2009/12/lessons-for-developing-traders-more-on.html"&gt;Lessons for Developing Traders: More on What
Moves Markets&lt;/a&gt; which talks about how different market participants
affects the way market's flow in different time frames. He uses the
analogy of visualizing the markets as an ocean. Global climate affects
the flow of waves across the ocean. At the same time, kids splashing at
a beach can also create ripples to these waves. Obviously, one is a
macro-phenomenon and the other is a localized event. Similarly, central
banks and institutions are what powers the long term trend of a market.
But market makers and retail traders can create ripples in the short
term. What works for one timeframe might not work for another. My
trading style has always been geared toward riding the bigger waves,
e.g. my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC setup&lt;/a&gt;. So if I become affixiated with what's happening
with the short-term ripples, it would not only cause me to over-trade
but also affect my long-term strategy too. As such, here is what I will
do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on analysis from the weekly and daily charts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-signal/"&gt;trading setup&lt;/a&gt; only from daily and 3 hour charts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time my entries and exits from the 3 hour chart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute my trade orders on the 30 minute chart and for short-term
    confirmation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the 1 hour chart if necessary to scaling in or out a position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never enter or exit a trade based on the 30 min. chart (or anything
    less) alone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I have started following this process this week already and it
seems to be working well. I will review my performance at the end of the
month &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/monthly-review"&gt;as usual&lt;/a&gt; to see how this goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="over-trading"></category></entry></feed>