<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/paper-trade_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-02-21T19:39:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed all CADJPY long @ 88.40 for +152 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-all-cadjpy-long-8840-for-152-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-21T19:39:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-21:paper-trade-closed-all-cadjpy-long-8840-for-152-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CAD/JPY reached my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-cadjpy-86-88-stop-86-10-target-88-0/"&gt;target of 88.00 last Friday&lt;/a&gt;. It broke through
88.00 nicely and tested 88.50 on Tokyo open just now. I decided to book
my profit in the demo account on this CAD/JPY long position entered at
86.88 and 87.87. See Figure 1 for the 3-hour chart with the entries and
exits marked. Main reason for my cold feet is that there's a lot of
resistance on CAD/JPY above 88.50, all the way to 90.70, from the daily
chart (not shown). I couldn't tell if CAD/JPY will continue pushing
upward or retrace. So I'm booking my profit now to observe the price
action from the sideline. This position has turned out +40 pips more
than I expected, so I'm trying not to be too greedy in this volatile
time. The net profit on this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper trade&lt;/a&gt; amounts to +0.3% of my demo
account. The yellow triangle in Figure 1 shows my exit. I risked 0.1% on
the initial entry (first blue triangle). Then added 70% more to the
position above a weak resistance level (second blue triangle) and moved
the stop on the initial size to breakeven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CAD/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-21-cadjpy_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Long CADJPY @ 86.88, Stop 86.10, Target 88.0</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-cadjpy-8688-stop-8610-target-880/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-17T21:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-17:paper-trade-long-cadjpy-8688-stop-8610-target-880/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I entered CADJPY long at market for 86.88 just now. This is a
continuation of my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-1-0540-for-131-pips/"&gt;previous USDCAD short&lt;/a&gt; position. However, USDJPY
is on a run upward so I'm switching to go long on the loonie with yen
instead. Figure 1 shows the daily chart of CADJPY. Notice the imminent
MACD bullish crossover and the already in-play stochastic upturn. I like
it. My stop loss level is set at 86.10. It's the high of a previous peak
on February 3, two weeks ago. My target is the round number 88
resistance. 88.0 has been an important price level for CADJPY for the
past few months. So I'm setting my sight there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CADJPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_d.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows my timing for this entry. CADJPY is noticeably meeting
some resistance at 87.50. 87.50 is also the 61.8% Fibonacci level of a
recent down move. This is a cause for concern on my long position as we
could very well retrace here. However, the bullishness of CADJPY is
apparent in Figure 2. Prices have consistently been bought for the past
few days right on the short term moving average (teal line).
Furthermore, the intermediate term moving average (orange line) is about
to cross the long term moving average (red line) as I enter this
position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, gold price has taken a dive from 1130 to 1100. Meanwhile, crude
oil price is holding the 77 support nicely. Thus, this confirm my
previous view that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-change-of-wind-for-australian-dollar-shorted-audusd-0-9183-and-audcad-0-9546/"&gt;oil has better upside than gold&lt;/a&gt; in the
intermediate term. Which is why I've been trading the loonie these past
weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this particular CADJPY trade, I have another buy order waiting above
current support level to add to my long position. Let's see if CADJPY
can break decisively to the upside in the next 24 hours as US and
Canadian data comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="CADJPY,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_4h.gif" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-17-cadjpy_4h.gif"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Stopped USDCAD short @ 1.0540 for +131 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-10540-for-131-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-15T09:23:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-15:paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-10540-for-131-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally a profitable trade in my USDCAD short after being stopped out a
few times. My decision last week to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/usdcad-short-target-hit-1-0581-trying-something-new-to-hold-for-longer/"&gt;hold this for longer&lt;/a&gt; after
USDCAD touched my target paid off. I moved my stop closer last Thursday
evening and the order got filled on Friday. However, as I type this on
the following Monday, USDCAD is trading even lower at 1.0478. It looks
as though my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;original target of 1.0415&lt;/a&gt; is in the cards. Even though
this is a profitable trade with a 0.17% gain in my demo account, there
is one major flaw with this short USDCAD play. I was not able to squeeze
more out of this profitable move. As I've said, this short took a few
tries. In fact, if we consider all the entires and exits of this play.
My stopped out losses totaled 0.29% and my single win here is merely
0.17%. So I'm actually at a net loss of 0.12% from all these work. My
win/loss rate is about 40% based on my review of recent forex trades. I
was able to edge out more than &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;10% profit in four months&lt;/a&gt; because
when I am wrong, I take small steps. But when I'm right, I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;pile into a
position&lt;/a&gt;. Ever since my trading environment has changed, I've been
trying to trade a longer timeframe. This USDCAD short is my first
attempt on a new strategy. Evidently, I will need to re-think and
re-learn what I've become accustomed to in the past few months. One of
the necessary trait of a successful trader is to be able to adapt.
Markets change. Traders need to evolve with the markets or they will
become obsolete. This will be a good test of myself to see if I can
re-invent myself to adapt to a changing trading environment. [caption
id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-13-USDCAD_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="CAD"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>USDCAD short target hit @ 1.0581, trying something new--to hold for longer</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/usdcad-short-target-hit-10581-trying-something-new-to-hold-for-longer/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-10T20:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-10:usdcad-short-target-hit-10581-trying-something-new-to-hold-for-longer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;USDCAD comes to a halt at 1.0581 today. My original target was 1.05761.
A mere 5 pips difference. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;This position&lt;/a&gt; is now +79 pips on paper. I
moved my stop to breakeven last night. Normally, I would have covered
most, if not all, of the position at this point. But I'll hold onto the
full amount this time. For now. Reasons are as follow. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USDCAD likes to grind out both bulls and bears at obvious levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;down move that I'm seeing&lt;/a&gt; is still in an early
    stage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My position is too small to be worthwhile if I take profit now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of my recent performance shows that I often don't ride my
    winners long enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I must learn to adopt a longer term strategy now that I [can't trade
    as often][].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, Figure 1 shows what I mean by #2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-10-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption] In fact, I intend to look for opportunities
to add to this position. As long as USDCAD stays below 1.0645, I'm
confident (not exactly the right word though) with this down move. From
this point onward, it's new territory for me as I push beyond my comfort
zone. Is this an ill-fated move or a spark of insight? Let me know what
you think about this extended trade. Update February 15: I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-1-0540-for-131-pips/"&gt;closed this
trade&lt;/a&gt; for +131 pips gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short USDCAD @ 1.0671, Stop 1.0756, Target 1.05761</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-10671-stop-10756-target-105761/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-09T18:56:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-09:paper-trade-short-usdcad-10671-stop-10756-target-105761/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Perhaps third times' the charm? I tried to short USDCAD twice last week
already. Both times I've been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-out-of-usdcad-short-1-0640-for-67-pips-re-entering-1-0680/"&gt;stopped out&lt;/a&gt; for a total of -0.2% of
account loss. My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;intermediate term analysis&lt;/a&gt; remains the same as
before. So I won't repeat myself here. Entry signal for this particular
short is shown in Figure 1. I'm just using the 4-hour chart as I have a
well defined (recent top) stop this time. I compensate with a smaller
position size to limit my risk to 0.1%. Reward / Risk = (1.05761 -
1.0671) / (1.0671 - 1.0756) = 1.11 [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="USD/CAD, 4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-09-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Stopped out of USDCAD short @ 1.0640 for -67 pips, re-entering @ 1.0680</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-out-of-usdcad-short-10640-for-67-pips-re-entering-10680/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-04T20:10:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-04:paper-trade-stopped-out-of-usdcad-short-10640-for-67-pips-re-entering-10680/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well this was awful. USDCAD continued on a rampage upward and I was
caught on the wrong side of the fence. Total loss for this was 0.12% of
my account. At least I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;was light in it&lt;/a&gt;. In retrospect, I broke my
own rule and didn't enter at one of the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/4-fundamental-entry-signs-for-trading-and-why-they-are-not-that-important/"&gt;4 fundamental entry points&lt;/a&gt;.
However, after some bear rampage throughout the markets today
(Bloomberg: [Stocks Plunge on Concern Rising Debt, Job Losses Threaten
Global Recovery][]), USDCAD is at the top of my channel as shown in
Figure 1 below. So while my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/4-fundamental-entry-signs-for-trading-and-why-they-are-not-that-important/"&gt;previous entry&lt;/a&gt;
was early. USDCAD at this price is a good short. I will take it slow
this time by setting a limit order below current support on the 4-hour
at 1.0680, with a stop at 1.0750. And then adding a second chunk at
1.0640, my stopped out price. As is customarily lately, I am only
risking 0.1% of my account on the initial order. On a weekly chart,
1.0750 to 1.0810 is obviously a strong resistance for the USDCAD. It is
a congestion zone in 2007 and 2008. Then USDCAD spent the last quarter
of 2009 trying to break this resistance to no avail. But who knows,
perhaps USDCAD has had enough and it will break this resistance
decisively soon. That's why I'm only betting on this reversal with
limited risk. It's just a matter of wait and see now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-04-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Stocks Plunge on Concern Rising Debt, Job Losses Threaten Global
  Recovery]: http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=20601087&amp;amp;sid=a8ajRZqBemfs&amp;amp;pos=1&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short USD/CAD @ 1.0573, Stop 1.0640, Target 1.0415</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-10573-stop-10640-target-10415/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-02T22:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-02:paper-trade-short-usdcad-10573-stop-10640-target-10415/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Taking a first position in USD/CAD short here at 1.0573 on a 4-hour
moving averages cross-over (Figure 1). I've also placed a limit order to
add more at 1.0519 below Fibonacci support (shown in Figure 1). Reason
for this trade is that USD/CAD is moving away from an upper bound
channel with a overbought stochastic reading, as shown in the daily
chart of Figure 2. I've also considered going long AUD/USD, but AUD/CAD
trend remains bearish. So I chose to short USD/CAD instead. Secondly,
crude oil (and gold too) looks to be bouncing off an oversold level with
a rapid move in 2 days from 72.43 to 77.39. Coincidentally, INO.com
posted an intermediate term &lt;a href="http://www.ino.com/info/513/CD4184/&amp;amp;dp=0&amp;amp;l=0&amp;amp;campaignid=3"&gt;cyclical analysis video with a bullish
outlook&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link). They put out a better case than I do.
USD/CAD might make a short-term upward bounce here because of a
short-term oversold condition. However, there's evidently a lack of
buyers in the past few hours (Fig. 1). The price has been sitting on
support a bit too long in my view. Thus, I'm expecting it to break
without a meaningful retracement (hence the short entry). A confirmation
would be a break below 1.0530. Thus I have a limit order to short more
below that price. I am risking 0.1% of my account on this trade. As you
may have noticed, these charts are from Metatrader. I'm switching over
to the MT4 platform as of today. Having played with its charting
features for the past few hours, I'm quite satisfied with it so far.
Although my needs are low as I was fine with the Oanda platform too
(arguably the most simplistic platform out there). [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USD/CAD,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-02-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="USD/CAD, daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-02-usdcad.gif" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-02-usdcad.gif"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: GBPJPY @ 145.24, Stop 144.70, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-28T21:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-28:paper-trade-gbpjpy-14524-stop-14470-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I've switched over to long EURJPY @ 125.40 as EURGBP's
downtrend seem to be running out of steam. Moreover, EURJPY looks better
on the daily chart with a clear support and an oversold reading. I'm
back in my long GBPJPY play at 145.24. The currency pair is breaking an
hourly resistance since consolidating around 145. I had a low ball offer
at 144.20 since &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;taking my profit last night at 146.42&lt;/a&gt;. But that bid
for never filled. So I'm re-entering on a short-term breakout. For this
entry, I am risking 0.1% of my account. This re-entry is a tough
decision. Almost all the respectable pros that I &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/Quantisan"&gt;follow on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
are on the other side of this trade via other currency pairs. However,
my long setup is valid as long as GBPJPY is above 144 level. So I'll
take this trade until proven otherwise. Although I must admit that my
confidence in this trade is very low. I also considered long CADJPY
instead as it seems to offer more upside potential. However, as I've
been following the GBPJPY pair this week, I'll stick with my plan. I
also have a limit order to add more at 145.81 as you can see in Figure 1
below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-28-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Closed GBPJPY @ 146.42 for +140 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-27T22:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-27:paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-14642-for-140-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just closed my GBPJPY long at 146.42 for around +140 pips average gain,
or 0.4% in the account balance. Damn good for a 24 hours holding. Obama
just finished his State of The Union address at the moment. I am not
impressed. Still all talk of change but nothing concrete yet. Anyway,
that's beside the point in this &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trade log&lt;/a&gt;. 146.50 price level for
GBPJPY is the 10 day moving average. It has also been a strong support
back in late December. This should be a good resistance level. My guess
is that GBPJPY should stall, or even retrace, here for a while. Thus I'm
taking profit at this price as shown in Figure 1 (yellow triangle). I
still believe my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-144-24-stop-143-60-target-148/"&gt;bullish setup from yesterday&lt;/a&gt; is still good. So I'll
be watching this pair for a re-entry. Update: I re-entered at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-gbpjpy-145-24-stop-144-70-target-148/"&gt;145.24
the next day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBPJPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-27-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exit"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper Trade: Long GBPJPY @ 144.24, Stop 143.60, Target 148</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-26T22:33:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-26:paper-trade-long-gbpjpy-14424-stop-14360-target-148/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My previous &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;short-side setup on GBP/JPY&lt;/a&gt; played out beautifully. Yet
I wasn't able to ride it down because I got stopped out on a stop-hunt
counter-move before the dive, see Fig. 1. Now that GBP/JPY has reached
its other end. I am betting for it to go reverse with a long position. I
expect this move to be more fierce with more upside potential as it's in
the direction of the long term up trend. Some people are calling the top
has been printed in the markets and the wind is now blowing the other
way. I am not one to guess what the market is about to do. So it's
business as usual until the trendline is broken. What I really like
about this setup is that GBP/JPY is testing a double trendline cross on
the weekly, Fig. 2. Secondly, the 3-hour chart of Figure 1 is showing a
RSI positive divergence on this test of the long term support. I am
quite confident of this setup. However, I am not confident about the
timing as GBP/JPY is known to be a wild horse and volatility could very
well stop me out, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-gbpjpy-146-32-target-143/"&gt;like last time&lt;/a&gt;. With
British preliminary GDP number coming out in about 6 hours, it might
have been wiser to wait until the after that to enter. On top of that,
the markets have been on a stall for the last few days waiting for data
in the next 48 hours. End-of-week volatility this week is expected to be
significant. Anyway, I've put in a position already and will just let it
run. This a small initial position with 0.1% of my account at risk. I
have also placed limit orders above resistances to add to this position.
We'll how this turns out soon enough. Lastly, even though I said I've
been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/barred-from-trading-at-work-a-curse-or-a-gift/"&gt;cut off from trading at my day job&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn't mean I'm
completely out of the game. I just have to adapt my manual trading
strategy while my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/quantitative-finance/systems/"&gt;automated system&lt;/a&gt; is still in development.
Basically meaning that I'll trade with a slower timeframe for
longer-term moves. All the better, as longer term moves are generally
less deceptive. Update: I closed this at &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-closed-gbpjpy-146-42-for-140-pips/"&gt;146.42 for +140 pips gain&lt;/a&gt;
the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="GBP/JPY,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="GBP/JPY, weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-01-26-GBPJPY_wk.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="long"></category><category term="paper trade"></category></entry></feed>