<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/pmvv_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-01-20T11:28:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Bought 1000 PMV.VN @ 0.62</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-1000-pmvvn-062/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-20T11:28:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-01-20:bought-1000-pmvvn-062/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 26:&lt;/strong&gt; The share price of PMV.V crossed my mental stop
yesterday so I had to reassess the position. I sold my shares at \$0.56
for a loss of (\$0.56 - \$0.62) * 1000 = \$70 + \$19.90 commission =
\$89.90 = 0.9% of account. Gold is falling while USD tanked this week.
The lack of volume on today's goldminers rally is also uncharacteristic
of the recent uptrend. The long term uptrend of gold and gold miners is
unmistakable on both fundamental and technical basis. I am taking a
dabble in this junior gold miner as its share price is making a gap fill
on a recent breakout (Fig. 1), amongst other things. Intraday chart
(Fig. 2) is also showing signs of life at this support level. What's
going to happen to gold as it breaks below 1350 (first time since
November) from worries about Chinese inflation, which led to strength in
USD (on fear of further Chinese tightening) as EURUSD dropped 60 pips in
2 hours. See FT: &lt;a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ab89d906-244e-11e0-a89a-00144feab49a.html"&gt;Fears grow that China is overheating&lt;/a&gt;. Couple that
with political and economic uncertainty, we have a short term
uncertainty in gold's direction. However, all these is in line with the
underlying gold-bug case that money is becoming more worthless as
governments pump in money to their respective economies. Another point
to note is that as the Shanghai Composite and Bombay Stock Exchange
(i.e. growth markets) are making 3-month lows in recent weeks, people
will start to look for other assets to diversify their wealth. This is
all conjectures anyway. I can't predict the future.I am merely placing
my bet as the stars seem to have aligned for me to increase the
probability of this good reward/risk trade. Mental stop is \$0.55. Hard
stop is \$0.48, however, I'll give it some margin and say 0.40 is my
stop as liquidity is thin in this junior. Thus, risk is (\$0.62 -
\$0.40) * 1000 = \$220 + \$9.95 commission = \$229.95 = 2.4% of
account. Note: You might have noticed that my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;trade log&lt;/a&gt; style has
changed for 2011. I am trying to jot down my thought process rather than
the data analysis and numerical logic to better capture my &lt;em&gt;thinking&lt;/em&gt;
for the record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="PMI Gold Corp.
(PMV.V)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2011-01-20-PMV.V.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="PMI Gold Corp. (PMV.V)
intraday"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2011-01-20-PMV.V-intra.gif" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2011-01-20-PMV.V-intra.gif"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="gold"></category><category term="Mining"></category><category term="PMV.V"></category><category term="RRSP"></category></entry></feed>