<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/programming_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-04-14T07:28:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Comparing Trading API from 6 Online Forex Brokerages</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/comparing-trading-api-from-6-online-forex-brokerages/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-14T07:28:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-04-14:comparing-trading-api-from-6-online-forex-brokerages/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Choosing a discount broker for forex trading is time consuming. As the
forex market is not centralized, choosing a discount broker is sort of
like picking a stall in a farmer's market. They all offer the same
product, but prices, features, quality, and services can vary
considerably between fx brokerages. One criteria that I consider
seriously is the Application Programming Interface (API) offered by the
broker. Most people couldn't care less about API because they never
intend to develop their own automated trading program. However, if this
is something that interests you, then I'd like to save you some time
here with the following table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Forex brokers
API table"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-04-13-FX_API_table.png" /&gt;][][/caption] All the dollar values are in U.S. dollar.
I highlighted the important limitation of each API. I have different
level of experience with each of these six APIs. As of this writing, I
am using &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/jforex/"&gt;JForex&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="http://www.dukascopy.com/ibentry.php?ibref=1143/"&gt;Dukascopy&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/in-a-forex-brokers-and-trading-platforms-jumble/"&gt;various personal reasons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="API"></category><category term="broker"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>From Object Oriented Programming to Object Oriented Design</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/from-object-oriented-programming-to-object-oriented-design/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-22T07:22:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-22:from-object-oriented-programming-to-object-oriented-design/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The good news is that I have finished my data scraping module for
extracting all the company data listed on the two Toronto Stock
Exchanges (TSX and TSV). I presented an &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/"&gt;alpha version of this data
scraping module&lt;/a&gt; last week. I added the functionality to download all
the historical quotes from Yahoo for all the companies. These data are
stored locally in a cool HDF5 format with PyTables. I am very happy
about that part. The bad news is that my module looks more like a hacked
job than a piece of software. There is no defined structure for my
underlying codes. It is obvious to me that this module would be
difficult to extend, which is the whole point of my project. In
programming jargon, my &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_smell"&gt;code smells&lt;/a&gt; (Wikipedia). Then it finally
dawned on me. I am &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; behind in my programming skills. For the past
few years, my quant work has been confined to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/starting-to-use-matlab-for-quantitative-finance/"&gt;MatLab&lt;/a&gt; or some
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/4-automated-trading-development-platforms-for-beginner-to-advanced-traders/"&gt;proprietary trading platforms&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote scripts. Not programs. My
problem with programming is that I am still stuck in a procedural
programming mentality because that is what I've always used. Even though
I updated my knowledge recently by learning Python, learning to program
with an object oriented programming language is only the first step. (I
am also familiar with C++ and Java from way back) To use an analogy,
programming a software is like constructing a building. The actual
coding itself is akin to the construction work. I got that part. But
coding without a well designed plan can only go so far. It is now clear
to me that if I am to build the trading software to complement my
trading as I have envisioned it, I need to step it up with my &lt;em&gt;software
design&lt;/em&gt; ability. Consequently, I am now catching up on object oriented
design and analysis, as well as software design patterns with a couple
of books. I will try not to get too carried away with these though. My
main focus is trading. But this will be very beneficial for my trading
in the long run if I can build a more robust trading software that can
easily grow with my future needs. I have many big plans for this side
project of mine. I posted a UML diagram showing an &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/what-is-your-trading-process/"&gt;architectural
overview of my project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="object oriented"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>A sign that you are truly enjoying what you do</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/a-sign-that-you-are-truly-enjoying-what-you-do/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-15T07:10:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-15:a-sign-that-you-are-truly-enjoying-what-you-do/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When was the last time that you were working on something and you were
so immersed in it that you have forgotten about the hours that gone by?
That feeling of timelessness while doing something for hours. Not the
type that you're stressed and feel that you don't have enough time to do
a job. I am talking about the other kind of feeling. The positive one.
The feeling that is serene and content. If you know what I'm talking
about, then congratulations! You have found what you're born to do.
There are a handful of activities that I am passionate about. I
sometimes get that zen-like feeling when I am cycling through a mountain
path or snowboarding down a hill. But what I truly like to do is problem
solving. In particular, I find that programming quantitative trading
systems is a perfect outlet for this side of my personality. Programming
is one of the few ways in which you can create something out of nothing.
Very much like a composer or a poet. But unlike those trades, you can
solve practical problems with just your sheer mental capacity by
programming your thoughts into codes. To problem solve, you also need a
source of inspiration. And what better field can there be than the
capital markets. It is basically an ever-changing chess game in which
you are playing against the entire world. Talk about setting a bar high.
As you may have read, I've run into a few &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/what-to-do-when-life-gets-in-your-way-of-trading/"&gt;obstacles with my trading&lt;/a&gt;
lately. I need to develop a new trading program to let me regain my
edge. So I got up early this Saturday to program &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/"&gt;my new trading software&lt;/a&gt;. Next thing I know, it was 4pm already. It was a blissful
day. And that, is my reason for wanting to trade for a living.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="programming"></category><category term="trading for a living"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I am not a big fan of MQL4 or trading platform scripting</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/why-i-am-not-a-big-fan-of-mql4-or-trading-platform-scripting/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-08T13:38:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-08:why-i-am-not-a-big-fan-of-mql4-or-trading-platform-scripting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent most of 2008 trading futures and developing automated systems on
Tradestation. The futures trading didn't turn out so well as I lost 40%
of my account and had to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/retirement-from-futures-trading-and-back-to-stocks/"&gt;call it quit&lt;/a&gt;. My quant development work on
the other hand, was coming along slow but steadily. However, since I
couldn't bear the monstrous maintenance fee anymore at &lt;a href="http://www.tradestation.com/"&gt;Tradestation&lt;/a&gt;,
I had to abandon that work. Then last year &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-thoughts-and-goals-on-automated-trading-a-year-later/"&gt;when I wanted to pick up
where I left off&lt;/a&gt; on Matlab, I found that I couldn't just continue my
work. For one, I've lost most of my files. I think I left them in my
other computer in Hong Kong. Which is probably in a landfill by now.
Secondly, I didn't keep a thorough journal &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/2008/"&gt;back then in 2008&lt;/a&gt; like
I'm doing now. Lastly, from the important files that I've kept, I didn't
bother to convert the codes because I might as well write new ones from
scratch than figure out what I did. The reason why I am reminiscing at
the moment is because I am finding myself in the same cycle again. As
regular readers may be aware, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/what-to-do-when-life-gets-in-your-way-of-trading/"&gt;recent events&lt;/a&gt; have accelerated my
quant projects schedule. I am experimenting with using Metatrader 4 for
my foreign exchange trading and scripting in MQL4 for automated trading.
Like Tradestation, &lt;a href="http://www.metaquotes.net/en/metatrader4"&gt;Metatrader 4&lt;/a&gt; is a trading platform with scripting
capabilities. Its programming language, MQL4, is a proprietary language
based on C. I took a few hours this weekend to learn it (as I'm familiar
with C already). So that I can start coding this week. However, after
giving it more thought, I've decided to scale down on my projects with
MQL4. I don't want to rely on a proprietary system for short-term
convenience. As trading programmers know, the language used is merely a
choice. Experience tells me that the bulk of development time is not
spent on the actual programming itself. Rather, much of the time is
spent on formulating, analyzing, and optimizing your algorithm. So I
might as well bite the bullet to build from scratch my automated trading
systems and quant analytics on one platform (i.e. on Python). That has
been my long term plan all along. Everything under one roof. But I
digressed. Then there's the issue of re-useability. Metatrader 4 is
forex-only and only works with brokers that support it. As such, I would
have to use something else for stock trading. Even for a forex-only
system, it would help if I can do intermarket analysis quantitatively.
That's not possible as far as I know with MQL4. Which is another major
downside for me. To summarize other reasons on how I came about this
decision, here are the advantages and disadvantages of using MQL4 versus
using a general programming language, such as Python or C++. The
advantages of using MQL4 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saves A LOT of development time as it's already built for trading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charting, manual and automated trading on one platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the popular C programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many forex traders use it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large repertoire of forex-specific programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disadvantages of using MQL4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not for real quant analysis or data mining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited to MT4-supported brokers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forex trading only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proprietary programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must run on Metatrader 4 client terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MQL5 coming soon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is certainly a tough choice. Judging by the huge user base, it's
evident that many people are satisfied with MQL4. Yet, as I've discussed
here, there are downsides to using it (besides technical matters). My
current plan remains the same as what I said in &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/january-2010-trading-performance-review/"&gt;my last month's trading
review&lt;/a&gt;. That is, I will use MQL4 to plug holes in my trading system
for now before migrating to build my own system. In fact, I am already
brewing my first expert advisor starting today. Perhaps I might even
have something to post by the end of this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EasyLanguage"></category><category term="MQL4"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry></feed>