<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/quantisan-systems_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-03-14T14:34:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Today is day 1 of Quantisan, the company</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/today-is-day-1-of-quantisan-the-company/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-14T14:34:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-03-14:today-is-day-1-of-quantisan-the-company/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
&gt; The reasonable man adapts himself to the world: the unreasonable one
&gt; persists in trying to adapt the world to himself. Therefore all
&gt; progress depends on the unreasonable man. G. B. Shaw, *Maxims for
&gt; Revolutionists*

While cramming for the CFA level 1 exam the past 3 weeks, I can't let go
of the fact that I'm leaving my work out cold on the table. This sense
of urgency feels like every minute that I delay my trading system
development projects, bits of them will fall apart. This weekend I
finished reading through my Schweser study notes from cover to cover, to
cover to cover, and repeat that 3 more times for a total of 5 books.
It's certainly useful and interesting material. But I can't see the
value of cramming for 3 more months to memorize everything in even more
excruciating detail. No term will be without a definition in my head and
no problem will be without a solution on my BA II Plus calculator. Just
so I can say that I passed my level 1 exam on my resume. What the
curriculum offers is information, but what we need more in this world is
wisdom. I stand by my belief that [credibility is as important as
experience and skills][]. However, that doesn't mean that I need to head
for the path most traveled. Why can't I be unreasonable and push my
limit to do what I've always been set out to do. Credibility can be
gained from attaching professional designations to your name, but it can
also be gained from simply achieving results in the real world. So this
morning, before going to work, I took the first baby step in turning
this little hobby of mine into a real business. I registered a business
entity with our government. After 10 years of [trading][], 5 years
[blogging about the market][], and 3 years in [trading system
development][], today is day 1 of Quantisan Systems! And this -- is how
my business got officially started. My plan towards [unreasonable
goals][] in a world of reasons is finally set in motion.

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CFA"></category><category term="Quantisan Systems"></category></entry></feed>