<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/recovery_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-01-13T14:18:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Work harder, trade fewer in a long and excruciating trading drawdown</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/work-harder-trade-fewer-in-a-long-and-excruciating-trading-drawdown/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-13T14:18:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-01-13:work-harder-trade-fewer-in-a-long-and-excruciating-trading-drawdown/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I write this as I am in my [first trading drawdown of 2010][]. As I said
[previously][first trading drawdown of 2010], I find that I am still
ill-trained to respond to big drawdowns. I caught myself over trading
again hoping to rake in a few quick paper bucks in my demo account to
get myself out. However, the ability to maintain discipline and
performance under stress is what separate the pros from newbies like me.
I know what I must do at the back of my head but I took the easy way.
This trading drawdown is definitely bringing the worst trader in me. As
Dr. Steenbarger wrote in his post on [Stress and Performance in
Trading][],

&gt; "... one reason stress might affect performance among traders is by
&gt; skewing their assessments of risk and reward. Under pressure, traders
&gt; may narrow their cognitive scope to only the information most salient
&gt; to them (availability bias) or relevant to their expectations
&gt; (confirmation bias); focus only on superficial qualities of
&gt; observations (representativeness heuristic); or become more likely to
&gt; take profits than losses (disposition effect). In other words, stress
&gt; disrupts performance by altering normal, sound information
&gt; processing."

In addition to a narrowed mindset, the cause of my bad habit to over
trade during a big drawdown is that I subconciously associate the need
to recover my account balance with the need to trade. Nothing will
happen if you don't trade, right? Well, at least you won't lose anymore
than you have. That would have been a good start. So I considered to
ease back on trading by focusing on [my quant work][]. Then I realized
this is yet another misconception. I was merely walking away from my
problem. What I needed to do is to face it, not with mindless trading
though. **During a stressful drawdown, work harder and think plenty
about the market, *not* about recovering from your drawdown**. In the
mean time, only trade your best strategy to reap the best probability of
profits. At the end of the day, nobody can dig yourself out of an
account drawdown but you. Something must have been wrong with your
trading or your current perception of the market to get you in a
drawdown. Or, it could very well be just plain old bad luck. In any
case, take a step back from trading and use the opportunity to realign
yourself with the market or wait for market conditions to sync back with
you. This is a forgotten lesson that I have wrote about in a [previous
drawdown][]. I have since added an additional section in my [trading
rules][] to impose it upon myself with this re-ocurring problem. I can
never get rid of large drawdowns completely because they are a regular
part of trading. This particular one has been a great self-discovering
experience. Ultimately, learning to cope with trading under stress is
one of my top training priorities to achieve before moving on to trading
a live account with real money.

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="drawdown"></category><category term="recovery"></category></entry><entry><title>An example of how trading in fear is bad for your account</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-example-of-how-trading-in-fear-is-bad-for-your-account/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-18T19:25:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-11-18:an-example-of-how-trading-in-fear-is-bad-for-your-account/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having had &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-bad-eurusd-day-trading-and-what-to-do-about-it/"&gt;a hard time day trading the EUR/USD last week&lt;/a&gt;, things
haven't been well for me this week either with the market in a gridlock.
My one and only viable setup so far is &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftcs/"&gt;built for a trending market&lt;/a&gt;.
So this range-bound market is new territory for me as I experiment (in
hindsight, haphazardly) to come up with more profitable forex trading
setups. As you can imagine, trading without discipline is a recipe for
diaster. I have given back all the paper gain from this month by the
start of this week and is treading on thin ice with my demo account
dipping dangerously close to the November opening balance. Needless to
say, I do not want to see my account in the red for this month. But that
is what happened after today's string of failed trades. I am officially
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;in the red for this month&lt;/a&gt;, for now. While there are several mistakes
I made resulting in this mess, I think it all boils down to one flaw in
my trading this week. Yes, those day trading stints I did surely have
put a dent in my demo account, but what's worse is that I've
unconsciously have let those losses affect my trading mentality. These
losses were stuck in my mind and my mental "goal" for this week was
recovering from them. However, I have approached the problem in the
wrong way by not wanting to lose anymore in my account. In other words,
I was afraid of losing. So how did that materially affect my trading?
Here is a simple example as illustrated in my order history on the
GBP/JPY chart attached at the bottom of this post. The 3 yellow
triangles are my short entries and the 3 red dots marks the stopped
exits. According to my setup, my original entry at 149.50 had a stop at
150.50. But I moved my stop closer to 149.80 in the morning because I
didn't want to risk more. That got taken out easily as 149.80 is within
the congestion zone. Then I tried to short it a couple more times with
tight stops because I see the downside potential to be still intact.
Those were eaten up alive too and now I don't have a position because it
would have been more foolish to keep trying in vain. While just 3 trades
wouldn't have done much damage, I was doing the same thing across the
board in shorting CAD/JPY and EUR/CAD. A few here and a few there. They
add up to a bad day. As of this writing, it looks like these pairs are
finally moving in my direction. But instead of being patient with
reasonable stops, I thought I could do better and micro-managed my
positions to end up taking multiple small losses and with nothing left
on the table to ride the move. So what is the correct way of following
up on a dent in the account? I should have done the following instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce risk exposure by limiting trade size or overall opened
    positions until I am back up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on what I did wrong last week and stop doing that, i.e. no
    more day trading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recall my best trades and do more of that, i.e. my one and only
    finalized setup, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/an-introduction-to-my-forex-trend-continuation-setup-ftc/"&gt;FTC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so coincidentally, now that I'm in the deepest drawdown ever, this
is as good as ever to put this emergency recovery procedure into
practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="GBP/JPY,
1-hour"][&lt;img alt="GBP/JPY, 1-hour" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-GBPJPY_1h.PNG" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2009-11-18-GBPJPY_1h.PNG"&gt;GBP/JPY, 1-hour&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="drawdown"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="recovery"></category></entry></feed>