<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/scsc_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2009-04-29T21:29:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>BOUGHT +50 SCSC @23.52</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-50-scsc-2352/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-29T21:29:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-04-29:bought-50-scsc-2352/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I placed &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/huge-opening-swing-with-scsc-after-earnings-report/"&gt;my stop at \$22.70 as planned&lt;/a&gt; today and it was triggered at
10:41 am. The exit price ended up at \$23.52 from a quick run. But SCSC
further pushed along and closed at \$24.14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should have noticed from the 200 week MA that SCSC has been pretty
strong lately. I should have only entered when the long term trend is in
sync with my position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after running through a few more charts, it seems that my stock
filter is giving a contrarian indication. There's still a lot of work to
do to develop this new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1329" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="ScanSource"]&lt;img alt="ScanSource" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-29-scsc.png" title="2009-04-29-scsc" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exit"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="scsc"></category></entry><entry><title>Huge opening swing with SCSC after earnings report</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/huge-opening-swing-with-scsc-after-earnings-report/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-24T21:32:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-04-24:huge-opening-swing-with-scsc-after-earnings-report/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As title says, ScanSource (SCSC) had a huge 20% swing at the open today.
SCSC released an earnings report yesterday at the close. I don't really
care what they said, but we actually broke above my stop at \$22.70
briefly at the open. Although my stop order didn't get filled. Then SCSC
just drifted ever so slightly downward thoughout the day. Remember, the
market climbed back to 870 today, so this is suppose to be a bullish
day. This is definitely a weakness on SCSC. The waiting game continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1311" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="ScanSource (1 minute chart for
today)"]&lt;img alt="ScanSource" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-24-scsc_prop.png" title="2009-04-24-scsc_prop" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="scsc"></category></entry><entry><title>SCSC short entry stop $21.40, buy exit stop at $22.70</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/scsc-short-entry-stop-2140-buy-exit-stop-at-2270/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-22T21:01:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-04-22:scsc-short-entry-stop-2140-buy-exit-stop-at-2270/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am experimenting with a new trading strategy. This is a log for a
&lt;strong&gt;paper trade&lt;/strong&gt; I'm taking using this strategy for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new stock filter as part of this new strategy generated a list of
stocks yesterday based on options volatility. Then I hand picked
ScanSource (SCSC) in particular to watch today as it looked to be
forming a basic setup where I can recognize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, the signal is for short. So this is a setup for a short
entry. Following my newly etched 3 rules, I'm not jumping in with a
market order. Instead, I'll be setting up a short entry stop and
attaching it with an exit stop on the order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/end-of-the-6-week-rally-and-back-with-the-year-long-beartoday/"&gt;Monday's epic dive&lt;/a&gt; and Tuesday's rebound, the market has
closed below 845 on Wednesday. In particular, the late day dive is
looking good for the bear. Let's see if we can break below 835 tomorrow.
In any case, I don't want to digress into a market analysis here. Just
note that for the short and intermediate terms, the market seem to be
going down. Thus, I'm looking for shorting opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to SCSC. Notice the negative divergence on the daily and weekly
indicators. Also notice that \$22.70 is a long term resistance from last
October. Thus, I'm setting a stop at \$22.70 for this trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, when should I enter? I have given the entry more leeway since
we're in a choppy market. Also, I would like to enter at an obvious
point when the stock is starting to tank. So there's a higher
probability of success. I chose the entry stop at \$21.40. It is the top
for a previous run-up on April 3. See figure 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My target is marked on Figure 2 at \$18.50. It was a major support for
January and February before the run down into the abyss for SCSC. Also,
I took into account the Stochastic information. SCSC has been in an
overbought level on the daily for almost a month now (along with the
rest of the market). The previous support point according to the
stochastic was in early February, which had a range around \$18 to \$20.
Furthermore, \$18.30 is the 50% Fibonacci retracement level if we're to
go down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risk taken for this trade is \$22.7 - \$21.4 = \$1.30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reward is \$21.4 - \$18.5 = \$2.90&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reward/Risk = 2.23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 2.23, the reward/risk isn't that good. I would like to aim for at
least a 3-fold return. However, I'll let this go this time because I'm
only experimenting with this strategy. So I just want to see how it goes
and learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've set my &lt;strong&gt;simulated order&lt;/strong&gt; to be submitted after 10am tomorrow for
50 shares (about \$1000 paper money). We'll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: The short entry stop order executed at 10:01:59 am and shorted
50 shares of SCSC at \$21.36, simulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1290" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="ScanSource (daily left, weekly right)"]&lt;img alt="ScanSource (daily
left, weekly right)" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-22-scsc_weekly.png" title="2009-04-22-scsc_weekly" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1288" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="ScanSource (hourly left, daily
right)"]&lt;img alt="ScanSource" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-22-scsc.png" title="2009-04-22-scsc" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="scsc"></category></entry></feed>