<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/td_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-03-30T09:25:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>TD Bank making headlines with a new all-time high</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/td-bank-making-headlines-with-a-new-all-time-high/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-30T09:25:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-30:td-bank-making-headlines-with-a-new-all-time-high/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A bank making an all-time high! Another reason not to short this market
&lt;em&gt;just yet&lt;/em&gt;. However, the fact this made the news is a tempting short
prospect. I just saw TD Bank making &lt;a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/blogs/streetwise/td-bank-stock-hits-new-record/article1516929/"&gt;the headline today on Globe and
Mail&lt;/a&gt;. TD.TO is running away from the pack. See Figure 1 on TD.TO
versus TSX Financial Index. TD is trending bullishly away from the rest
of the banks gradually since end of 2007. Why? I have no idea as I don't
follow it. Moreover, TD is making a bullish dead cross (50 over 200
moving averages) on the weekly chart of Figure 2 (marked with circle).
That is very bullish indeed. Nevertheless, there is an obvious long-term
negative divergence as TD is making a new high as shown in Figure 2.
Secondly, if you observe Figure 1 again, you will see that TD/SPTFS is
testing a strong resistance. There is evidently a conflict between the
bulls and bears. Price is telling one story and the indicators are
telling another. Either way, this stock will be a good one to watch.
Patience on the short for now... I am hunting to short something in the
energy sector. No shorting Canadian financials for me. I am not crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TD Bank / TSX
Financial Index"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-30-TD-SPTFS.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="TD Bank"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-30-TD.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-30-TD.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="TD"></category></entry></feed>