<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/tsx-venture_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-03-11T07:29:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Data Scraping the Toronto Stock Exchange: Extracting 3,660 companies' data</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-11T07:29:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-11:data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the tasks that I've always wanted to make more efficient in my
stock trading is the work of scanning for stocks to trade. One look at
my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;trading strategy posts&lt;/a&gt; and you'll see that I have devised many
stock scanning systems in the past few years. The most recent system
that I've used is one that uses &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/week-of-sept-13-2009-in-play-stocks-breakout-results/"&gt;options data to filter stocks&lt;/a&gt;.
However, it is not automated. So it takes a lot of time to gather and
analyze the data. Furthermore, the set of tools that I use is limited to
U.S. stocks. Now that I have taken an interest in the Canadian stock
market, I can't seem to find any public tool that I like. Thus, I am
biting the bullet now and taking my time to develop a custom system once
and for all. Before we can analyze stock data, we need to extract them
first. Where better else for that than go straight to the source at
TMX.com, the parent company of Toronto Stock Exchange (TSX) and TSX
Venture Exchange (TSXV). TMX.com provide a list of publicly traded
companies in ten Excel files. The files are divided by sectors. Each
contain a number of fundamental company data, such as market
capitalization and outstanding shares. So step 1 is to extract those
data. This is where I am at now. I attached the source code for an
alpha/developmental release below for anyone interested. It is a working
program to scrape the data from TMX.com's files. But it's still a
work-in-progress. That's why I am calling it a version 0.1. The next
milestone is to program a Stocks class to hold, organize, and manage all
three thousand, six hundred, and sixty companies' data. This is an easy
task to do by extending the built-in dictionary class in Python.
However, I haven't gotten to that chapter yet in my scientific
programming with Python learning book. I stopped at chapter 8 to work on
this project. Chapter 9 is the inheritence and hierarchical material.
The goal of this project is to build an automated data scraping program
for TSX and TSXV data from various sources into my computer. Once I have
my data, that's when the real fun starts. Regarding the code below, I
know that source code is useless for most people. Once the project is
complete, I will compile the code into a standalone application and post
it on this site. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/feed/"&gt;Subscribe to my RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; so that you can keep
up-to-date with the progress of this project and my other ramblings on
trading. [python] # extractTMX.py # version: 0.1 alpha release #
revision date: March, 2010 # by Paul, Quantisan.com """A data scraping
module to extract company listing excel files from TMX.COM""" import
xlrd # to read Excel file #import sys from finClasses import Stock #
custom Stock class def _verify(): """Verification function for a
rundown of the module""" pass # copy test block here when finished def
findCol(sheet, key): """Find the column corresponding to header string
'key'""" firstRow = sheet.row_values(0) for col in
range(len(firstRow)): if key in firstRow[col]: return col # return
first sighting else: # not found raise ValueError("%s is not found!" %
key) def scrapeXLS(book): """Data scraping function for TMX Excel
file""" listingDict = {} # dict of ('ticker': market cap) for index in
range(book.nsheets): sh = book.sheet_by_index(index) mcCol =
findCol(sh, "Market Value") assert type(mcCol) is int, "mcCol is a %s" %
type(mcCol) osCol = findCol(sh, "O/S Shares") assert type(osCol) is int,
"osCol is a %s" % type(osCol) secCol = findCol(sh, "Sector") # multiple
matches but taking first assert type(secCol) is int, "secCol is a %s" %
type(secCol) hqCol = findCol(sh, "HQ\nRegion") assert type(hqCol) is
int, "hqCol is a %s" % type(hqCol) for rx in range(1, sh.nrows): sym =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=4)) # symbol s =
sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=2) # exchange col. if s == "TSX": exch =
"T" elif s == "TSXV": exch = "V" else: raise TypeError("Unknown exchange
value") mc = sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=mcCol) # market cap # check
for empty market cap cell mc = int(mc) if type(mc) is float else 0 os =
int(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=osCol)) # O/S shares sec =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=secCol)) # sector hq =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=hqCol)) # HQ region listingDict[sym] =
Stock(symbol=sym,exchange=exch, mktCap=mc,osShares=os,
sector=sec,hqRegion=hq) return listingDict def fetchFiles(fname): infile
= open(fname, 'r') # text file of XLS file names listing = {} for line
in infile: # 1 file name per line if line[0] == '#': continue # skip
commented lines line = line.strip() # strip trailing \n print "Reading
'%s' ..." % line xlsFile = "TMX/" + line # in TMX directory book =
xlrd.open_workbook(xlsFile) # import Excel file
listing.update(scrapeXLS(book)) # append scraped the data to dict
return listing #if __name__ == '__main__': # verify block #
if len(sys.argv) == 2 and sys.argv[1] == 'verify': # _verify() if
__name__ == '__main__': # test block listing =
fetchFiles('TMX/TMXfiles.txt') [/python]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="data scraping"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="source code"></category><category term="TSX"></category><category term="TSX Venture"></category></entry><entry><title>Another reason against stocking into a registered trading account this year</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-reason-against-stocking-into-a-registered-trading-account-this-year/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-05T07:32:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-05:another-reason-against-stocking-into-a-registered-trading-account-this-year/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's another reason why I am so &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/is-a-5000-questrade-tfsa-trading-account-cost-effective-part-1/"&gt;reluctant to put money into a TFSA
trading account&lt;/a&gt; to invest in Canadian stocks. As you know, in a
registered trading account, such as a RRSP self-directed trading account
or a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;Questrade TFSA trading account&lt;/a&gt; (aff), you cannot short shares
and can only buy because you can't trade on margin. As such, a
registered trading account is an account for buy-only trading. It
doesn't take a genius to figure out that a buy-only trading strategy is
best used ... in a bull market. As trading wisdom goes, trade with the
trend. So the question is, are we in a bull market in 2010? Figures 1
and 2 shows the weekly chart of TSX Index and the TSX Venture Index,
respectively. Referring to Fig. 1, TSX is bumping up against some
headwind at a 12,000 resistance. Unless TSX can stay above 12,000
cleanly (a weekly low above that level at least), I am still bearish in
the market because that financial crisis back in 2008 (&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-breakdown-of-a-major-multi-year-support-are-we-going-down-and-i-mean-really-down/"&gt;remember those
days&lt;/a&gt;?) is still overshadowing long term prices and trader sentiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-TSX_wk.png" /&gt;][][/caption] TSX Venture is depressed even more as seen
in Figure 2 below. Just look at the huge gap from current price to the
200 week moving average (red line). This isn't a good sign as lack of
interest in high-risk stocks means traders are generally cautious. Yes,
it's true that the equity market has been running up, up, and up for a
good year. However, the fact that TSX is sitting at the same level as in
2001 proves that the long term, multi-year bull market has been cleanly
broken. We might very well see pockets of multi-month rallies
materialize (like we're seeing now), but unless proven otherwise, the
long term trend is not looking green for the markets. It will not be
easy money in the stock market like back in the pre-tech bubble 1990's.
As opined by Bill Cara, the &lt;a href="http://www.caracommunity.com/"&gt;time for buy-and-hold is gone&lt;/a&gt;. It is
well known in the community that the coming years will be volatile with
big ups and downs. That is my little secret for moving to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;trade
forex&lt;/a&gt;last year and the main reason why I am reluctant to set aside
money on a one-sided stock trading account. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX Venture,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-CDNX_wk.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-CDNX_wk.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="TSX"></category><category term="TSX Venture"></category></entry></feed>