<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/tsx_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-10-13T14:21:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Three obvious reasons to watch 13,000 on the TSX</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/three-obvious-reasons-to-watch-13000-on-the-tsx/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-13T14:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-10-13:three-obvious-reasons-to-watch-13000-on-the-tsx/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Talks of QE2 (WSJ: &lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/source/2010/10/13/qe2-or-titanic/"&gt;QE2 or Titanic&lt;/a&gt; and Econbrowser: &lt;a href="http://www.econbrowser.com/archives/2010/10/why_is_the_fed.html"&gt;Why is the Fed
doing this?&lt;/a&gt;) and earnings season are pushing the market higher and
higher. Gold is still pushing to new all time high and the dollar is
breaking to new lows. The TSX, in particular, is testing 12,700 today.
13,000 is just around the corner. 13,000 price level is the line in the
sand for the commodity-heavy TSX for three obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It marks the breakdown support level back in the 2008 crash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the bottom of a prolonged congestion zone in much of 2007 and
    2008 before that crash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And most importantly, #1 and #2 are very easy to spot on the chart
    (potentially self-fulfilling).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is likely that the TSX will be reaching 13,000 shortly in this
earnings season. However, what happens afterward is anyone's guess. At
this point, I am neither long or short for the long term. The
reward/risk isn't good for going long at this point with that much
uncertainty. And the threat of QE2 and earnings release isn't good for
going short either. I am watching the forex market closely for signs of
a direction as that is a driver of the equity market these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="S&amp;amp;P
TSX"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-10-13-TSX.png" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570"
caption="CBOE Market Volatility Index (VIX) vs. inverse
S&amp;amp;P500"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-10-13-VIX.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-10-13-VIX.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>Still waiting on the sideside in my RRSP</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/still-waiting-on-the-sideside-in-my-rrsp/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-09T10:42:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-09-09:still-waiting-on-the-sideside-in-my-rrsp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As much as I rant about trading and forex, a big portion of my
investment funds are in a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;Questrade RRSP trading account&lt;/a&gt; for the
long haul. However, that account has been dormant for a few weeks now.
The money is just sitting there, not even making any interest. The
reason is that I am just not seeing any long-term opportunity on either
long or short just yet. Even though the month of September started well
after Labour Day, as the market is inching higher, the long term picture
is still unclear. Figure 1 below clearly shows that not much has really
happened for the whole year. There was a lot of volatility as TSX swings
up and down a thousand points now and then. Evidently, a buy-and-hold
strategy wouldn't have been doing too well this year. As such, I am
waiting with no position in hand. At least I'm not going &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-6-cm-10oct-put-74-00-6-60-mark-70-70-8-0/"&gt;all out
shorting the equity market&lt;/a&gt; anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX weekly
chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-09-09-TSX_wkly.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>To hell and back? A review of TSX after a V-day</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/to-hell-and-back-a-review-of-tsx-after-a-v-day/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-06T20:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-05-06:to-hell-and-back-a-review-of-tsx-after-a-v-day/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As every trader knows already, the Dow tanked 1,000 points (about 9%) in
like 15 minutes today. But what's more amazing is that all the indices
made their way back just as quickly. Figure 1 below is today's chart of
TSX Composite (blue) and S&amp;amp;P 500 (red). So what does this mean for TSX?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-05-06-TSX-SPX.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="TSX Composite and S&amp;amp;P 500" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-05-06-TSX-SPX.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Let's zoom
out to take a look at the big picture. Figure 2 is a weekly chart of
TSX. The top indicator is the percentage of TSX traded issues above
their 200 day moving average. The overlay indicator is the percentage of
TSX traded issues above their 50 day moving average. The lower indicator
is the percentage of issues above 200 MA divided by the percentage above
their 50 MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX
Composite"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-05-06-TSX-200-50.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TSX index is an aggregate of prices from a handful of companies. But
there are over three thousand issues trading on the TSX. This view of
Figure 2 provides another perspective of where the market stands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question to be answered is this, how much technical damage did
today's sell-off produce?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, both the 200 and 50 numbers are at their respective
support after the close. This is as low as we have been in the past 9
months or so. However, they are still hanging high above according to
the 200 percentage. There are still 56.5% of companies above their 200
day moving average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the shorter term though, the 50 number is pretty low at 30%. Only 30%
of companies are above their 50 day moving average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referring to the historical pattern as shown on Figure 2. Typically
numbers 30 or below means that the down move is exhausting. Since most
(70%) companies are trading low already, so there's not much room for
big dives until the market can reload. It is interesting that we touched
30% this week yet the TSX index is still not down that much in the big
picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, I am still bearish on the market in the long run.
But I don't think today's move is the beginning of &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; dive. Since
volatility has contracted to a recent record low, this move is just a
shake-out of the bulls. Is this the end of this down move? I don't know.
But I expect to see at least an opposite shake-out of the bears soon
before any real move can materialize. Control your risks in expectation
of big ups and downs in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's just too good to be true for the bears that the market makes a
U-turn and head straight down after congesting below a support level for
weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my trading, I'm all cash today. So it was fun to watch the
move with no strings attached. I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-12-cve-to-puts-2-90-mark-27-50-10-gain/"&gt;covered my CVE.TO shorts yesterday&lt;/a&gt;
at a decent price. CVE.TO broke down further today during the panic but
ended up closing slightly higher. So my exit was good as I couldn't have
covered during that rapid breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Mish offers &lt;a href="http://globaleconomicanalysis.blogspot.com/2010/05/trader-error.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+MishsGlobalEconomicTrendAnalysis+%28Mish%27s+Global+Economic+Trend+Analysis%29"&gt;a good brief on today's extraordinary move&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>Sold 12 CVE.TO Puts @ 2.90 Mark $27.50, +10% gain</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-12-cveto-puts-290-mark-2750-10-gain/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-05T20:16:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-05-05:sold-12-cveto-puts-290-mark-2750-10-gain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I closed my short Cenovus Energy (CVE.TO) position this morning as crude
oil broke below \$80 briefly and the Dollar Index rose above \$84.
My&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-3-cve-to-jul-30-puts-1-75-mark-30-10/"&gt;original target was \$27&lt;/a&gt; for this short. But considering the fact
that I mistakenly doubled my position size, I am closing this trade a
step above at this \$27.50 support level (see Figure 1 for CVE.TO
support lines). Furthermore, the time decay on the options premium is
accelerating so I needed to sell this soon. The final profit on this
position is \$858.15 (after \$63.80 commission), or just over 10% in my
RRSP account. Although this trade is profitable, it is a horrible trade
for the following reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="Cenovus Energy
(CVE.TO)"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-05-05-CVE-TO.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I accidentally &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/i-just-made-a-grave-fundamental-mistake-in-my-cve-to-trade/"&gt;bought more contracts when I intended to sell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not correcting my mistake immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I risked too much at 3% (of account) initially and then 10% after my
    mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peak drawdown was over \$1000 (12.5%) at one time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too eager to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-3-cve-to-10jul17-puts-30-00-mx-2-45-mark-28-64/"&gt;add to my position once it moved&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reward-to-Risk ratio is less than 1.0, so I threw big money for
    smaller gain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commission ends up eating 7% of profit away. That is too much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I made one, two, ... seven too many mistakes in this
trade. Luckily, I did manage to do some things right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patience. There were a few days when the price moved sideway. I
    didn't succumb to my emotions and dump the shares when it was nerve
    whacking to hold onto a loss. The price was still below my mental
    stop so I held.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the initial shock of doubling my position as the price moved
    away, I mentally accepted my loss and was able to study the market
    objectively since.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Didn't take profit too early once the price moved back in my favour
    this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't be as lucky every time. Learn from my mistakes and exploit on my
strengths. That is the lesson from this trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CVE.TO"></category><category term="Energy"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="options"></category><category term="RRSP"></category><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>April is Earnings Season One Year After the Bottom</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/april-is-earnings-season-one-year-after-the-bottom/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-30T11:47:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-30:april-is-earnings-season-one-year-after-the-bottom/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earnings season is approaching as the first quarter of 2010 comes to a
close this week. In April, companies will try to woo us with their
numbers and outlooks. With the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-first-analysis-of-the-sptsx-60-index/"&gt;market looking so toppy&lt;/a&gt; already, how
will the market react? Consider Figure 1. Past 3 earnings season since
the epic rally from March of 2009 have consistently been followed by
market corrections (blue lines). Will we see the same selloff in a
couple of weeks? As the Shocked Investor points out, "... positive
surprises will be harder and harder to come by. Given that the markets
are even more overvalued now, there is &lt;a href="http://shockedinvestor.blogspot.com/2010/03/markets-drop-during-earnings-season.html"&gt;reason to expect similar
behavior&lt;/a&gt;." On the other hand, this quarter's earnings report will be
the first time in which the year-over-year value will be compared to &lt;em&gt;a
period in the worst of the fallout&lt;/em&gt; (see Q1 of 2009 in Figure 1). As
such, it will no doubt be easier to paint a pretty picture as anything
compared to an apocalypse will look good. With the market squeezed
between the bulls and the bears entering earnings releases, the next few
weeks should be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX cyclical
analysis"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-30-TSX_earnings.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>My first analysis of the S&amp;P/TSX 60 Index</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/my-first-analysis-of-the-sptsx-60-index/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-27T11:04:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-27:my-first-analysis-of-the-sptsx-60-index/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seeing that I will be trading (not investing) the Canadian market in my
RRSP, I am starting to follow the S&amp;amp;P/TSX 60 Index. I will adapt a
method that I have been using for the S&amp;amp;P 500. Namely technical analysis
(price), internal sentiments (depth), and intermarket analysis (breath).
Nothing fancy, really. I will discuss my method and analysis in this
post. The goal is not to find a holy grail trading method, but to get a
feel of the ebbs and flows of the market. Let's review the TSX from
three angles. First is a standard price chart. As I was saying in the
beginning of the month, &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-reason-against-stocking-into-a-registered-trading-account-this-year/"&gt;my long term view of the TSX is still
bearish&lt;/a&gt;. The one and only condition to invalidate my bearish outlook
is that the TSX stay clear of the 12,000 resistance price level on the
weekly chart. As you can see in Figure 1 below, that hasn't happened yet
despite a continuing intermediate term (in weeks) bullishness. On the
other hand, the intermediate term up move in the market is undeniable.
The market has been making higher highs and higher lows for months now.
So the fight continues as we wait to see which side will win. The 12,000
resistance or the relentless rally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX 60
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_wkly.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows a reason for my bearishness. As the price of TSX 60 moves
up in the past few months, the percentage of companies on the TSX
Composite (representing over 70% market capitalization on the Toronto
Stock Exchange) that are over their 200 day moving average has been
forming a toppy pattern (top of Figure 2). Similarly, the 50 day moving
average percentage confirms this price divergence from a shorter term
perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX internal
sentiment"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_internal.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_internal.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Lastly, I consider the dynamics between
the financial and energy sectors, two of the biggest components on the
TSX. Here is why I picked those two sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing that the financial sector is the bane of global economy in recent
months, price moves in this sector represent public risk appetite.
Conversely, the energy sector is the foundation of the Canadian economy.
As such, I use it as a crude measure of risk aversion. So a ratio
between the TSX financial index versus the TSX energy index is my way of
estimating risk appetite versus risk aversion. I call this ratio my risk
meter. Basically, a high value is good and a low value is bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 shows that the up trend in recent months is actually confirmed
by an increasing risk meter. So as much as I've been ringing the bear
bell, this rally is legitimate so far. As such, the market is decidedly
bullish in the intermediate term (as if anyone doesn't know by now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX Financial
vs. Energy"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_sectors.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-27-TSX_sectors.png"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, my long term view is bearish but my intermediate term view
is bullish. Even though a month has passed since my last peak of the
TSX, things remain the same. The line in the sand at 12,000 is still
being fought for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not short or long the market until a clearer scenario presents
itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="3D analysis"></category><category term="Canada"></category><category term="TSX"></category></entry><entry><title>Data Scraping the Toronto Stock Exchange: Extracting 3,660 companies' data</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-11T07:29:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-11:data-scraping-the-toronto-stock-exchange-extracting-3660-companies-data/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the tasks that I've always wanted to make more efficient in my
stock trading is the work of scanning for stocks to trade. One look at
my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/trading-how-tos/trading-strategy/"&gt;trading strategy posts&lt;/a&gt; and you'll see that I have devised many
stock scanning systems in the past few years. The most recent system
that I've used is one that uses &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/week-of-sept-13-2009-in-play-stocks-breakout-results/"&gt;options data to filter stocks&lt;/a&gt;.
However, it is not automated. So it takes a lot of time to gather and
analyze the data. Furthermore, the set of tools that I use is limited to
U.S. stocks. Now that I have taken an interest in the Canadian stock
market, I can't seem to find any public tool that I like. Thus, I am
biting the bullet now and taking my time to develop a custom system once
and for all. Before we can analyze stock data, we need to extract them
first. Where better else for that than go straight to the source at
TMX.com, the parent company of Toronto Stock Exchange (TSX) and TSX
Venture Exchange (TSXV). TMX.com provide a list of publicly traded
companies in ten Excel files. The files are divided by sectors. Each
contain a number of fundamental company data, such as market
capitalization and outstanding shares. So step 1 is to extract those
data. This is where I am at now. I attached the source code for an
alpha/developmental release below for anyone interested. It is a working
program to scrape the data from TMX.com's files. But it's still a
work-in-progress. That's why I am calling it a version 0.1. The next
milestone is to program a Stocks class to hold, organize, and manage all
three thousand, six hundred, and sixty companies' data. This is an easy
task to do by extending the built-in dictionary class in Python.
However, I haven't gotten to that chapter yet in my scientific
programming with Python learning book. I stopped at chapter 8 to work on
this project. Chapter 9 is the inheritence and hierarchical material.
The goal of this project is to build an automated data scraping program
for TSX and TSXV data from various sources into my computer. Once I have
my data, that's when the real fun starts. Regarding the code below, I
know that source code is useless for most people. Once the project is
complete, I will compile the code into a standalone application and post
it on this site. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/feed/"&gt;Subscribe to my RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; so that you can keep
up-to-date with the progress of this project and my other ramblings on
trading. [python] # extractTMX.py # version: 0.1 alpha release #
revision date: March, 2010 # by Paul, Quantisan.com """A data scraping
module to extract company listing excel files from TMX.COM""" import
xlrd # to read Excel file #import sys from finClasses import Stock #
custom Stock class def _verify(): """Verification function for a
rundown of the module""" pass # copy test block here when finished def
findCol(sheet, key): """Find the column corresponding to header string
'key'""" firstRow = sheet.row_values(0) for col in
range(len(firstRow)): if key in firstRow[col]: return col # return
first sighting else: # not found raise ValueError("%s is not found!" %
key) def scrapeXLS(book): """Data scraping function for TMX Excel
file""" listingDict = {} # dict of ('ticker': market cap) for index in
range(book.nsheets): sh = book.sheet_by_index(index) mcCol =
findCol(sh, "Market Value") assert type(mcCol) is int, "mcCol is a %s" %
type(mcCol) osCol = findCol(sh, "O/S Shares") assert type(osCol) is int,
"osCol is a %s" % type(osCol) secCol = findCol(sh, "Sector") # multiple
matches but taking first assert type(secCol) is int, "secCol is a %s" %
type(secCol) hqCol = findCol(sh, "HQ\nRegion") assert type(hqCol) is
int, "hqCol is a %s" % type(hqCol) for rx in range(1, sh.nrows): sym =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=4)) # symbol s =
sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=2) # exchange col. if s == "TSX": exch =
"T" elif s == "TSXV": exch = "V" else: raise TypeError("Unknown exchange
value") mc = sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=mcCol) # market cap # check
for empty market cap cell mc = int(mc) if type(mc) is float else 0 os =
int(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=osCol)) # O/S shares sec =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=secCol)) # sector hq =
str(sh.cell_value(rowx=rx, colx=hqCol)) # HQ region listingDict[sym] =
Stock(symbol=sym,exchange=exch, mktCap=mc,osShares=os,
sector=sec,hqRegion=hq) return listingDict def fetchFiles(fname): infile
= open(fname, 'r') # text file of XLS file names listing = {} for line
in infile: # 1 file name per line if line[0] == '#': continue # skip
commented lines line = line.strip() # strip trailing \n print "Reading
'%s' ..." % line xlsFile = "TMX/" + line # in TMX directory book =
xlrd.open_workbook(xlsFile) # import Excel file
listing.update(scrapeXLS(book)) # append scraped the data to dict
return listing #if __name__ == '__main__': # verify block #
if len(sys.argv) == 2 and sys.argv[1] == 'verify': # _verify() if
__name__ == '__main__': # test block listing =
fetchFiles('TMX/TMXfiles.txt') [/python]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="data scraping"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="source code"></category><category term="TSX"></category><category term="TSX Venture"></category></entry><entry><title>Another reason against stocking into a registered trading account this year</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-reason-against-stocking-into-a-registered-trading-account-this-year/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-05T07:32:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-03-05:another-reason-against-stocking-into-a-registered-trading-account-this-year/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's another reason why I am so &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/is-a-5000-questrade-tfsa-trading-account-cost-effective-part-1/"&gt;reluctant to put money into a TFSA
trading account&lt;/a&gt; to invest in Canadian stocks. As you know, in a
registered trading account, such as a RRSP self-directed trading account
or a &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/questrade/"&gt;Questrade TFSA trading account&lt;/a&gt; (aff), you cannot short shares
and can only buy because you can't trade on margin. As such, a
registered trading account is an account for buy-only trading. It
doesn't take a genius to figure out that a buy-only trading strategy is
best used ... in a bull market. As trading wisdom goes, trade with the
trend. So the question is, are we in a bull market in 2010? Figures 1
and 2 shows the weekly chart of TSX Index and the TSX Venture Index,
respectively. Referring to Fig. 1, TSX is bumping up against some
headwind at a 12,000 resistance. Unless TSX can stay above 12,000
cleanly (a weekly low above that level at least), I am still bearish in
the market because that financial crisis back in 2008 (&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/another-breakdown-of-a-major-multi-year-support-are-we-going-down-and-i-mean-really-down/"&gt;remember those
days&lt;/a&gt;?) is still overshadowing long term prices and trader sentiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-TSX_wk.png" /&gt;][][/caption] TSX Venture is depressed even more as seen
in Figure 2 below. Just look at the huge gap from current price to the
200 week moving average (red line). This isn't a good sign as lack of
interest in high-risk stocks means traders are generally cautious. Yes,
it's true that the equity market has been running up, up, and up for a
good year. However, the fact that TSX is sitting at the same level as in
2001 proves that the long term, multi-year bull market has been cleanly
broken. We might very well see pockets of multi-month rallies
materialize (like we're seeing now), but unless proven otherwise, the
long term trend is not looking green for the markets. It will not be
easy money in the stock market like back in the pre-tech bubble 1990's.
As opined by Bill Cara, the &lt;a href="http://www.caracommunity.com/"&gt;time for buy-and-hold is gone&lt;/a&gt;. It is
well known in the community that the coming years will be volatile with
big ups and downs. That is my little secret for moving to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/category/forex/"&gt;trade
forex&lt;/a&gt;last year and the main reason why I am reluctant to set aside
money on a one-sided stock trading account. [caption id=""
align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="TSX Venture,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-CDNX_wk.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-03-04-CDNX_wk.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Canada"></category><category term="TSX"></category><category term="TSX Venture"></category></entry></feed>