<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Paul Lam</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/usd_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2011-06-24T09:28:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>How do you minimize risks when EURUSD moves 100 pips up and back down in 2 hours?</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-do-you-minimize-risks-when-eurusd-moves-100-pips-up-and-back-down-in-2-hours/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-24T09:28:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-06-24:how-do-you-minimize-risks-when-eurusd-moves-100-pips-up-and-back-down-in-2-hours/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;And this happens quite often. [caption id="attachment_5526"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURUSD, 5 min"]&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/06/2011-06-24-eurusd-5m-580x204.png" title="2011-06-24-eurusd-5m" /&gt;[/caption]
There are a few choices to minimize your risks in times like these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay on the sideline until the dust settled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Target higher time frames with larger stops and smaller positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partner up with someone from another timezone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a trailing stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set alerts to wake you up on extraordinary events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a position management bot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opted for #6. What about you? The picture is worse in equities as you
are locked in your positions overnight. [caption id="attachment_5527"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="S&amp;amp;P500 ETF"]&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/06/2011-06-24-SPY-580x258.png" title="2011-06-24-SPY" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EUR"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Bearish USDJPY on 19th week of 2011</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bearish-usdjpy-on-19th-week-of-2011/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-05-08T22:58:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-05-08:bearish-usdjpy-on-19th-week-of-2011/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am going bearish on USDJPY this week using my QTD system. No position
is opened at this point. I am merely entering my sentiment into &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/quantised-trading-desk/"&gt;the
system to trade for me&lt;/a&gt;. Figure 1 is a daily chart of USDJPY. Notice
it's lack of life despite the USD making headlines last week. Figure 2
shows the move with a US dollar index, USDX, daily chart. Furthermore,
according to the order book on USDJPY, there are massive bullish
positions in the red (at a loss) which make this pair ripe for some bull
squeeze. I am going short on NZDUSD as a hedge on this move. It is my
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/"&gt;favourite long USD pair these days&lt;/a&gt;. [caption id="attachment_5405"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USDJPY,
daily"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDJPY-580x383.png" title="2011-05-08-USDJPY" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="attachment_5406"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="U.S. dollar index futures,
USDX"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDX-580x288.png" title="2011-05-08-USDX" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDJPY-580x383.png" title="2011-05-08-USDJPY" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDJPY.png
  [&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDX-580x288.png" title="2011-05-08-USDX" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/05/2011-05-08-USDX.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="JPY"></category><category term="NZD"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>First QTD trade, 0.19% gain long EURGBP</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/first-qtd-trade-019-gain-long-eurgbp/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-21T21:51:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-04-21:first-qtd-trade-019-gain-long-eurgbp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My semi-automated trading system, Quantised Trading Desk, closed its
first trade this week. I was &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/"&gt;bullish EURGBP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/"&gt;USDJPY&lt;/a&gt;, and
bearish NZDUSD as per the previous discussions. The QTD system saved me
from the premature calls in both USDJPY and NZDUSD by not making any
trade this week. That, in and of itself, has made me very happy with
QTD's first week of live trading. Particular in light of how fierce that
USDJPY down move has been. As a bonus, QTD entered a long position in
EURGBP for a small 0.19% gain as illustrated below. My parameter were a
maximum of 0.25% risk per position. The gain could have been better if
it weren't for that 61% retracement. Not that I'm complaining as I
haven't even looked at the market this past couple of days while the
system is trading for me. USDJPY touched my threshold support price
80.70, my bullish sentiment needs to be reevaluated. NZDUSD just cracked
a higher high (marginally though), so I'm easing on the bear button for
now. EURGBP is testing some resistance to, so I'm not so eager to dive
in again. Overall, I've been 2/3 wrong. I've told you before that &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/i-didnt-miss-a-boat-i-missed-a-freakin-rocket/"&gt;I'm
very bad at timing the market&lt;/a&gt;. That's why I developed QTD to trade
for me. Seeing that it's a long weekend, and I'll be way from town, I'm
just going to shut down my remote trade server in London until next week
when I can have some time to re-do my analysis. [caption
id="attachment_5361" align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURGBP,
hourly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr-580x411.png" title="2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr-580x411.png" title="2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-21-EURGBP_hr.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="EUR"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="NZD"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Bullish EURGBP as hedge and Bearish NZDUSD as diversification</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-18T21:14:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-04-18:bullish-eurgbp-as-hedge-and-bearish-nzdusd-as-diversification/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had more time to study the market tonight and is running a second
and a third instances of Quantised Trading Desk (QTD) to trade 3
currencies in total simultaneously. For my dollar bull sentiment, I'm
dividing between USDJPY long and NZDUSD short. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/"&gt;QTD still hasn't taken a
position in USDJPY in the past 24 hours&lt;/a&gt;. That's a good thing as
USDJPY is still drifting downward today even as the dollar is gaining
some ground. My line in the sand is at 80.70 for USDJPY and above 0.8100
for NZDUSD. EURGBP long is a hedge against my dollar longs. Again, I'm
not making any trade at this point but merely &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/quantised-trading-desk/"&gt;setting up QTD to wait
for the right moments to enter&lt;/a&gt;. A break below 0.8660 for EURGBP would
challenge my bullish bias. These three currencies should be my complete
market bias for a while. I'm just going to let QTD do its thing and
trade for me. Hopefully this will be the last you'll hear from me about
my market bias for a while. [caption id="attachment_5342"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="NZDUSD,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly-580x264.png" title="2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly" /&gt;][][/caption] [caption id="attachment_5343"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="EURGBP,
weekly"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly-580x264.png" title="2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly-580x264.png" title="2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-NZDUSD_wkly.png
  [&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly-580x264.png" title="2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-18-EURGBP_wkly.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="EUR"></category><category term="GBP"></category><category term="NZD"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Bullish USDJPY on week of April 17, 2011</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-17T21:50:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2011-04-17:bullish-usdjpy-on-week-of-april-17-2011/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have unofficially launched my Quantised Trading Desk (QTD) expert
system this weekend as the system is ready for live trading after almost
a year in development. You can't miss the announcement if you visit the
new frontpage of this blog. So, I won't talk about it anymore here. The
purpose of this post is to discuss my forex trade. It's been over 7
months since I've traded on the forex market. I have been working on QTD
during all these months to improve my overall trading. Anyway, let's
dive right to it for my first trade back into forex. I am bullish on the
U.S. dollar this week. Why? The Financial Times is letting on &lt;a href=""&gt;rumours
that the US Fed is signalling an end to quantitative easing&lt;/a&gt;.
Coincidentally, the U.S. dollar appears to be testing supports across
all major currencies. Secondly the US equities market hasn't been able
to make higher highs even as the dollar is marking new lows. Still, I'm
not one to call a bottom, nor am I hunting for one. This is merely a
good risk-reward trade to gun for an obvious move. In particular, USDJPY
appears to be the best of the bunch as its been holding well over the
past few months while the dollar crumbled. The fact that Europe and US
are rumoured to be lighting up on the money printing whereas Japan's
money printing press is on full steam for the quake reconstruction (Yen
bearish) is a decent excuse to place some chips on USDJPY. You might
have noticed, I haven't specified my entry price, amount, or stop loss
price as usual. This is because I am relying on the Quantised Trading
Desk expert system to trade USDJPY for me. QTD will monitor the market
for me and execute trade entries and exits as it sees fit to accumulate
a long position in USDJPY. All the risk management and quant analysis
are built into the system. So I don't have a position yet because I'm
waiting for QTD to do the grunt work. [caption id="attachment_5332"
align="aligncenter" width="580" caption="USDJPY weekly
chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly-580x333.png" title="2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;http:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bcad7330-691a-11e0-9040-00144feab49a.html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly-580x333.png" title="2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly" /&gt;]: http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/2011/04/2011-04-17-USDJPY_wkly.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="JPY"></category><category term="QTD"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Closed USDCAD short @ 1.06525, breakeven</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/closed-usdcad-short-106525-breakeven/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-31T18:24:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-08-31:closed-usdcad-short-106525-breakeven/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seem that USDCAD isn't about to die just yet. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/short-usdcad-1-0654-stop-1-077/"&gt;My USDCAD short&lt;/a&gt; got
stopped out at breakeven this morning. In fact, the pair is still
struggling around the descending resistance line as shown in Figure 1.
It made a higher low so I won't be surprised if it cracks higher.
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-08-31-USDCAD.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why I took this trade was that the opportunity seemed too
good to pass on &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/short-usdcad-1-0654-stop-1-077/"&gt;based on my analysis at the time&lt;/a&gt;. I
always keep an eye on the market even when I'm not trading. Although the
basic setup remains intact, the opportunity isn't so fantastic that I
couldn't say no anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I shouldn't be wasting time managing a minuscule trade. Back to
staring at codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Short USDCAD @ 1.0654, Stop 1.077</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/short-usdcad-10654-stop-1077/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-25T09:40:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-08-25:short-usdcad-10654-stop-1077/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first real forex trade after &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/usdcad-holding-on-to-intermediate-term-support-at-1-0868/"&gt;a year minus one day of
studying the market&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper trading&lt;/a&gt;. Shorted USDCAD based on
the following intermarket observations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday's equities sell-off held around S&amp;amp;P at 1050&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overnight Asian market seem orderly, not every market followed
    through, but most did&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;European markets down move were slow overnight until US open&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But perhaps most importantly, EUR/USD made a higher low with an
    increasing COT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, as much as the sell-off tries to scare off people, the
markets don't seem to be moving in unison. So it would seem this move
(in equities, thus inverse USD) is still a bear trap in an intermediate
term bull rally. Plus this daily chart, Figure 1, for picking USDCAD
specifically. [caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570"
caption="USDCAD daily chart"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-08-25-USDCAD_daily.png" /&gt;][][/caption] And this 4-hour chart
for trade execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-08-25-USDCAD.png" /&gt;]&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-08-25-USDCAD.png"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;[/caption] Size of trade is 1000 unit. Risking about
0.05% of capital with a hard stop at 1.077. Anything above 1.070 would
put me on alert though. Coincidentally, I first got into the forex
market by studying the loonie. Let's see how this first trade performs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Stopped USDCAD short @ 1.0540 for +131 pips</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-10540-for-131-pips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-15T09:23:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-15:paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-10540-for-131-pips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally a profitable trade in my USDCAD short after being stopped out a
few times. My decision last week to &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/usdcad-short-target-hit-1-0581-trying-something-new-to-hold-for-longer/"&gt;hold this for longer&lt;/a&gt; after
USDCAD touched my target paid off. I moved my stop closer last Thursday
evening and the order got filled on Friday. However, as I type this on
the following Monday, USDCAD is trading even lower at 1.0478. It looks
as though my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;original target of 1.0415&lt;/a&gt; is in the cards. Even though
this is a profitable trade with a 0.17% gain in my demo account, there
is one major flaw with this short USDCAD play. I was not able to squeeze
more out of this profitable move. As I've said, this short took a few
tries. In fact, if we consider all the entires and exits of this play.
My stopped out losses totaled 0.29% and my single win here is merely
0.17%. So I'm actually at a net loss of 0.12% from all these work. My
win/loss rate is about 40% based on my review of recent forex trades. I
was able to edge out more than &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/trade-log/"&gt;10% profit in four months&lt;/a&gt; because
when I am wrong, I take small steps. But when I'm right, I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/how-to-stockpile-a-trade-position-one-step-at-a-time/"&gt;pile into a
position&lt;/a&gt;. Ever since my trading environment has changed, I've been
trying to trade a longer timeframe. This USDCAD short is my first
attempt on a new strategy. Evidently, I will need to re-think and
re-learn what I've become accustomed to in the past few months. One of
the necessary trait of a successful trader is to be able to adapt.
Markets change. Traders need to evolve with the markets or they will
become obsolete. This will be a good test of myself to see if I can
re-invent myself to adapt to a changing trading environment. [caption
id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD,
3-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-13-USDCAD_3h.png" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bad trade"></category><category term="CAD"></category><category term="exit"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>USDCAD short target hit @ 1.0581, trying something new--to hold for longer</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/usdcad-short-target-hit-10581-trying-something-new-to-hold-for-longer/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-10T20:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-10:usdcad-short-target-hit-10581-trying-something-new-to-hold-for-longer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;USDCAD comes to a halt at 1.0581 today. My original target was 1.05761.
A mere 5 pips difference. &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;This position&lt;/a&gt; is now +79 pips on paper. I
moved my stop to breakeven last night. Normally, I would have covered
most, if not all, of the position at this point. But I'll hold onto the
full amount this time. For now. Reasons are as follow. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USDCAD likes to grind out both bulls and bears at obvious levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;down move that I'm seeing&lt;/a&gt; is still in an early
    stage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My position is too small to be worthwhile if I take profit now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of my recent performance shows that I often don't ride my
    winners long enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I must learn to adopt a longer term strategy now that I [can't trade
    as often][].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, Figure 1 shows what I mean by #2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="570" caption="USDCAD,
4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-10-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption] In fact, I intend to look for opportunities
to add to this position. As long as USDCAD stays below 1.0645, I'm
confident (not exactly the right word though) with this down move. From
this point onward, it's new territory for me as I push beyond my comfort
zone. Is this an ill-fated move or a spark of insight? Let me know what
you think about this extended trade. Update February 15: I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-usdcad-short-1-0540-for-131-pips/"&gt;closed this
trade&lt;/a&gt; for +131 pips gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper trade: Short USDCAD @ 1.0671, Stop 1.0756, Target 1.05761</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-10671-stop-10756-target-105761/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-09T18:56:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-02-09:paper-trade-short-usdcad-10671-stop-10756-target-105761/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Perhaps third times' the charm? I tried to short USDCAD twice last week
already. Both times I've been &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-stopped-out-of-usdcad-short-1-0640-for-67-pips-re-entering-1-0680/"&gt;stopped out&lt;/a&gt; for a total of -0.2% of
account loss. My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/paper-trade-short-usdcad-1-0573-stop-1-0640-target-1-0415/"&gt;intermediate term analysis&lt;/a&gt; remains the same as
before. So I won't repeat myself here. Entry signal for this particular
short is shown in Figure 1. I'm just using the 4-hour chart as I have a
well defined (recent top) stop this time. I compensate with a smaller
position size to limit my risk to 0.1%. Reward / Risk = (1.05761 -
1.0671) / (1.0671 - 1.0756) = 1.11 [caption id="" align="aligncenter"
width="570" caption="USD/CAD, 4-hour"][&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.quantisan.com/static/images/img_archive/2010-02-09-usdcad_4h.gif" /&gt;][][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CAD"></category><category term="entry"></category><category term="FTC"></category><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="short"></category><category term="USD"></category></entry></feed>