<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/uso_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2009-05-08T12:25:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>USO: Short entry stop $32.21 / Exit stop $32.49</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/uso-short-entry-stop-3221-exit-stop-3249/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-05-08T12:25:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-05-08:uso-short-entry-stop-3221-exit-stop-3249/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's finally a real order after a string of &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/tag/paper%20trade/"&gt;paper trades&lt;/a&gt;. Remember
USO? I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-35/"&gt;was long in USO&lt;/a&gt; not too long ago. Well, the same channel that
told me to exit my long position is looking toppy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned from my USO trade is that this ETF is a money losing
game. [The roll over every month of contracts put a severe strain on USO
share price][]. And yesterday was the last day of this month's rollover.
At around 1:30pm yesterday, there were some significant volume with
dumping of USO shares at \$32. This is the first sign of distribution of
USO shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then today, I see the same thing happening at the intraday resistance.
Sudden spike in volumes within seconds at the resistance of \$32.42.
This is a sign that a big player is dumping shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is mere a conjecture on my part. This could also be a way
for some big players to rake in more shares. So don't rely on this too
much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the bigger pictures though, I see weaknesses in the weekly
and daily charts too. Also, the break to the top of the up channel
(Figure 3) was only greeted by low volumes. So it's unlikely that we
will break further up from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this is a small play with a tight stop and high probability
(contango is on my side this time around) of success, that is if I don't
get stopped out first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short entry stop: \$32.21, just below some intraday congestion and
support from last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exit stop: \$32.49, intraday top so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target: \$29.50. 50% Fib level from this rally and near bottom of a huge
congestion zone in the recent months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reward / Risk = 2.71 / 0.28 = 9.7 &gt; 3.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: USO dipped below \$32 in the pre-market on Monday. But I'll pass
because I'm very low on available cash in my trading account. I need to
limit my risk exposure even though I still think this is a great
opportunity. I'll put this one in a &lt;strong&gt;paper trade&lt;/strong&gt; just to see how it
goes. Order is set for an entry short stop at \$31.99 to be submitted at
3:30pm today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1369" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="US Oil Fund (daily, weekly)"]&lt;img alt="US Oil Fund" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/2009-05-08-uso_long.png" title="2009-05-08-USO_long" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1370" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="US Oil Fund"]&lt;img alt="US Oil Fund" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/2009-05-08-uso.png" title="2009-05-08-USO" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1371" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="US Oil Fund"]&lt;img alt="US Oil Fund" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/2009-05-08-uso_prop.png" title="2009-05-08-USO_prop" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The roll over every month of contracts put a severe strain on USO
  share price]: http://shockedinvestor.blogspot.com/2009/02/tale-of-uso-usl-and-contango.html&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="paper trade"></category><category term="USO"></category></entry><entry><title>BOUGHT +2 USO 100 MAY 09 28 PUT @.35</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-35/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-05-04T13:56:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-05-04:bought-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-35/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just closed my USO long position. I bought back the &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-175/"&gt;puts that I wrote
for \$1.75 about a month ago&lt;/a&gt;. This represents a realized profit of
\$280 - \$15 for commission. I actually wanted to get out of this
position last Friday when USO tested \$30. But &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/buy-stop-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-65/"&gt;my stop was never
triggered&lt;/a&gt; so I held on to the options through the weekend, thinking
I'd benefit from the time decay anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, USO reached \$30.50 with some relatively low volume. \$30.50 also
mark the top of a recent up channel (Figure 2). With my limited profit
potential at this point, I'm inclined to take my profit than risk a
retracement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trade has certainly been a roller coaster ride. The &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/review-of-positions-srs-and-uso/"&gt;price of USO
didn't move up as planned&lt;/a&gt;. It actually took a dive but picked itself
up back to around my entry price on a slow up move. In the end, it was
the time decay of the options that helped to make this supposedly losing
trade into a winning one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another example to favour writing puts instead of buying shares
in this volatile market condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note, I'll look into USL instead of USO in the future for any
Oil trade. The April roll over contango took a stab at the USO price
last month. I was lucky for the short put strategy saving me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1347" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="US Oil ETF"]&lt;img alt="US Oil ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/2009-05-04-uso.png" title="2009-05-04-uso" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1348" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="US Oil ETF"]&lt;img alt="US Oil ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/2009-05-04-uso_prop.png" title="2009-05-04-uso_prop" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exit"></category><category term="USO"></category></entry><entry><title>Buy Stop +2 USO 100 May 09 28 Put .65</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/buy-stop-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-65/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-05-01T11:47:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-05-01:buy-stop-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-65/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have placed an exit buy stop for &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-175/"&gt;my USO short puts&lt;/a&gt; at \$0.65. In
other words, I've placed an exit stop for my long USO position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USO tested the recent up channel on low volume today. Furthermore, NY
Crude futures (QM) at \$53+ is nearing a long term resistance of \$55.
So there's not much upside left in this. Thus, I've placed an exit stop
just below an intraday support to take some profit. I'm just trying not
to be greedy here. I'll write a more thorough analysis if this stop gets
triggered today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1333" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="US Oil"]&lt;img alt="US Oil" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/2009-05-01-uso_prop.png" title="2009-05-01-uso_prop" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1334" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="NY Light Sweet Crude"]&lt;img alt="NY Light Sweet Crude" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/2009-05-01-qm.png" title="2009-05-01-qm" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="USO"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of positions: SRS and USO</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/review-of-positions-srs-and-uso/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-16T07:49:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-04-16:review-of-positions-srs-and-uso/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-31-srs-4808/"&gt;SRS position is deep underwater&lt;/a&gt;. To add to the mistake, I &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-1-srs-100-may-09-35-put-610/"&gt;added
to it last Thursday in a hurry&lt;/a&gt; hoping for a rebound from a massive
selloff to a new 52-week low. Even though the chart looked like it was
testing support last Thursday, I &lt;strong&gt;should have waited for a rebound
before entering&lt;/strong&gt;. And second, &lt;strong&gt;if I don't even have the time to write
my trade log, I should never enter a trade&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is definitely a wakeup call to rectify my tendency of entering too
early in the short term. I have since mentally walked through what I
should have done and have come up with a simple entry strategy that I
will follow from now on. Basically, I will wait validation of a intraday
low and then enter only if it passes its intraday resistance. Then I
will set a hard stop just below a recent support. This will no doubt
create a lot more stopped out trades, but it's up to me to find high
probability trades. All it needs now is some verification...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, I clearly need to spend less time trading and more time
developing my skills and strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the positions at hand. From Figure 1, SRS is at the bottom of a
long term down trend. Stop is \$30. Target is \$41. From the look of it,
SRS will be going down even further if the market can hold its ground
above 850. However, if the market fails to climb up, then yesterday's
slightly higher low than Monday is a small plus point for SRS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: Interestingly, in today's news &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123979197193420547.html"&gt;U.S. Foreclosures Jumped in
March&lt;/a&gt; and General Growth Files For Bankruptcy: Report. The 2nd news
came in the middle of the night. And it's nowhere to be found unless you
really look for it. I only read about it from &lt;a href="http://caracommunity.com/content/caras-commentary-community-chat-thurs-apr-16-2009"&gt;CaraCommunity&lt;/a&gt;. For one
of the largest REIT to declare bankruptcy, you'd think it'd be all over
the news. Doesn't take a genious to figure this incident is deliberately
hidden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1241" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="Ultrashort Real Estate ETF"]&lt;img alt="Ultrashort Real Estate
ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-15-srs.png" title="2009-04-15-srs" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My USO position is faring better, although it's merely hovering above
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-175/"&gt;my entry price&lt;/a&gt;. Now that the &lt;a href="http://shockedinvestor.blogspot.com/2009/04/uso-rollover-report-for-april.html"&gt;April roll over of USO&lt;/a&gt; is complete,
the downward pressure on USO should be gone. Even during the roll over,
USO has managed to remain above its upward trendline. This is definitely
a big plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New stop is \$28.80 and conservative target is \$32.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1242" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="US Oil Fund ETF"]&lt;img alt="US Oil Fund ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-15-uso.png" title="2009-04-15-uso" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="SRS"></category><category term="USO"></category></entry><entry><title>SOLD -2 USO 100 MAY 09 28 PUT @1.75</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-175/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-08T10:16:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2009-04-08:sold-2-uso-100-may-09-28-put-175/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I entered a long position in US Oil Fund (USO) today by writing puts.
(CBOE has a good article about put writing strategy, &lt;a href="http://www.cboe.com/micro/put/PUTIndexEnnisKnupp.pdf"&gt;PDF here&lt;/a&gt;) At
least this time, time decay will be on my side. Seeing that USO traded
down to 28.40's in the pre-market, I placed a limit order at 8am at
2.05, but it was never triggered when I got back to my desk at 10:30. NY
crude oil futures (QM) went just below \$48 but it bounced back pretty
quick. This led to my conviction that Oil has strength underneath its
belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I suggested in the weekly review, I'm to look for values in the
tech/telecom. But I also noted Basic Materials as a viable alternative.
Well, I read through a few charts last night, namely ADBE, INTC, and
CHL, but as nice as they were, they aren't screaming buys at this point
based on the indicators and chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also considered precious metals using SLW, but Gold/Silver seems to be
at a pivot level at this point. So it's anybody's game for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I read a couple of blog posts regarding USO/UCO from some
respectable traders. Figure 1 and Figure 2 shows my own analysis. The
pattern looks good and the indicators are in buy zone too. On top of
that, the overnight and premarket moves as I explained above looked good
too. That's when I decided to enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1213" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="U.S. Oil Fund ETF"]&lt;img alt="U.S. Oil Fund ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-08-uso.png" title="2009-04-08-uso" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_1214" align="aligncenter" width="500"
caption="U.S. Oil Fund ETF"]&lt;img alt="U.S. Oil Fund ETF" src="http://traderpau.files.wordpress.com/2009/04/2009-04-08-uso_prop.png" title="2009-04-08-uso_prop" /&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target: From Figure 2, \$32 is first level. Then \$34.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop: Recent lows about \$28.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: Since I wrote puts on this, time is on my side. The time
decay in options will add to my bottom line. And because we long weekend
coming, the options premium is going to drop and bunch as well as low
activity level expected this week. I will try to hold this until next
week and hopefully longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a sidenote, I feel that I've learned from my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/sold-5-ge-100-apr-09-11-put-79/"&gt;recent mistakes&lt;/a&gt; of
&lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/bought-31-srs-4808/"&gt;entering too early&lt;/a&gt; and demonstrated patience and discipline in this
entry. In particular, I &lt;strong&gt;waited til the morning and watched it bounce
on support before placing a limit order&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USO touched \$29 and retraced to close its intra-day gap when I entered
this position. It just glided over the support and bounced right back.
That was very bullish in the short term. As I'm writing this, USO
continued its climb to \$29.80 now.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entry"></category><category term="options"></category><category term="USO"></category></entry></feed>