<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quantitative Artisan</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/feeds/tag/vixcto_atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.quantisan.com/</id><updated>2010-10-14T12:20:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Canadian VIX: TSX to have their own volatility index</title><link href="http://www.quantisan.com/canadian-vix-tsx-to-have-their-own-volatility-index/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-14T12:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Lam</name></author><id>tag:www.quantisan.com,2010-10-14:canadian-vix-tsx-to-have-their-own-volatility-index/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't know if anyone noticed, but in my previous post &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/three-obvious-reasons-to-watch-13000-on-the-tsx/"&gt;discussing the
TSX&lt;/a&gt;, I included a chart of VIX (S&amp;amp;P500 volatility index) versus S&amp;amp;P
500. VIX is one of the market indicators that I can't live without.
However, as much as the Canadian and the American equity markets are
correlated, they are still separate markets. So using the VIX vs. S&amp;amp;P500
on an analysis of the TSX is like borrowing salt from thy neighbour. But
there's no more need for that soon as TSX is finally getting its own
volatility index starting Monday (October 18)! This is to replace the MX
Implied Volatility Index (MVX) from the Montreal Exchange, which I
didn't have access to previously (aside from &lt;a href="http://www.m-x.ca/indicesmx_mvx_en.php"&gt;data published on their
website&lt;/a&gt;). One question I have is that the TSX VIX will be based on
TSX 60 index options activity according on their &lt;a href="http://www.standardandpoors.com/servlet/BlobServer?blobheadername3=MDT-Type&amp;amp;blobcol=urldata&amp;amp;blobtable=MungoBlobs&amp;amp;blobheadervalue2=inline%3B+filename%3D20101014_TSX-60-VIX_Volatility-Launch.pdf&amp;amp;blobheadername2=Content-Disposition&amp;amp;blobheadervalue1=application%2Fpdf&amp;amp;blobkey=id&amp;amp;blobheadername1=content-type&amp;amp;blobwhere=1243766536405&amp;amp;blobheadervalue3=UTF-8"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;, but
the TSX 60 index options isn't that active. So would the TSX VIX be as
efficient as the S&amp;amp;P500 VIX? An opportunity with the introduction of TSX
VIX on the Toronto Exchange is that I can now place bets on market
volatility in my &lt;a href="http://www.quantisan.com/ranking-investment-options-for-my-self-directed-rrsp/"&gt;self-directed RRSP trading account&lt;/a&gt;. Which is
arguably more predictable than the underlying index these days... In any
case, this will be a vital market indicator for Canadian market traders.
For more information on TSX VIX, see the &lt;a href="http://www.standardandpoors.com/indices/sp-tsx-60-vix/en/us/?indexId=sp-tsx-60-vix"&gt;product information page on
Standard &amp;amp; Poor's&lt;/a&gt;. And a hat tip to &lt;a href="http://optionmatters.ca/"&gt;Option Matters&lt;/a&gt; (Montreal
Exchange's blog on options) for this news.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="indicator"></category><category term="market analysis"></category><category term="VIXC.TO"></category></entry></feed>